Hello, LinkedIn makers and movers. Our
guest today is what I classify as a
LinkedIn insider. That's a term I just
made up. It's not someone who works at
LinkedIn. It's someone who's building
software or service to support the
rapidly growing segment of creators uh
who are building personal brands.
They're building businesses. It's a term
for someone who's put in the reps, has
insights and perspective on how to do
LinkedIn better, derived from seeing
patterns across the clients they serve.
Our guest today is Alex Boyd, the CEO of
Aware. But before we welcome him
formally, I just want to turn back the
clock and talk a little bit about his
career to date. He got his start in
sales. No surprise here because it was
sales as a profession that first
embraced today what we call thought
leadership, personal branding or founder
brand. Back then it was just called
social selling. He started his career as
a foreign exchange broker. He then moved
into financial services. In both roles,
he crushed his quota. Then he took on a
management role overseeing a team of 20
AES and SDRs turning around a struggling
SDR team. During that time, he was named
an MVP by modern sales pros and a top
sales development leader by sales
hacker. After that, you think he set his
sights for a VP of sales role or chief
revenue officer, but he went out and he
started an SEO agency called Revenues
Zen. And recently, he built that to a
seven-figure exit. And while growing
that business, he stumbled upon the pain
of social selling, you need to
constantly engage with your target
audience via commenting to warm them up
to a conversation. And at the same time,
for folks who are building their
personal brands, LinkedIn got more
crowded. It started to behave more like
Twitter and that you really need to
engage to grow. And the common, you
know, pain for those people is that
LinkedIn has a terrible feature set for
organizing and surfacing comments of
people who are posting on your content.
So from that pain came Aware, a LinkedIn
engagement software and now that has a
seven figureure evaluation almost a
thousand users and Alex has a ton of
insight to draw from. In in fact he just
published a 50page state of LinkedIn
report that we'll talk about. And one
other fun thing that I learned about him
in his research he once described
himself as a philosopher who should live
in the forest. And today, while he's not
a philosopher in the traditional sense,
to me, he's the philosopher of LinkedIn,
his posts are some of the most
thoughtful and insightful out there on
strategies and tactics to grow as a
creator. And with that, let's welcome
Alex Boyd, the founder of Aware to the
LinkedIn Famous Podcast.
[Music]
Welcome to the LinkedIn Famous podcast.
The show where we get real about what it
takes to build a personal brand on
LinkedIn that gets real business
results. We're talking about driving
revenue from a personal LinkedIn profile
by sharing real and authentic stories
and points of view. I am Brad Zoic, your
host and the founder of Spectrimer, a
personal brand consultancy that helps
founders and executives get LinkedIn
famous. Join me for unfiltered
conversations from the trenches of
LinkedIn. We'll meet CEOs, go to market
executives, subject matter experts, and
company employees with blockbuster
LinkedIn results. We'll unpack strategy
and leave you with tactical advice to
grow your personal brand and demand for
your company's products and services.
All right, LinkedIn hustlers, it's time
to level up.
[Music]
That is the most thorough intro I think
I've ever heard. You went further back
than uh anyone has. Uh no one nobody
goes back to FXCM, but you did. So I
applaud you. Thank you for having me,
Brad. Awesome. Well, it's great to have
you here. And is there anything in your
background that you want to double click
on? Oh, man. Um tons. Yeah, the um the
one interesting link from the agency was
that it started as a sales consulting
and SDR agency and it migrated as we
took on new partners and so um it didn't
start out to uh create an SEO agency but
it ended up there which I think
illustrates the power of pivoting and
rebranding and never being afraid to say
dear LinkedIn I am something else and
just saying that for three months and
eventually it's true. Hey, that's a
founder life. Almost every quarter, you
know, you're burning the whole thing
down and starting over. Yeah. For a
while, then you hit it and then it's all
up from there. All right. So, I always
like to ask our guests to tell us
something about themselves that the
audience couldn't learn from their
LinkedIn profile. Interesting. I'm down
25 lbs since I last took my photos, and
I'm going to eventually be at my
co-founder's weight if I keep this up
soon. So, I'm very hungry right now, but
I had a nice big green smoothie for
lunch. And actually, you might be
surprised how podcastw worthy I
nevertheless feel. So, it's a very in
the- moment thing that is not clear for
my profile. Are are you guys uh having
some sort of health competition?
Kind of. You and your co-founder. Okay.
Well, no. Uh it's more like my wife is
um encouraging me to uh join and my
co-founder is just been like a lean
stick of a man for as long as I've known
him and the fact that I'm getting close
to him is very surprising. I've known
him for I don't know eight years at this
point. So well I appreciate that. I
guess having fallen into kind of founder
life that you know taking care of
yourself almost kind of helps you be
better at the the work that you do. So
puts you in the game shape so to speak.
That's what I'm thinking, man. Sure hope
so. So, um, maybe another question along
the lines of kind of behind the scenes,
Alex, what we don't know about LinkedIn.
What is something that people assume
about you based on LinkedIn that isn't
true? I think they assume I spend a lot
of time on LinkedIn, that I spend a lot
of time writing all my posts. I think
they assume that I am not going to
respond when they reach out. I think
people, many of people who commented on
my post asking for that recent state of
LinkedIn report were genuinely surprised
that I responded and that I was not
automating my responses and people just
had this moment of like, wow, you
actually came through and it's like,
yeah, it's me in the coffee shop writing
to you direct from my own brain and my
own two hands like this is what I do.
That is amazing. we can kind of get into
that kind of play and also a little bit
about how you do your system. But I I
kind of want to get into the journey
first and going back to kind of maybe
back to the first time you started
consistently posting or you're like I
want to do this. What was the motivation
and inspiration to start investing in
your presence here on this platform?
It was because I was learning at my job
of sales leadership and my boss had
indicated that I had done a good job
with that SDR team turnaround that you
alluded to earlier and that uh others in
town were talking about it and that was
the first time in my career that
anything of that nature had happened
where I hadn't even conceived of anybody
outside of the company knowing what I
was doing or thinking well of it. And it
the motivation was to just sort of
journal my thoughts and my ideas in
public to see if that was true. And I
thought I'll just put it to the test if
if I'm at all good at this. Writing down
what I know will be a way of seeing if
people respond negatively. I'll know I
have to go back to the drawing board. If
positively and or anything in between,
I'll know something. And uh the positive
response to it was the reason I felt
confident kicking off my consultancy was
just I realized I knew at least enough
to help people one or two steps behind
me in in my one area of business which
at that time was just sales leadership.
Um and that was enough. I didn't need
anything more than that. I just thought
I'll just start helping out and people
will take notice. I think I hope it
turned out to be true they did. That is
pretty cool. And uh so it sounds like
you had some positive signals, but I
imagine it wasn't all gravy. Were there
any challenges that you faced early on?
Yeah, I mean I I didn't know what I was
doing. There was no real system for it.
The closest thing to a LinkedIn thought
leader you had was do you remember Josh
Fector? Yes. Yes, I do. Bam media. Bam.
BF whatever it was. This is like the the
original broetry, right? And like that
was that was the best we had as far as
you know how to do LinkedIn. We had Oleg
whatever his name was just posting like
I don't know how he got viral but there
was you know the Bridget Hyestin and so
forth who just like sort of the mega
virals there wasn't a lot going on in
B2B there wasn't Justin Welsh was still
a director of sales uh so many things
that we now take for granted um were not
there so it was just the challenge was I
was just writing my thoughts down
pulling from where I could and then
creating what has now become a strategy.
But it um it's almost better that way
because now there's so much it's
distracting like how to do LinkedIn
courses. I can't think of a single how
to do LinkedIn for what we now think of
as like thought leadership and being a
creator. This is before creator mode was
a thing. This is back when there was
only one like button. Um there was no
LinkedIn lives, events, audio. There was
just you write post, people reach out.
That was it. So very kind of blue sky
thing at the time. So that was a
blessing and a curse. Nobody to teach me
what to do, but also nobody to distract
me. And was there a point where things
started to click? Yeah, like a month and
maybe a month in of maybe like four or
five posts in a contact that I knew from
a couple years prior like very very
vaguely like we were at a party one time
reached out and said, "Hey, I'm going my
sales team like saw you in my LinkedIn
newsfeed. We should talk." And then I
just signed them as a client for
consulting, assigned them as a client
for SDR services. had a huge
transformative impact on their company.
They paid us over
$200,000. And I was like, "This is
working. Like, I have the proof." He
said, "I saw you in my LinkedIn
newsfeed. I have the invoices to prove
it. Like, let's go." And so, and then it
started to become more systematic where
that happened again and again and again.
And I think we had about 136 closed one
deals for the agency sourced from my
LinkedIn. And at this point, it's over,
you know, 6.5 million of revenue from
that. And then the software sales and
valuation is just adding and adding and
I'm rapidly on the way towards uh eight
figures of LinkedIn source revenue. Not
all margin but agencies have pretty low
margin but at the same time like
nonetheless has been a huge just wealth
generator for me since. So it started
from the very humble beginnings of just
journaling in public and became like a
homegrown system that I've built myself.
That is quite impressive and congrats on
those feats. So it seems like you went
through a few iterations, right? You
started in sales and went to kind of SEO
services and to LinkedIn. The personal
branding change. What were those pivots?
A little bit worrisome. And deciding we
kind of had a seven figureure SDR
services business that we had decided we
no longer wanted, but giving it up all
at once was unthinkable, right? Like
what happens to our income? So we
decided to give it up slowly and pivot.
And I would just slowly start talking
more about content marketing and lead
genen and SEO and BD marketing overall
rather than just SDR. And so that was
kind of a you can see on the revenue
graphs at our company like the business
line revenue you can see the SDR one go
up up up up and then contents like kind
of down here and then slowly we let go
of a seven figureure business unit and
make a new one over the course of three
quarters. And on LinkedIn, what was
happening is I was posting about that
transition, but also just saying here's
what I am now. I didn't say here's what
I am now explicitly. I would just talk
about new things and people would
conclude that that's what I was now. Um,
some of the OGs will remember like, oh
yeah, I remember when you were talking
about sales development all day. I was
like, yeah, I don't do that anymore
ever. But once in a while I'll post
about outbound and people will come out
of the woodwork because it's still
somehow baked into my like algorithm or
audience that like if I talk about
outbound there's a little bit of a
weight behind it because I spent years
in that segment. But it was surprisingly
easy to just talk about new things
suddenly are a new thing. You change
your headline, change your banner,
change your post topics and then now you
have to go back several years to find my
outbound posts. They're there. you can
find them, but takes a few months to
really rebrand. What about the
networking element? Obviously, you have
your existing base that you know they're
along for the ride, right? And and some
of them will move on and be interested
in that stuff and engage. Others may
not. How did you like kind of sculpt
your network and shape it as you were
evolving? It was tough. A lot of people
saying, "Hey, this is what you're doing
now, it sounds like, or hey, can you do
this old service for me?" and I had to
really engage them on like the story of
why we transitioned. So, lots of just
hand-tohand DMing of like explaining the
transition, sitting down with people,
tons of offline meetings, people be
like, "Hey, it looks like you're doing
this new thing now." And I explain it to
them and hundreds of, you know,
explanations later, suddenly people are
like, "Yeah, yeah, I remember when you
told me about that." And they get it. A
lot of the people that were engaging
with me were connected to the new buyer
persona. So like a head of sales is not
that much different from the same
company's head of marketing. So there
was a bit of like forming new
connections and just literally connect
requesting to tons of VPs of marketing,
engaging with new content. So instead of
engaging with sales content, I'm
engaging with founders and CRO's and
CMOs. But that was in my control. Again,
like a few months of doing that, it was
starting to build up. You got to really
take an action in your own hands. Like
you really have to force the market to
believe in your pivot without telling
them that it's a pivot. Like don't say
it's a pivot. just do it. But then it's
effective. But yeah, connecting, DMing,
offline meetings, posting, literally
everything you do on LinkedIn changes
and offline too. Off LinkedIn as well
has to match that change for it to be
effective. So it sounds like a little
bit of brute force, but obviously for
all those new connections you meet, it's
kind of a easy transition and maybe even
like moving from the SEO kind of content
world to LinkedIn, that's actually
probably a more natural progression,
right? cuz like almost the channels of
communication changed a lot during that
time which is convenient, right? Yeah.
I'm kind of curious. We talked a lot
about I guess you know your branding and
your evolution, your network. What was
going on with how you approached content
or your LinkedIn in general I guess your
system if you will. What it look like
and what has it evolved to? Uh well in
the past I was posting an average of one
to two times a week for many years. So
like nowhere near what people say now if
you got to post every day. I was like no
way. And I would engage a good amount.
So I would just spend time in the feed.
U there was no aware back then. So I
would just spend time in the feed
commenting on posts and trying to be
insightful in in quips in public and
comments and stuff and I would do plenty
of offline meetings with other people
who were also growing on LinkedIn. So
there's a lot of people who I had met
offline also trying to do the same thing
and we would engage with each other. It
just formed this like wasn't a pod. It
was just a bunch of people who when we
saw each other in the feed were like,
"Oh yeah, that guy." I was just doing
that and I didn't have a system. Lately,
I've been more systematizing content. I
mean, I'm going to release the aware
customtuned AI writer soon, but like I
have a AI writer trained on my own top
hundreds of posts. So, if I talk about a
same topic I've talked about before or a
similar one, it sounds like me because
it is me, you know? And uh this didn't
exist when I was starting out. The
imagery, I used to do all the graphics
myself. I would take Excel file
screenshots. Canva didn't exist. So I
didn't have really much at all except,
you know, screenshots of our client
reports. And now I have a carousel guy,
an infographic guy, branded Figma
templates for all my stuff. You know,
there's just more infrastructure. And
with infrastructure, you can you could
do more. You pave the highways and you
go faster than horse and buggy. I made
it work. But now I have a car on a
highway. Uh but I had to build that over
a longer period of time. Um so the
system sort of became like how do I not
spend my whole day on LinkedIn to get
the things done need to get that done.
And now I spend remarkably little time
on LinkedIn as far as what people might
think. I'm excluding like customer
service here because a lot of aware
customers contact us on LinkedIn. That's
not marketing, that's customer service.
But for the actual marketing time, it's
not that much. Podcasts can be clipped
into video and posted. I've developed a
writing practice that I can write my own
content pretty quick. The AI trained on
my voice helps me get drafts out the
door that I can then plus or minus 30%
of and build on. The engagement I do
through aware and it's much quicker than
doing it by hand. All these things just
every aspect of it has received this
attention and systemization which has
not reduced authenticity but increased
it. I now have the bandwidth to be
better in all these channels because I'm
not so strapped for time. So I can spend
more time reading and thinking and
talking to people in a real way because
I'm not spending eight hours a day
spinning my wheels on LinkedIn. The
influencers who say, "Yeah, spend three
hours a day commenting." It's like,
"What impression are you leaving?" You
know, I'm at no more than an hour a day
max, including customer service, PR,
marketing. Um the basics, 20 minutes a
day, no more. basics is like your is
that more engagement or is that the
content itself? Engagement and inbox.
Yeah. Okay. And then the other 40
minutes is writing. Do you have like a
writing practice or uh writing managing
designers, managing video editing,
recording the content itself? So like
setting up the camera, recording the
content, scripting things like getting
LinkedIn live set up, tweaking with
Streamyard, just all the stuff in and
around it. Um, I mean, I have the rest
of my businesses to run, so I just I
must spend no more than really an hour a
day on it. Yeah, that's impressive, I
gotta say. And you are you posting daily
now? Almost six times a week on average.
Okay. What's your take on people who are
like getting involved now? Do you think
there's like a right frequency to start
at or does that depend? It's got to
depend. Like I said earlier, it's been
overs systematized, I think, by the rags
to riches crowd and the I was broke a
year ago, now I'm a LinkedIn whatever. I
have this many followers. Not telling
you what they're making on the back end
and it's often not that much. But
there's all there's all this like do do
this and you'll be rich stuff for
LinkedIn. But when I think about to how
I started, I started as like a
professional journal. And so there was
no cadence that I must post at unless I
had something to say. So starting out,
I'd recommend it be a business journal
and post when you have something to say.
Once you're in the habit of coming up
with these with ideas based on a daily
reflection, right? Like two bullet
points a day in an iPhone notes dock and
then writing once a week one or two of
those into a full post. Once that's down
pat for you, great. Repurpose. Create
media out of it. like start to build on
the production value. But people do the
best on LinkedIn when it begins as them
showing up with the lessons they've
learned, trying to help others in their
industry and not trying to do LinkedIn,
but trying to share knowledge,
credibility that they've earned in the
trenches of whatever job they're doing.
That is an amazing perspective and I
kind of agree with you uh and having
kind of worked with a few founders when
they kind of jump in almost frequency is
arbitrary, right? depends what they have
to say. And I think a recipe for
disaster is I'm going to do five to
seven a week and not having the right
kind of underpinnings or structure or
foundation to actually feed the ideas
into that because that's a place where
it dries up. There are multiple places I
guess in that you call it an idea or
content funnel where you know from
inception to posted content where it
could all fall apart and yeah like that
organic approach. I wanted to dig in.
You hit the buzzword bingo with AI.
Honestly, I think what you're doing is
uh genius. What does that look like? Do
you have a custom GPT or uh or it was
effectively something like that or what
did you build to kind of make it your
life easier when it comes to writing? Um
well, I tried all the GPTs and all the
chat GPT prompts and stuff and they were
all pretty much garbage because um my
voice is pretty distinct at this point.
Uh, so I'm talking about an aware
feature. What we do is we our product
trains a model. It's actually
fine-tuning an open AI model on as many
posts as we have. So for me, it was I
think we did the last couple hundred of
my posts and then fine-tuned the model
that I can now prompt with a certain
thing and I'll get a draft back that's
pretty good because it's fine-tuned on
my history of writing. And sometimes if
it doesn't know, it makes stuff up
because if I take it in a direction I've
never written about, it's gonna it's
going to reach. So I have to be ready
for that. But especially for
repurposing, especially for addressing
similar topics in new ways. If you have
three posts about commenting and I want
to say these other four ideas about
commenting on LinkedIn, I could prompt
four new ways and it's going to be able
to draw from it because I have a base of
knowledge trained on it. And all of
these like 12step AI processes that I've
seen out
there, some of them are okay, but I've
never seen anything come close to at
least for my own voice to what Aware has
been able to build for me. We haven't
turned this feature on publicly. It's
still just request only. So for people
that are using aware, you won't see it
unless you ask. But that's what we built
and it's you don't need to spend all
this time dinking around in chat GPT.
just you'll be able to hit a button or
just ask us and we'll hit the button. 20
minutes later you have a little prompter
in your post creator and you can prompt
yourself or if you're an agency your
client's past writing history for a new
post and it's damn good. That is
compelling. Having been around around
the block a little bit in this LinkedIn
space, I've definitely tinkered and I
tried a lot of the different AI products
out there and they've been largely
disappointing. Yeah. Right. I think if
you're a good enough writer, it's almost
most of the time it's easier just to
kind of it is just write it yourself
unless you can get it to sound like you,
right? Fool yourself, you know, then you
can fool other people, right? It's the
bar, right? Is the bar for AI is is it
better than a blank page? And until uh
until this, nothing was better than a
blank page. It was almost actively
distracting to have this just dre that I
was supposed to what edit work with. It
was just like it I almost insulted
myself trying to start with the chat GPT
post as the baseline. You know, I was
like this is awful. I don't want to
start with this. I want to just create
for myself until now. And now I'm like
I'd rather start with a aware AI draft
because it's better than a blank page
which for me that's the threshold. All
right, I'm signing up to give that a
try. I want to dig back into the
commenting. Number one, it's amazing
that you could do all this commenting in
such a short amount of time. What's the
approach now? Like I guess how do you
think about targeting
frequency coordination with kind of your
post as well? For me or for somebody
starting out? Actually, I guess you can
answer the question both ways. Okay. I
think in the last month I've written in
total on my own posts and other posts
about 200 comments. That's too many. A
that's overwhelming. And B, you can't do
that without Aware. You just there's
just too much. Like there's no way you
without automation or Aware to
streamline it for you. and aware is not
automating my comments. How do we get
there? Um, one of my posts I wrote 900
comments in response to because there
was 900 comments people asking for the
thing I was distributing. So that's 900.
So the rest of it is 1500. A good amount
of those are comments responses on my
own posts. In terms of the outbound
comments, I have a few approaches. One
is my community feed. This is an aware
feed, which is people's posts from the
people that engage with me the most. So,
I'm just saying if you engage with me a
lot, you'll be on my community feed
automatically and I'll just easily be
able to engage with you, too. I have
because we sell to LinkedIn agencies and
teams and people who talk about
LinkedIn, I have the influencer list in
aware for the LinkedIn growth
influencers. You could make this
yourself with a spreadsheet or a
bookmarks bar, but just take more
clicks. Um, but a bunch of people that I
think are in the space that I want to
engage with their content on because my
comments on their content will be seen
as like entries in other people's feeds.
Fun fact, right now more of my profiles
appearances across LinkedIn are from my
comments than from my posts, which is
that new That's neat. Yeah. Did you just
see that new feature that came out in
the search? I did. I did. Yeah. I'm ever
since that came out, I'm like trying to
do more commenting myself as well. It's
convincing, isn't it? Yeah, I I've
always thought that there's more upside
in commenting. It's literally unc it's
like there's no cap. You can comment all
day long, right? Probably some people
do. Me, too. One guy was commenting
eight hours a day and then he would used
a wear to do it in two hours a day. He's
still using it way too much in my
opinion. That's too much. But if you
save six hours a day of LinkedIn
obsession, that's well worth it. But
yeah, some people do this. Like I get on
calls with them and they're like, I do
500 comments a day. And I'm like, how
does that impact your life? And one guy
was like, "He's 100,000 followers, 500
comments a day." And he said, "It's
routinely an argument with his
girlfriend." I was like, "I freaking bet
it is if you're just commenting that
much, you know? I mean, how could you
not be on your devices all the time? It
must be that draining." And I was like,
"Dude, you're going to cry when you see
this." And I showed him the aware
engagement feed and he was like pretty
much there. He was like, "Holy shit." I
was like, "I'm not saying do less than
500. I'm just saying, what about two
hours a day versus six? Can we negotiate
a little bit and like use this? That
does happen. People do spend freaking
all day doing this. I gota wonder if
you're spending that much time like how
do you do your work or if you're running
a business like how do you have sales
calls or do the work? Yeah. So that's
interesting. I want to shift gears a
little bit. Okay, I want to talk about
this report that you just generated and
I'm kind of curious maybe start with top
level, you know, what your most
compelling findings were and I think
maybe moving on after that like what did
you find kind of surprising? It was a
lot in that I thought was interesting.
Much of it confirmed a lot of the rumors
we hear. You hear um
engagement out will lead to engagement
in and that's true. There's a 648
correlation R squared which is stronger
than normal correlation between comments
you write and comments you receive. Now
that is this was before the comment
profile appearances thing came out and
it was the best data I had but I was
like that's really justifying of why you
should do this. The outliers were like
mega influencers on the one side of like
they just have so much coming in that
they just can't the relationship breaks
down. When you receive thousands of
comments a day, you just cannot respond
to them all. There's no way. Even with
aware, it's too much. So then the
correlation breaks down. On the other
end, you have the automated spam
comments. So like you know those bot
products where it's like plug in and
we'll do your engagement for you. 200
comments a day done for you in the
background. It's like, okay. And those
are the ones where they do a lot out and
don't get much in because it's all crap,
right? It's like the pods, right?
They're lamp pod or things like that.
Like their AI comments and group
comments that too. There's just there's
also now, if you're curious, like
standalone products where you just plug
it in. It's not a pod. It just does a
bunch of outbound commenting for you,
like automated. I tried one that was it
was embedded in LinkedIn. It would do
like an AI comment for you. It just
didn't feel right. But I haven't seen I
haven't gotten to that point where it's
just like a here's a boatload of
comments, press a button, go. Yeah, I've
seen a couple of those. They're not
doing very well on the business side
because I think people are realizing
like that doesn't work. Another
interesting finding from the report was
that on average people in aware are
seeing slightly more total engagement,
but average engagement per post is flat
or ever so slightly down across the
board. But because of the increased
posting, they're making up the
difference. So they're posting 28% more
on average. And yet the median person
not in aware, their engagement is down
about 25% in the last year. And so if
their engagement is down and the
engagement rate percent is overall up,
which is what we've seen, that means
their reach is likely down like at least
30 if not 40%. which would make sense.
More people responding to the advice of
create on LinkedIn, that means more
supply of posts. But the demand of
eyeballs looking for content has not
risen that fast. It's rising about 1.3%
a year of user growth on LinkedIn in the
United States. And that's who most
people are selling to anyway. There's
way more than 1.3% a year growth in
creators. What do you think is going to
happen, right? Like to supply and
demand, it's got to something's got to
give. So that told me like it confirmed
my thought that yes, the bar has gone
up. You can't get away. You can't get
tons and tons of free reach flowing out
the gills like you used to for me
content. It's just got to be better.
It's got to be more consistent. It's got
to be all these things. But my reaction
to that was not give up. It was do
better. And that's the thing I hear when
I hear complaints on LinkedIn. There's
almost like this defeist tone of like,
well, the days of the golden days are
gone. It's like, okay, the silver days
are here. I'll be fighting it out in the
bronze days. Will you? You know, um,
it's like if you've built an audience on
Facebook in the early days, now you have
a big Facebook profile, you're golden.
You did it at the right time. So, I
think it's if you want to start or
really go on a growth spurt, now is the
time to invest. So that by the time
LinkedIn becomes a much more pay-to-play
focused environment, you'll have that
foundation built and you won't have to
spend as much, if not any, building up
your presence from scratch. Um, so the
golden day is I'll even admit that it's
over, but if I do, then the silver day
is here, right? Like it's almost as good
of a day and it just means you got to
try a little harder, which fine, do it.
So maybe I'll reduce that to maybe a
single question. In its current form, do
you think LinkedIn is overrated or
underrated? Underrated still. All right.
Still by far the best platform. Job
titles, company names, professional work
associations, there's you don't get that
with any other platform. I mean, Reddit,
what am I going to age with the Zo Man
95 and expect that I know it's you? Like
that doesn't work. Exactly. It's all
trolls. Cool. Well, that's some exciting
findings in the report and makes a ton
of sense and very validating for the
work that you're doing. I want to shift
back to you. Obviously, in the intro, I
talked a lot about the business impact
of your investment in LinkedIn.
Personally, what's been the impact? I've
had to go through a journey of like
disconnecting in some way with it. I
think there was a period where I got I
realized that LinkedIn had become a part
of my identity in a way that I didn't
want. And I would say in the last year
and a half, I've begun to detach a lot
more from that, which has improved my
content cuz I just give fewer fs about
what I'm saying. So it's just I've just
become naturally punchier because I'm
not as like invested in what everyone
thinks of me. Like I care what fewer
people think of me than I did before. So
that's been good. I've met a lot of
great people. Like I've met a lot of
wonderful genuine friends, partners that
went on to become good friends from
LinkedIn. Not just people I worked with,
but people I maybe I worked with them
and then became friends or vice versa
from this. It's kept me like sharp,
professionally relevant, all these
things. The downside is I mean even even
if across the board across all functions
of the business I'm spending an hour a
day, that's an hour a day not spent
reading in the forest. So there is a
drawback for in that sense, right? The
philosopher needs to be in the forest.
He does. You know, Walden was not
written in a post, but I've made that
trade-off on purpose thus far, and I
think it's been overall good. Couple
years ago, it suggested that my wife
build her business on LinkedIn instead
of on Instagram. Turned out to be a
really good decision. Now, she's an
influencer in her own right. And there's
been tons of good things from it. I
mean, I've refined my writing in a big
way from this. It's generated the wealth
from business acquisition and sales that
has allowed me to experience more
personal freedom, which I credit to
LinkedIn. So, there's just so many
knock-on effects of having made this
investment that I I can't be grateful
enough for it. That's amazing. It's a
bountiful and there's still a lot of
opportunity there according to Alex
Boyd. Uh I think so. We're rounding the
corner towards the end and of the
podcast. sad time, but I have a couple
of lightning round questions. If you'll
indulge me, I will. If you were running
LinkedIn for a day, what's the first
thing you change? I would advertise the
business page manager more and increase
the price of it. If I was running
LinkedIn, yeah. Yeah. Um, I'm answering
that question as if I'm the shareholder
of LinkedIn, not the CEO. That's what I
would do. You didn't know there was one?
Yeah, I would advertise more. I know
there's like you can advertise on it,
but you know beside and there's a like a
social management piece, but I didn't
know there was like a paid one. Go to
the business page, you'll see it pop up
on the top, but it's like it's weird
hidden. It's like why hide it so much?
Is it useful? I haven't used it, but
people that I work with have said it's
very useful and they're happy with their
purchase. All right, interesting. Yeah,
check it out. All right, next question.
What is a LinkedIn trend you wish would
go away? Running lead magnet posts and
then not sending the magnet. Even worse,
sending it and having it be all chat GPT
dre tossed into a notion file and called
something like the million-dollar sales
playbook when it is not. That needs to
die, right? I see that. I see that like
everywhere these days. And I kind of at
one point I wanted to do it because I
have, you know, insights to share now,
too. But it's like h like it seems like
a little like played out or cheesy, but
uh what do you think? I mean, you if
you'll deliver Yeah. do it. If you won't
deliver, don't. It's like if you have
something good that you've worked on
that is actually good. And I don't mean
you shortcuted your way with a chat GPT
deep research prompt. That's not that
doesn't qualify. Then do it and deliver.
And it might take you hours and hours to
deliver 900 responses to it. That's
okay. Be prepared for that. If that's
what it takes, just do what you say
you'll do. So if I don't begrudge
anybody at growth hack if you do what
you say you'll do. If you won't do that,
don't bother. All right. So, the send
the ebook for the common play. If you
can deliver, do it. According to Alex.
All right, last question before we start
to wrap things up. Who do you follow and
learn from? Who do you think is crushing
it? A few people you might want to shout
out. People I've been taking inspiration
from for a long time are Amy
Wolis, Greg
Hed, Ken Marshall, Jonathan Bland.
Okay, those are some new ones. I would
say if you know Amy Volis, the other
three I don't think you know are quite
familiar. I'm going to check those
people out. We'll link them in the
recap. So, I appreciate you sharing your
time and insights with us today. Like,
we could talk forever. We should
definitely have you back again because I
know you're a wealth of knowledge just
from reading all the posts out there.
So, we'll have to make another
appointment later this year. Is there
anything exciting happening at Aware
that you want to share with the
audience? We're releasing the two to
three most gamechanging features that we
have released in a year and a half this
month. The AI post generator that's
trained on your voice is one. The second
one is influencer discovery. Ability to
generate lists of influencers by looking
within aware's own data by keyword of
what's in their profile, what they post
about, scored. It's like favicon but
easier and better. Uh, right within
aware included in the subscription. I
can't wait. I'm so pumped. Yeah, I'm
excited for that. Is there a third one?
I think I said two. There are others
that I think are better, but they're um
they're still in the GitHub phase, not
in the release this month phase. March,
we'll keep it to those two. April, stay
tuned for some cool stuff. All right,
I'll be watching this space. Thank you
so much for sharing with us today.
Everybody, go follow Alex Boyd. He has
so many great insights. I feel like
every time I see in my feed,
enlightening, you know, I learn
something. I evolve my perspective. And
thank you for sharing here and sharing
there. And until next time, stay
connected. Thank you, Brad.
If you enjoyed this episode, follow Brad
and Spectre on LinkedIn for hot takes
and tactical executive branding advice.
For the readers in the audience,
subscribe to LinkedIn Famous on
Substack. And if you really love this
episode, leave us a review on Apple
Podcast, Spotify, or the podcasting
platform of your choice. Until next
time, stay bold, authentic, and keep on
creating.
[Music]