We are entering an era where the things
people are saying about you may become
more important than the things you say
about yourself.
I think that's really scary. But my
existential crisis aside, I believe
there's something we can do about it. If
you can take a second right now to
Google yourself, and by yourself, I mean
your brand. So for me, I searched up
what is spark Toro and who is Amanda
Natividad. Now look at the snippet. Do
you like what you see? What's good, bad
or fine? What do you want to see
reinforced? Or what descriptions should
be there? This is our starting point
because increasingly people are forming
opinions about your brand before they
ever visit your site. They do it through
reviews, subreddits, best of lists, AI
answers snippets, and all the other
public material floating around the web.
Third-party discussion is winning
category visibility, and AI systems can
reinforce whatever public claims are
easiest to retrieve and repeat.
This episode is not about why that's
happening. And actually, if you missed
last week's episode called attribution
is breaking, measurement needs to grow
up, that covers the why. So if you
missed it, go ahead and check that out
first. This episode is about what to do
about your public record. Because if the
public record is shaping how people
perceive your brand, then marketers need
a playbook for strengthening that public
record on purpose.
I'm Amanda Natividad and welcome to
ZeroClick Marketing.
Before I get into the sevenstep
playbook, here are a few names I'll be
referencing. Will Reynolds, the founder
of Seer Interactive, who's been doing a
lot of smart work around GEO and AI
search. Ross Simmons, the founder of
Foundation, and he recently published a
big piece of research on Reddit's role
in B2B SAS search. I will also mention a
recent search engine land article on why
some content shows up in AI overviews
and why some doesn't. And then I'm also
going to bring up Alert Mouse, a Google
alerts competitor and Spark Toro, the
makers of fine audience research
software. All right, so step one, audit
the story the internet is already
telling about you. Before you create
anything new, look at what already
exists. Search your brand name. Search
your category plus your brand. Search
your competitors plus your brand. Look
at what comes up and look at the
snippets and citations that show up
first. And by the way, if you need a
better way to track your brand mentions,
sign up for Alert Mouse. It's a free
Google Alerts competitor, but this
actually works. You'll get a daily email
digest of all your brand mentions and
alert mouse even flags the biggies like
major media mentions. Now in this audit
you're trying to answer a very simple
question. What claims about us are
already winning not what is true
internally rather what is actually
visible. This matters because repeated
public claims can become
disproportionately influential.
Will Reynolds from Seir Interactive
recently blogged about how one old
negative review about Seir got serviced
repeatedly in branded AI prompts because
it was public and duplicated across
enough places to be treated like signal.
In Will's words, because it existed and
AI goes deeper than humans do, AI found
it. The key takeaway here, start by
figuring out what the web currently
believes. Now, step two, treat
third-party surfaces like part of your
brand footprint.
Ross Simmons research of Reddit in B2B
SAS basically says Reddit isn't just
stealing clicks from best of keywords.
It's showing up right in the middle of
category discovery, which means a lot of
buyers are meeting your category and
maybe even your brand in a Reddit thread
before they ever see your site. So those
forums and review sites, keep an eye on
them and get involved. Don't spam them
and don't become a reply guy, but
understand which third party services
influence buyer assumptions in your
category and where possible contribute
useful information there. Oh, and by the
way, do you know if Reddit specifically
is where people would fathomably
discover your brand? Because if you're
not sure, you should search your
audience in Spectro. Literally, you can
type out a plain English query
describing your audience like you would
to a colleague, and you can see which
subreddits, which social networks, and
search and AI tools your audience hangs
out in or uses. Because if buyers are
meeting you or your category there
first, those surfaces are part of your
brand footprint whether you like it or
not. Step three, separate weak claims
from strong facts. Once you audit the
landscape, split what you find into two
buckets. Bucket one, weak but visible
claims, old reviews, thin comparisons,
outdated summaries, past complaints,
things like that. Bucket two, strong
facts you can actually support. Original
data, customer counts, your own case
studies with your verified outcomes with
real customers. You have those, right?
Note your own product explanations,
expert points of view. The thing is AI
and search systems are not good judges
of truth. They're often working from
what is available, repeated, and easy to
reuse. That's a core lesson from Seager
Interactives experiment. And it also
aligns with search engine land's recent
article that stated retrieval and
citation depend on structure and
extractability, not just classic ranking
strength. So your job in this step is
not to complain about bad evidence. It's
to take stock of all of it, good and
bad. Step four, publish facts only you
can publish. Most brands publish generic
top offunnel content that any competent
intern or LLM could have drafted, but
then they wonder why it's not getting
cited or amplified. But hey, if you
happen to be getting success with this,
you do you. Keep it up. But don't stop
there. What you really need to do is
publish the stuff only you can credibly
say. Your data, your category
perspective, your customer patterns,
your explanation of how the product
actually works, your receipts. In SER
interactives experiment, they found that
when they published a page with specific
retention data, those facts started
getting cited. That's the kind of
content I mean actual facts that
strengthen the public record. Step five,
make your content easy to retrieve,
site, and summarize. So, Search Engine
Land's recent piece argues that top
rankings do not guarantee AI overview
visibility and frames the problem as one
of retrieval, structure, and citations.
They found that content is more likely
to appear when it provides direct answer
units, strong structure, and visible
expertise signals. So, if you want your
content to make it into the public
record, make it easy to read and crawl,
put the answer high on the page, use
clear headings, write plainly, include
specific quotable lines,
state the claim, and support it. Make
the strongest parts legible to both
humans and machines. Step six, refresh
the public record proactively.
One of the more brutal lessons from Seir
Interactives experiment is that fixing
the record once may not be enough. Seir
found the effect of its public response
was not necessarily durable, which is
why the team moved toward a more
centralized and maintainable source of
truth. The public record is not a
one-time asset. It's a living system.
So, update your proof points. Publish
new data. Replace vague claims with
specifics.
Fill in the holes before weak third
party material fills them for you.
You're not trying to control the
narrative. You can't. But you can try to
make sure the strongest available
narrative is yours.
Step seven, our last step, measure
whether the public record is getting
stronger. Look for things like, are
better sources showing up for branded
searches? Are AI answers citing stronger
facts? Are more prospects mentioning the
right differentiators?
Are weak claims getting displaced? Are
branded queries increasing?
are third-party surfaces reflecting your
real positioning more accurately.
This is the work of reputation
management. You won't see outcomes right
away, but you can track what's changing.
Right now, the goal is to improve what
people find, read, infer, and repeat
about you before they ever visit your
site.
So if I were to boil this down, the
playbook is this.
Audit the current public record.
Treat third party surfaces as part of
your brand footprint. Identify the weak
claims that are winning.
Publish better facts that only you can
publish.
Structure them so they are easy to
retrieve and site. Refresh the record
continuously.
and measure whether the story the
internet tells about you is getting
better. Like it or not, your brand is
being shaped before anyone visits your
website. And if you're not actively
contributing to the public record that
informs that, somebody else will fill
the gaps. Thank you for listening,
friends. If you enjoy this episode and
want to see more playbooky frameworky
type things like this, let me know. Give
me a shout or please leave a kind
review. that really helps indie podcasts
like mine. So until then, I'll see you
next week, friends. Bye.