[Music]
y the next
episode yo I'm Devin Reed and I'm on a
mission to build a bigger and more
inspired career as a marketer Creator
and entrepreneur after 10 years in sales
and marketing and leading content for
two billion doll SAS startups I know one
thing real growth takes more than basic
tips and tricks and learning from the
best will help me reach my potential
let's ride so I'm traveling America for
candid street level conversations about
creativity marketing and playing by your
own rules you'll get practical advice to
grow your career confidence and income
and have fun doing it are you ready this
is read between the lines the show for
people who want to achieve phenomenal
[Music]
results content is the most powerful way
to grow your brand and business but that
requires creating high quality
differentiated content which is hard to
do so today we're going to learn from
one of the best my guest today is
Brandon
Hufford founder of grow Sprints where he
helps SAS companies go from 10 to 100
million ARR with short focused content
marketing Sprints I've learned a lot
from him just from following on LinkedIn
and I'm excited because this is the
first time that we're going to sit down
and go deep on content growth we're
going to cover the number one strategy
mistake that prevents marketers from
achieving massive results my go-to
framework work for creating original
content that Wows your audience every
single time and how to create
irresistible marketing offers that
resonate with your ideal buyers today
we're going all in are you ready let's
ride shout out to our sponsor goldcast
they are the B2B video content platform
they know that video is the most
effective medium for engaging audiences
and building longlasting brand
relationships and they do more than just
host amazing digital events they
recently released content lab which is
an AI powered video tool that I use to
turn long form content into branded
clips and minutes not ours and it's cool
because you can use your digital event
footage or upload video files to open
your account go to
gold. or hit the link in the show notes
now on to the show thanks for hanging
out with me man yeah dude this is fun
I'm really excited I want to jump right
into it into something you wrote in
March 2024 now I'm going to start there
because I'd known about you for a while
but this was something that you wrote
that turned me into a fan in one single
post and this was your checkbox
marketing idea and so I want to start
with that because I truly believe it is
the biggest problem in B2B marketing
right now and it's a mindset challenge
it's a mindset problem in my opinion not
really a tactic problem or a skill
problem so can you help like let's start
with you like walk me through what
checkbox marketing is and then how you
came up with it okay so so to explain it
I kind of have to tell you a story so I
was a teacher for 10 years High School
teacher I tried climbing that ladder I
was an assistant principal for a little
bit not for me right I loved it but like
being broke sucks and I was like doing
marketing on the side and a friend was
like hey go work somewhere so I worked
at a couple agencies I ended up going
in-house at active campaign for a little
bit because I wanted that experience I
get to work with a really great manager
his name is Benjamin Elias he's back
there now and I went to do some new
things there so my job was literally I
just listed out a bunch of things in a
spreadsheet when I was going to start it
when I think it would be done by and I
just went down the list that was in
checkbox marketing that was like things
I needed to get done sure I'll give you
an example we're an email marketing
platform Devin we had no
newsletter like what so I was like all
right cool we need a newsletter so I
went in there uh we had a thing at the
bottom of the blog that said get updates
and me as a marketer was like surely
nobody gives a [ __ ] about get updates
nobody wants that went to the team it
took of course it you know when you're
in the bureaucracy right it takes two
weeks to find out how many people are on
an email list even though it should be a
button click that we should all have
access to there was like 20,000 people
wow who wanted
updates Devon did we send them anything
no updates they're clicking get updates
and they're getting nothing they're
getting nothing so I was like all right
we can send this to people and
immediately they were like we want to
know how many trials this is going to
generate what's this what's this and I
had to spread spreadsheet the [ __ ] out
of it and then they're like we're going
to need 27 meetings with design cuz they
want to design it and product marketing
wants it and immediately no immediately
no like just let me do something let me
cook I looked at the list and I call
this uh I can even share this with
people called it the spreadsheet that
made me quit my job uh because it was
like a weekly blog a weekly this a daily
this and it was just going through and
checking the boxes and I noticed the
more I talk to other people at companies
the more I grew growth prints and
started Consulting we were all doing
this like we never it's good to start
with output when you don't know what the
impact would be right like I think them
pushing me early to be like how many
trials is this newsletter going to
generate and I'm like can I send the
Thing Once yeah it's like how how do you
set a goal without any Benchmark data I
would just be making it up and they're
like cool make it up well if I crush it
I'm wrong yeah and if I'm way under I'm
wrong so again why why not 20 webinars a
month why not one there's no reason for
it it's just we're just going through
and checking the boxes and that's what
like I was just heartbroken and I kept
hearing everybody go B2B is boring B2B
is boring B2B is boring and I was so
dead set on figuring out why that when
my brain just did that like magical
connection I was like oh it's because of
exactly what I experienced when I was in
house we're just checking boxes except
the one that matters which is resonance
and impact that's interesting so I I
didn't know it came from like a personal
experience in the the spreadsheet that
made you quit your job oh yeah that was
super rough and I know that I'm not
alone in that so it sounds like for for
like marketers listening right now
watching you can probably like self
diagnose that you're doing checkbox
marketing if what you're like to your
your strategy or to-do list every week
is just kind of going through the
motions and like output focused 100% I
think most marketers especially when
you're in-house I think this is even
true for you and me we want two things
right like we want what we do to have
impact obviously yeah but we also want
to like it we want to like the marketing
materials we're creating we want to be
proud of your work absolutely and you
want to be able to share it with your
peers and people be like oh that's
really cool like people compliment you
they're like oh that's cool people with
taste like this stuff and when you share
it with your peers they're proud of you
you're proud of yourself there's a lot
of us that are not proud of the work
we're doing every single week because
we're being asked to like check these
boxes over and over and over so what's
the cause of it and the B2B uh let's
just say B2B I work in SAS mostly I'm
guessing you probably do too yeah almost
exclusively so you're working with like
maybe you're talking to a New Prospect
right and you're starting to see like
all right they do checkbox marketing
what do you think is like the root cause
because I don't think it's the what like
the doers the individual contributors
the manager level maybe some director
levels that are like I'm enjoying this
and this is what I signed up for I think
we all get uh you know you get courted
right as you're interviewing and it's
like here's these things we're going to
do here's the impact you're going to
have right and you're like you get star
ey and you're like yeah that sounds
awesome that's what I want to do mhm you
do your boarding then you start doing
the work and I think it's a at least for
me like I think it's a slow like you
slip into it and you kind of almost
don't even realize like oh now I'm just
going through the motions and I just
have these output like metrics if you
will but like where does it come from
though cuz I don't think that's the
source of it so this had that happened
to me when I was in house too where I
started and I was like pumped to write
blogs and do things um and then after 6
months of writing you know my 25th blog
you know I'm looking at my wife and it's
like am I really on this planet to write
a [ __ ] blog a week for until I die
yes like that's yes right it's my life's
my life's purpose and if that is your
life's purpose more power to you I just
don't think it's any of ours so I think
underneath a lot of that I think is two
things one it is this like VC backed
startups have like lent itself to a lot
of that of like growth at all costs push
the output to an insane level Yeet a
million dollars a year into the sun in
Google and Facebook ads you know is just
like throw more at it growth at all
costs I think now that we're seeing a
lot more of what I would call like post
VC marketing where budgets aren't
unlimited and we do have to think about
impact more than output um that's going
to change and I think also it's hard to
break out of I think just as human
nature it's hard to break out of habits
yeah the this is what we've all always
done um there's a system in place
there's a system in place at the company
yeah and it's what the expectation is
and you have to have an honest
conversation with your boss or
leadership or your team of like how much
output are we willing to sacrifice for
the sake of maybe more impact yeah and
that's a hard conversation to have
because again I think we've all just
been turned into what I would call like
spreadsheet marketers or spreadsheet
Engineers where like everything has to
be in the [ __ ] spreadsheet and it's
like it it completely destroys uh
creativity there's a great book called
Alchemy by Rory Sutherland where talks
about that he's like if you look at all
the things that have had big impact none
of those came out of spreadsheets none
of those were like micro optimized into
success you know you're not going to
0.01% increase your way into tripling
Revenue yeah you have to take big swings
and we don't in a lot of companies you
just don't have a framework of like this
percentage is for big swings this is for
safe bets it's why a lot of like my work
now thinks in It's thinking in bets so
I've I've actually experienced this
before I won't say I won't say which
company but I started and we know which
company it is and sorry uh and it was um
the expectation was we want uh two blogs
every week it was the classic it's it's
it sounds cliche it probably sounds like
I'm making this up for the sake of this
conversation but I think that's also why
it felt like you were peering into my
soul when you wrote about checkbox
marketing cuz you put a name to this
like terrible experience and almost like
phenoma that like is happening right
yeah and so the expectation is too weak
and so I'm like and I'm you know I'm
resistant I'm like no like why would we
do that that's not a strategy and so I
did some digging you know I'm like
asking why asking why and it was because
the sales team wanted them the sales
team believed marketing equaled blogs
and so when I got finally like had a BD
or someone like in charge of this ask
and it was like well we have these new
verticals and I want people to hit the
website and see we're legit yeah we want
to see action so I I there's two things
one said I can actually empathize with
with what I think you were trying to
accomplish which is I call it a heat
check or legit check like do you know if
you go to like the
reader. and you're like click the blog
if I'm talking about content marketing
there better be a pretty legit blog with
at least some content there so I get
that he's like I want there to be
something there what I was trying to
reframe is like no one's doing that
though for the SAS company people aren't
like looking for answers and content and
going to this company's website.com
clicking the corporate blog and like
sifting through things like that's not
how people find information MH and so um
I I the first quarter I I I did it I
said fine I found like a writer cuz they
didn't care they chbt hadn't like come
out yet but I was like if you don't
really care and you just want a block
something I'll just get like a sheep
writer and we'll just pump it up so I
did that one quarter the next quarter
like the ass came back like H how many
blogs are we doing like corporate blogs
not SEO mind you not not with any
thought of distrib thought leadership
we're building a category not category
content not thinking about distribution
not SEO optimized just like Bland
corporate blocks like we're proud to
announce we're the G2 leader in these 97
not that dude like what is a basic
keyword that people like will look for
plus like industry plus like our comp
you know what I mean just like the
basics the most Basics and so in the
second quarter I just didn't do it and I
just straight up didn't do it and we had
the biggest quarter of uh new pipeline
sourced because we actually did safe
bets or what I call bigger bets yeah and
didn't say anything until the end of the
quarter and so we had this you know
great numbers dashboards are looking
better we had like kind of started to
turn the ship around and it was like you
know the the marketing kind of recap
quarterly meeting I was like Deon what
did you guys do
differently and I said I didn't write a
single blog but here's what we did
instead and it was we launched like an
AI product and it was a big feature
product marketing LED it they did a
phenomenal job we helped amplify it and
that had the most single day demo
requests in company history and so I was
like you have to kind of like show that
you know you have to kind of like meet
them in the middle say fine I'll kind of
like concede a little bit and then show
them hey there's actually another way to
Market and it's based on outcomes and
impact and it was one mini campaign or
like a medium-sized campaign not a
million dollars not Billboards nothing
crazy flashy just really intentional and
methodical higher level execution you
didn't put your logo on the outside of
the sphere in Vegas no the sphere wasn't
opened yet I think so I think there's
two ways to get around this you did what
I would call like downside risk where
like let's say [ __ ] went bad and then
they're like Deo what did you do and
you're like I didn't do any blogs and
they're like well see numbers are down
and you're like well it doesn't have
anything to do with the fact that I did
no blogs you could also do like upside
risk where it's like okay cool you want
two blogs a week for the next quarter
we're going to do four a week and if
nothing changes we know they didn't do
anything it kind of De I think a lot
about that of like downside risk versus
upside risk so instead of not like I I
looked at my uh my lead flow and
pipeline compared to I I just wonder one
overlapped it with like my LinkedIn
Impressions which could not be you know
I think as marketers were like that's
not how this works but I was just
actually believe it is correlated and I
have we'll talk about that in a second
go ahead but less correlated than like
something like branded search where it's
like how many people are Googling our
brand that's actually correlated I'm
seeing more and more data that like
branded search is correlated one to one
with Revenue it's just like a couple
months before like they actually look
exactly the same um but I looked at it
and I'm like well these actually match
up really close you know they're a
little off because The Impressions come
before the revenue and I was like well
the downside risk would be if I really
want to test the impact don't post on
LinkedIn anymore yeah but the risk is if
I'm correct and Linkedin Impressions do
matter like my pipeline goes way down or
I can do upside risk and I can post
twice a day for the next quarter which
is what I'm doing and that is that sucks
and is hard and has other risks
associated with it but I'm I'd rather
take the upside risk and report back
than like the downside one I like that a
lot I like that that's how folks can
basically Escape checkbox marketing it's
one of the ways yeah yeah so on the the
reason I conceded on that first quarter
was like if he wants a legit check I'll
give them the legit check you hit the
page there's blogs there's content you
get what you wanted the other thing I
did to help escape this was bring data
which was okay you guys think that this
is going to make a meaningful impact
we're all about Revenue we're all about
pipeline gen how many like people are
seeing this like how many visits is this
page getting how many Impressions didn't
know the answer y so I went and got it
less than 3 100 visits on every blog
over like the last 90 days and like one
to zero like all combined no so like
each page each blog had less than 300 I
think the highest was 336 and I remember
that number cuz I like this is the most
traffic we're getting with what we're
doing and the money we're spending we're
getting 333 people to see this half of
it's probably the sales team clicking it
to send it to people and the conversions
anyone want to guess 0 to one yeah one
was the highest on conversion which
means someone uh I think one person
likes sign up for a Dem
yeah so I'm like we just like look at
this for a second and tell me this is
going to help reach that big
aspirational you know investor uh pushed
goal for Revenue yeah and even like
correlation right like if I can look
back and say hey here's all of our
clothes one how many of those people
were like hitting the blog or whatever
else um or how many I we can do like a
self-reported attribution has its own
flaws of course but I'm still a fan of
it of like building it out systems to
gather that again and again like
gathered in your form gather it when
they talk to sales gather it after their
Clos one and be like hey just again like
what was there any content that had an
impact on you right and I think a lot of
people will talk about that stuff but
it's not always the stuff we think it is
like a good example is gong right like I
would never be a Gong customer but God
damn if I didn't download every single
one of those things that was like if you
say this word you're going to lose your
sales if you have this slide in your
deck you're [ __ ] like that that sorry
yeah no that was like yeah that was
definitely the lead gen ad on LinkedIn
but I opted in for all of those because
I was like this really helps me do my
job better and it tapped into the right
piece of it now I'm sure you could see a
stronger correlation there than like
corporate blog so where should we put
our attention yeah you know so how can
B2B marketers Escape checkbox
marketing so the most important and
easiest way is what I call content IP
which is instead of defining a category
this is again something we did at active
campaign where we try to become customer
experience automation like active
campaign the value prop is email
Enterprise grade email marketing and
marketing automation $11 a month that's
it like don't over complicate it and
instead you got to the homepage and
you're like welcome to the customer
experience automation platform and if
you're selling to small businesses and
you don't have a defined ICP on purpose
which they don't and that's on purpose
we can talk about that if you want but
like when you have that going on you
can't confuse the [ __ ] out of everybody
who hits the homepage so instead of that
why don't we work on solving a problem
and when you become problem focused and
you name the problem and all of your
content exists to help your ICP solve
that problem all of a sudden the
checkboxes go away and it becomes let's
unify all of our marketing on solving
this one problem or this set of problems
or we'll solve this problem for this
person in a buying you know if you have
like a really complicated or like
multiproduct platform cool just slow
down like eat eat your steak one bite at
a time and just solve this problem for
these people this problem for these
people and just go through and then all
of a sudden it's like well let's all
agree what's the best way to reach them
the best way to reach them is this or
that we can do channels later but the
problem is we're really obsessed with
the channels and getting all of our
boxes checked yeah and we're not we've
lost sight of the problem so I like the
transition to content IP can you like
how do you define it for folks who maybe
aren't familiar content IP is simply
giving words or phrases to the problems
people have we all know that this sells
really well right if I if I've had a
problem for years I'll give you an
example not B2B right um I was reading a
book about like uh I don't even know
what is like fatherhood and like just
like guy stuff and there was this one
throwaway sentence where he said I
remember when my body used to feel like
a
weapon holy [ __ ] I have felt that way I
didn't have every former dad athlete
right knows a time when they felt that
way and we would always it's a very
common thing of like oh I used to be in
shape or I used to be able to do this or
that or whatever we feel like we've kind
of lost a step but I remember when my
body used to feel like a weapon I'll buy
I don't know what you're selling at this
point but I will buy all of it yeah I
don't care if it's a supplement or a
training program or life coaching I'm
buying it like I'm in yeah right when
you define that problem when you give
them a word or phrase to Define that
problem all of a sudden they just trust
you more than anybody else really what
we want especially in B2B especially in
SAS is just to be in the consideration
set or the default one that people think
of when they think about this problem
well that's the difference between
attention and mind share attention can
be fleeting but mind share is you said
something that resonated with me so
deeply that later days months years when
that problem arises I think of that
phrase and I think of Brennan for
example like checkbox marketing I feel
like that's is that your version of that
like is that your that's my IP yeah it's
weird that I'm like solving I'm doing
but it's I have to be meta about it
right I have to be very circular I'm
constantly fighting off dadbod that's
what I tell people like they're like
What's you like do like strength
training I'm like I'm just fighting
dadbod like that's what I'm trying to
trying to do yep um okay so content IP I
I agree part of it is naming it but I
think it's also the content that you
create to help battle it so for example
your uh checkbox marketing is like the
villain if you will right and your
content IP let Frameworks templates
guides like the show potentially but
we'll talk about that actually in a
second is like also part of your content
IP right so it starts with labeling the
problem you have to understand your
audience so deeply that like that's what
I said earlier like felt like you like
peered into my soul that's what it does
right that the weapon line or the
checkbox you you want I call it like the
snapping point where you say it and they
you're like oh that like that's what
that is and you're like that's what
that's called and they're like cool
thanks and that's what like I know like
full circle like that's what it was with
you like I'd heard of you people have
talked about you we' never met
but I saw that post I was like that
that's it and all of a sudden I'm like I
got to meet this guy I want like I want
to learn more you sent me a DM right
away and you're like this is really good
I was like this is really really good
okay so now let's talk about okay so
we're going to move from going through
the motions we're going to going to
understand the problem and coin a new
term for it yep because you have to have
a new term because you can't Define old
things with new old Tech excuse me new
things with old language well the other
I'll say this a lot of times we like try
to make fetch happen especially in SAS
again with the category stuff so people
will try to like give names to things
that already have names can you give me
an example by chance I know I'm putting
on the spot like can I I'm not TR to
[ __ ] on but like inbound lead outbound
or like something dumb like with my eyes
roll so hard they fall back into my head
like you know we're just trying to like
name a marketing motion or something and
everybody's like dude that's not because
again we're trying to name we're trying
to name a solution right we're trying to
name the thing we do instead of like
naming the problem you know who did a
good job is Mark uh he to be Outreach I
I can always mess up his name but he did
he named the problem his company his new
company is called operator but the
problem he calls it the great ignore so
this is my like arpe yes I think that's
really I think it's great his whole
homepage is a Manifesto it is I have
notes on the homepage but I love the I
love the commitment and when he went to
Market with that of like hey this is the
great ignore we did this to ourselves
yes and all of a sudden you're like it
we really are in that and the I to be
honest I took this just to give credit
words too there's a guy named Kurt
Woodward who is like my Sensei for a lot
of this stuff he runs content at Zoom
info he's super smart he has a
journalism background and when I first
started talking about content IP he was
like oh those are conceptual Scoops in
journalism conceptual Scoops are instead
of a scoop of like I'm doing this like
digging behind the scenes or whatever
this investigative journalism I'm
noticing a larger trend happening yes
and I'm naming it now we saw this with
uh quiet quitting is a conceptual scoop
we all saw it happening but all of a
sudden we had words for it and it took
off the great resignation conceptual
scoop we all saw it happening nobody had
words for it cool and let's be really
clear like quiet quitting and the great
resignation are like A++ copywriting
like they're so good I'm not saying we
have to be at that level but you can see
how valuable it is so even if you've
never if you for some reason are
listening to this watching this you
don't work in marketing or like you need
a larger connection we've seen it
rampant it works on everybody 100% right
so when we name this problem like all of
a sudden we can take it forward and I
think operator did that really well with
the great ignore which isn't that
different than the great resignation but
like that is a thing that everybody's
been talking about like is outbound debt
is this channel debt is that channel
dead like it's because it's just
everything is highly ignorable now and
if you look at the the like uh I always
break this down like phonetically or
like what did they do to make that stick
like the Great Depression was the
original one I think then it's like the
great blank like but you know you have
to build into it which which Mark did
really well like the great ignore right
that's a that's like a framework or a
template like we're used to and we
recognize quiet quitting we are suckers
for literation as human beings like
we'll hear like I've heard things that
like oh that sounds pretty slick and
then I like wait hold on a second that's
just alliteration making me think that's
a little smarter than what it is not in
this example but I'm just saying mouth
feel matters like how you say it and
hear it matters I feel like mouth feel
is like almost one of those phrases um
one it's not a it's not the problem but
one that I coined in the same thing it's
reminded me of like was workstyle
content which is there's lifestyle
content which is just about your life
but I had noticed and I had hia on the
show and uh Nal tanani does this really
well which is this uh Vin matano does it
really well which is like it's their
life but with the work overlap so it's
like behind the scenes so I was like hey
there's this thing happening called It's
like work style content and it's booming
right right now M and the thing that I
noticed that it started to work like
it's on the right Trail and everything
you just mentioned those examples are I
posted about it once on LinkedIn part of
a larger post and people in the comments
repeated it back and that is how you
know you're on can I get that on a
T-shirt and you're like oo I've had that
in the I screenshot anytime somebody
says anything nice about checkbox
marketing I screenshot it and save it
should and I love that my laptop now
when I search for things it can search
the images for text yes yes I don't know
when that update happened but that blows
my mind super like what a great use of
the the technology but I think even twoo
like I've seen this from uh Kyle Coleman
did this really well and he gave a talk
when we were in Vermont together about
drive drive yeah and he talked about
Revenue leak was the problem that Clary
solved right and go to market bloat is
what they're trying to solve at copy
like those sorts of things and I
remember he even said like they did they
tried to do category design or you tried
to do category design collection ly at
Clary and the category was weird but
they had a really good problem in there
so that the name of the category was not
uh good right it was Revenue
collaboration and governance which you
had to shorten to rev CG for short which
when I ask people what does REV CG mean
they're like I don't know the CH so that
didn't stick but the revenue leak the
problem coining the problem Christopher
lockhead shout out to him category
Pirates I thought was brilliant it was
really well done the best part of that
work and it took a little bit of time
but it did start to catch on and it did
start like people started repeating
Revenue leak but it does take time to do
that I kind of cut you off there but I
agree I want to agree like that was so
good but I agree with you it's like
don't Focus I think this where maybe
we're going so forgive me if I'm jumping
ahead but like don't focus on the
category name so much focus on the
problem because that's what's going to
earn mind share No One Like even dude I
love conversation intelligence yep even
that's like a mouthful you know what I
mean and like I now it is a category
people think yeah we do need that tool
which is cool but I think
casual conversation it's still like call
recording yeah and I think also like the
if you think about how much money and
time it takes to make a category happen
the real category creators are not
necessarily creating like this is one
thing I learned from like studying
gainsight was they said really loudly
like we didn't create this we saw the
wave happening like conceptual scoop we
saw this wave of customer success
happening and we just rode the wave did
such a good job too
absolutely so like that that's the thing
about category Creations you have to see
a wave happening we're just trying to
see a problem happening this is way
easier you can test 30 of them like you
can try things and fail versus like
category creation is like a real full
company commitment and there's analysts
and all this [ __ ] like just start
naming the problem and all of a like
you'll be able to find out really
quickly with almost no budget like start
using it in your email subject lines and
all of a sudden you'll see like what
resonates you know can we do something
uh can I put you on SP spot yeah dude
can I put you on spot no we'll find out
roll the dice so when I saw checkbox
marketing I've never said this aloud I
was so jealous I was like God damn it we
made it Mom I I loved it to be clear you
know like I loved it and I was like so
happy for you but also hated you because
I was like I want that to be mine yeah
so the first thing I thought was like
I'm going to start saying it and I'm
like in my head kind of joking like how
often like how many times do I have to
cite Brendan before I can just say it
not steal it m say it
and part of me is like I think that
actually puts it in like U our like
common lexic like we all just like let's
like I'm like it will help Brendan to
say it and I'm like I'm going to give
them credit cuz I do I you know hate
when people steal [ __ ] but I was like
there will be a time where people just
say it and they don't credit you but the
people will know that like it's you you
know like people will be talking and be
like like if someone's like oh category
design I'll be like oh like Chris
lockhead he's the Godfather of that him
and his his team so that was the first
thing I'm just going to give you some
flowers like appreciate it very jealous
of you in that one so then I was like
okay I Brandon on my show and I want to
help people figure out their problem
what would you say like could you help
me figure out what I would call my
problem so that I solve before we do
that I want to say the goal the goal is
for people to take it you can tell I've
already cited like six people since
we've been talking I do the same thing
too sometimes it feels Nam droppy and
shitty and like oh you're just trying to
seem cool but I'm just like rampantly
insecure and just want to make sure
people know where my sources are uh or
where thing I get things from so I think
with your problem this is hard because
the way that I walk clients through this
is very much like we start talking
through like what's wrong what's broken
why do you think that is what's
underlying that very much almost it's
like you kind of saw my stuff that I do
with clients like what you walked me
through just now like cool cool cool but
what's under that cool cool cool but
what's under that why is that what's
systemic about this what are we like all
of those sorts of things so we really
have to talk about like the things it
has to come from a place of like what
pisses you off and it has to come from a
place of like personal experience where
like you have that felt pain and I
understand if you're marketers and
you're working at like a devops company
like you probably haven't viscerally
experience the pain that your customers
are feeling but then it just means like
talking to the people that have
right I think the problem you help
people solve is
this is outside looking in there's no
wrong answer here I just thought it'd be
fun to like kind of live Workshop it to
even help people like what even what
components do I need even if we don't
get to an answer right now it's just
like okay how can I start thinking about
it cuz you you sparked this in me I was
like okay what's my thing then and I was
like well it's checkbox marketing but
that's taken so I'm like and it's
probably a little bit different you know
what I mean but for mine it's tough
because it's like bad content you could
like oh so you like help like bad
content I'm like yeah but that's like
pretty surface level most people don't
have a documented content maybe I'll
give you some pieces and if this this
helps yeah so like when I talk to CMOS
and VPS they're like we don't have a
documented content strategy but the real
thing they say first is like our content
isn't helping fuel growth for the
business there's a disconnect there okay
okay cool why is that you know why in
different ways I asked that and it comes
down to we don't even have a documented
content strategy MH and then so it's
like oh you're kind of doing random acts
of marketing you can almost agree that's
like a commonly understood one we all
kind of have experienced it's a good
problem I'm like okay and then so it's
like okay let me kind of break so I get
deeper and deeper and it's a it's a mix
of there's no documented strategy and
then there's missing pieces of the
strategy which is like you don't really
know exactly who your primary audience
is or you don't really know exactly what
your channel strategy is and you
actually don't have like prior you know
what I mean like there's just missing a
plan and you don't have a metric so it's
like you're missing like the whole thing
and you have some of the pieces and I'm
going to come in and help you kind of
like glue it like find supplement with
the right pieces make the pieces you
think you have like refine them and then
glue it together into like one cohesive
strategy and I call it content strategy
design so that's your solution exactly I
have that I don't have the like oh
you're struggling with uh what is it
shins splints I don't have the Shins
splints so like I I remember I was
talking to the team at at path Factory
about this and we both know them right
yeah sh path Factory very much like they
uh we talked a lot about this like
faith-based marketing that's what I tell
him a leap of faith right so it's
faith-based marketing right and we even
attach like publish and pray to it which
is what most people do with content you
just publish it and just like that's
good pray to the content Gods um so
silly but I pray to them every day to be
clear yeah for sure for sure uh the but
like publish and prey and faith-based
marketing go really well together
because it is a problem that they
specifically their product helps solve
and they can dig into that and make
everything about that it's funny cuz I'm
I'm I know Pete and I I work them and I
told them and we get along really well
uh for a lot of reasons one is like You
guys sell the software to my services
mhm it's a very similar figuring out
like what matters what's really broken
yeah they help answer what really
matters but I cut you off again because
you got me all excited I think it's hard
to say without like spending a lot more
time on this but that's your deliverable
if we peel back a layer two questions
what is a documented content strategy
solve and why don't they have one yeah
can you answer both of those for me so
what does it solve it gives you
confidence that you know what to create
why you're creating it and how to
publish it for maximum results MH right
and it's cohesive the reason you don't
have it is because you don't have the
in-house expertise or skill right so
people either like we have we have one
content marketer and we don't have
anyone like in charge of content
strategy sometimes like a director right
so like no one has been designated the
owner of having one mhm and that could
be because they don't have the resources
they don't have the person or they don't
have the experience or they don't have
the time where they're like I've had
CMOS where I'm like you know way more
than me about marketing you know she's
been doing for years and they still
hired me and at the end of delivering
this she's like this was so valuable
because we just haven't sat down and
done the critical thinking required to
put a plan together we're just go you
know investor Le growth go go go faster
faster faster and so what I've realized
I deliver is not just the deck with a
lot of answers but is decision
confidence that you now wake up knowing
I am doing my team has the right
direction and every day we're doing the
right things that gives me confidence
that we're going to hit these goals
that's going to move the business
forward that's going to make me look
good it's going to help us all make more
money so I think content confidence is
really cool uh that still solution side
right but keep that like yeah content
confidence is really cool I think like
digging more so my process very much is
to do a workshop like this right and
then go back into the the lab I guess
AKA my desk and my office and just start
word smithing the crap out of it trying
to find things that rhyme two or three
word phrases it's very rare that I come
up with something like on the spot yeah
for sure but but I think you're starting
to get to the thing you actually help
people solve and like this is like an
like you said it's a confidence issue
it's a mindset issue it's an
organizational
issue they know inherently that content
fuels everything they do right it's all
of the marketing no one's me unless they
have that realization or belief that
like content will help grow the business
they just it feels to me like there's a
such a big disconnect of like how and
then also you're bridging that uh which
is another good example of Ip but it's
in media of like that taste Gap where I
know what I like what we're making this
is the number one thing I talk to people
when they come to me is like do you like
what you're making right now like what
are you proud of and it's almost always
between you and me and everybody else
watching the thousands of people
listening watch the uh like the they're
like no not really like they're they're
like it might be working but they don't
love it they're not like psyched about
it um I think
that's there's another piece of this too
of like Buy in that you also help solve
of like people in inside your
organization are going to get excited
about this yeah that has come up and CEO
buy so I'll take three three different
problems and start like mapping out and
just brainstorming tons and tons of
words the next phase is like let's look
at all of these dumb phrases I've made
and I'm waiting for like the snapping
point where they're like o I like that
or oh I like that okay cool and then we
roll out and test right and you create
content around like the problem the
roadblock to the problem give them a
template to solve it a customer that
solved it and then like a highlevel like
non-customer like somebody they've heard
of that solved it right that's super
tactical but I don't think it's like a
like I give it to you and then you're
like oh I got it it's magic you got to
Workshop it you Workshop it and you test
it a bunch and you let people say it
back to you yeah and all of a sudden
you're like oh it's actually I thought
it was this I thought it was checkbox
marketing or faith-based marketing or
whatever uh and it's really this other
thing there's a layer I that's why I
keep trying to get underneath you almost
get into like systemic societal issues
yeah of like oh okay cool like at a
corporate level women's opinions aren't
valued like you get into like really
deep structural things in society but
it's important to get there because then
you can kind of like build back up out
of it and this is very like hand wavy
and kind of woowoo but no it's a thing
that's what make it stick that's what
makes it stick though because it has to
hit that the emotional level in the era
of let me check about the conversion
rate and my meta ads and like all of
this spreadsheet [ __ ] I I want to see
the pendulum swing back a little bit to
some of this and I come from a world of
keyword research and keyword volume like
everything in your content strategy is
De like decided by something coming out
of like [ __ ] semrush or
HRS like that it's awful right that's a
distribution channel it's not what
decides your content strategy but for a
long time it did because we had access
to all of this data and we got excited
about it because we didn't have it
before it was like the Madmen era of
like people watching like how many cars
went by a billboard every day so when we
had access to all this data we were like
okay cool database decision- making and
then eventually over time we're like
that data doesn't actually [ __ ] mean
anything and if we look at where it came
from like a lot of it's kind of made up
in bad guesses so we kind of have to get
back to a more like hand toand type of
not to use like fighting analogies but
like a hand toand combat kind of method
of getting to these answers I feel like
I failed you though I feel like I want
to I'm going to not just so you know I'm
thinking about this for the next 3 weeks
not expecting a full answer I wanted to
get in your head of how you think about
it because critical thinking is more
important right now for marketers than
it's ever been because how-to content
and like tactical stuff is like on chat
gbt right so I wanted to get your
mindset let's do this let's do uh I
would love for you to work on I'll hire
you I'm going to hire you to do this
we'll Workshop it and let's record that
and we'll share with people what we come
up with okay that would be a cool
process okay I love it let's imagine
people got their uh checkbox
marketing villain IP yep now let's go to
like the solution land now not not
talking about the product but content IP
so you just helped the reader for
example right we'll call faith-based
marketing I think it's funny I love you
know I grew up in the Christian church
I'm sure it's going to upset and make a
lot of people laugh um I mean my whole
arm is filled with Christian as if I
need to prove it no uh is what comes
next though so like okay right so people
like I got it oh what was the one that
Chris Walker and them did the the dark
uh dark social so here's the problem
with that he coined two good ones what
were they dark social me off dark social
and the attribution Mirage oh I didn't
hear that one attribution Mirage was
perfect cuz we were just like we think
we have all this data about what's
working and then you're like oh it's
first touch or last touch which is just
utter [ __ ] in what we sell right you
know nobody's about buying a million
dollars a year in software because they
clicked a Google ad first like that was
not it right that wasn't the thing that
sparked the click it wasn't it wasn't
the thing that sparked the click but it
also was not the thing that took it all
the way I mean you were in sales like
can you imagine like from first click
all the way to closed one we're going to
give credit to a Google ad like I've
lost a lot of attribution uh call it
battle or Wars where I'm like I'm seeing
all these content touch points that I
help distribute and create and then
someone at the beginning or someone at
the end gets like 50% of the weighted
credit we're using like w attribute it's
just like ABM delivered this landing
page at this time in the sales process
I'm like I wrote the content on the
landing page like what do you mean it's
going to the ABM team and like we just
believe not even credit just like we're
saying that's gets half the credit that
that was half the decision- making was
that one thing yeah or like somebody had
been outbound them and was ignored for 3
years yeah but because outbound had the
first touch Point 3 years ago we're
going to it's so there's this Mirage
around attribution and it causes really
bad spend yeah we deploy our resources
really poorly when we think okay we have
to do a million dollars a year in Google
ads or we have to like most VC money
just it's like a pipeline right to
Google and meta basically um but we
don't try other creative things the
problem was refined Labs at the time was
I got this question all the time in my
Community uh I have a community for
assassin software marketers they were
like what what do they do like nobody
knew yeah what they did and what they
did they were an advertising agency
right and if you're an advertis by way
we used them and they're really they did
a really good job and I've heard like
yeah but they didn't solve the
attribution Mirage or dark social so
they had two pieces of Ip that were
correct and great but I think that's a
good so to bring this full circle that's
what Chris does a lot now as I
understand it not to speak for him at
petto he helps companies he goes in they
audit all of their attribution all of
their spend they let them know that
where they're that's the right
connection between the IP and that he
also is an investor I think in Hatch or
part owner they do like dark social
content so the solution is at least tied
to the IP that they've created otherwi
you probably like confused inbound where
people were coming inbound to solve one
of those two things and then like oh we
do something we're going to run some
Reddit ads for you yeah huh yeah so I
think you have to like stay you don't
have to keep all your eggs in one basket
but like the baskets have to stay in the
same room I like that so you have to
allow it uh so you have to like be
thoughtful about these things because we
can run off naming problems be like
these are all the problems content
marketers deal with or all the company
SAS or all the problems SAS companies
deal with we name all that [ __ ] and
people like that's so smart and you're
like cool attention but Nott it
yeah but it can't convert to revenue so
let's talk about that what no so
solution aside not the software or my
services or your services but like I'm
guessing content IP like templates
Frameworks guides that has to be part of
the part of this as well right yeah so
the way I think about it is channel
agnostic these can be delivered webinar
blog social it does not matter what
channel we do but I think sticking to a
really simple framework can keep us
focused I try to keep it all in like
five the five buckets and I kind of
mentioned them briefly but but just more
naming the problem calling out the
problem over and over and I will never
shut the [ __ ] up about checkbox
marketing I will keep talking about that
even when I'm Devin I'm sure you feel
this way too like I'm so sick of my own
crap most of the like my content I'm so
over it most of the day but I know that
it's other people are seeing it for the
first time or it's like oh yeah I forgot
about that thank you for the REM like
it's not every we're all thinking about
ourselves right right so I'm going to
get sick of my stuff first you have to
like keep pushing past that and I focus
a lot on like talk about the problem the
solution to the problem uh that's fine
but then the first roadblock you're
going to run into hey we both agree we
have to solve checkbox marketing when
you try to solve it within your company
you're going to hit these three things
you're going to run into these three
bearers I hit them this other company
hit them we talk about that roadblock
people are like oh thank God because now
I'm Obi-Wan Kenobi now I'm now I'm Yoda
I'm the guide in the hero's journey
Joseph Campbell Heroes Journey that's
going to walk you through this which is
the position we should all in we're not
the hero we're not Luke or whoever um
we're the guide so we take them through
that and the roadblock content really
helps them with that I like that a lot
the third piece is a template it doesn't
always have to be an actual template
we're not looking for like some Mad Lib
like you you do a lot of work with
LinkedIn the template is not like here's
20 post templates where you fill in your
own details and then post it right like
that can work like I think we all did
that I posted an epic amount of like
Justin Welsh templates for a long time
because they were good it was good
for I have it right now the the the like
I call a bribe I know the bribe is not
the best phrase but I don't care like
the the bonus gift on if you go to my
newsletter and you sign up there's five
LinkedIn templates Y and but it's also a
guide too of like why like I do a
breakdown works and I've had people
respond and like on calls months later
and they'll be like getting like on a
you know a prospecting call and they'll
be like oh by the way use one of those
templates in your uh guide and I got
like one of the like best performing
posts ever and I'm like oh that's
awesome but it's just one little
stepping stone to help them get better
you know what I mean it's like training
wheels 100% but the templates can go
like I was selling SEO primarily for a
long time and now that's a piece of my
offer but it's not the whole thing and I
noticed that people really struggled to
explain SEO to their CEO right so I was
like well why don't I just give him a
template so I created the I am SEO
framework intent asset and medium right
it's intent what do they want how are we
going to give that to them what is the
asset we're going to provide and medium
where are we going to provide it we have
to optimize those three things and all
of a sudden a whether it's Google SEO or
YouTube or Pinterest or whatever channel
has a search function now a CEO is like
oh cool it's just I am it's I am in 10
asset medium now I understand SEO yeah I
gave them that framework to explain
their job that they had been brought in
to do to the person paying them because
I think that's something we all deal
with as marketers right we all have to
like rej justify our jobs over and over
the weirdest thing by the way that
there's an open job wreck like the
executive like most say CMO or whoever's
head of marketing was like yes we need a
headcount yes we need it for this role
then someone writes that role they
publish it they interview people they
hire someone they bring them in and then
at some point that person's like oh I
have to explain and justify my existence
here over and
over it's it's bizarre it's absolutely
insane and I think that's one thing I've
luckily been really good at I think a
lot of the Su success I've had in my
career is because I know how to do that
and that's because I was in sales for a
long time
so I know how to like Bridge like okay
what do you about what am I try to do
bridge that Gap but it's something I
love that's why I love what you've made
because so many marketers are like okay
great how do I take what we just built
or what I'm trying to do and go get my
CMO or CEO to see the value in it yeah
and that was the unexpected ask when I
when I created the content strategy
design thing was the CMO going great I
love all this now the last step the
final boss is we're going to go to the
CEO and explain why we did all this and
like get his Buy in and I was like oh
that wasn't even part ironically wasn't
part of my offering but it is now right
and it's that last step of like great
that's the last uh bit of confidence and
enablement I needed to be successful as
a CMO here and get like a good feeling
about all the work and investment I just
did with Brendan Devon Etc so talk about
the problem talk about a roadblock give
him a template again it doesn't have to
be like an actual like template like in
marketing we think template template
sometimes it's just like hey here's a a
way to think about this a way to almost
like you know I help a lot of clients
with Community now they've seen me build
multiple communities they're like hey we
have one or we're thinking of growing
one can you help us right it's content
and community so I give them a framework
of like here's four questions to ask
yourself before you think about starting
your own Community right simple helpful
framework so then it's a time you've
helped a client or customer solve that
problem we have to tie it back to
whatever product marketing whatever
function owns that but we have to tie
your IP to an actual customer here's how
I helped sendoso beat uh checkbox
marketing here's how you know whatever
uh and then it's zoom out and do some
journalism and say like hey here's how
HubSpot beat checkbox marketing or
here's how whoever and it's just me or
like maybe people are like well HubSpot
is like the epitome of checkbox
marketing it's just a thousand marketing
drones like checking their no insult
like but you know like some people might
feel that way um but it's like hey did
you know when HubSpot started Ed out
they did no checkbox marketing right so
early on and I listened to a podcast
with Kieran Flanigan where he talked
about 10 things they did 10 years ago
and I just make that a LinkedIn post
right about like how they used to be
anti- checkbox marketing right you're
just trying to create some content about
here's how a name like when I was doing
SEO stuff I figured out uh I talked to
Airbnb and I got a hold of a growth a
designer on the growth team and I was
just like hey when I look at your chart
in the SEO tools it's like up flat
up flat up and it looks like a stair
step and I was like what are those three
things yeah and he he kind of like
looked in and he's like oh those dates
match up to he said we don't have an SEO
team at Airbnb we have a growth team and
those are the three times the growth
team focused on SEO when we focus on it
it goes up and then we let it chill for
a while and it kind of levels out and
then we focus again we do a new
initiative grows a ton and then it
chills for a while and I was like I'm
going to tell everybody about this
here's how air like so just some sort of
like for your IP here's exactly like how
it aligns with your problem it aligns
with your point of view I love that okay
I've got a question for you yeah yeah
what is the difference between content
IP and content marketing or just content
so content IP is a maniacal focus on the
problem and it really is that like two
or three-word phrase and then everything
comes out of that two or three-word
phrase versus content marketing could be
like the origin of that is God knows
what it's [ __ ] coming out of an SEO tool
it's coming from this other thing it's
there's a lot of great places to get
content inspiration the problem is we
can with our resources we have now
especially in the world of generative Ai
and things like you know all these
different Tools around video and
everything like that we can do
everything yeah and I'm a big believer
of just because you can doesn't mean you
should sure and this keeps us focused
and that's a silly thing that so many
companies especially ones doing between
10 and 100 million in Revenue which is
the people I work with primarily they
struggle with that they're in every
channel they're trying to dabble in
everything and there's no Focus there
it's just here's our latest partner
webinar and here's this and here's that
and there's no like single uh I remember
Jenny Coupe uh who was one of the VPS at
active campaign she pushed us so hard to
make marketing was always she called it
singing from the same sheet of music mhm
content IP gets you to sing from the
same sheet of music no matter what
channel you own or what your function is
or whether you have one marketer or a
100 marketers if you're all focused on
the same piece of Ip you all sing from
the same sheet of music yeah we did that
really well at gong I think we didn't
have we didn't name it which I always I
look back at now and I'm like it's wild
that they were as successful as they
were and we didn't have a name for the
problem yeah but we did have the its
opinions over reality like if you like
look anyone in marketing like it was
clear like that was that was like the
problem but without wording it or like
the the the point of view without having
you like welcome to reality or like
things that's that's a that's a slogan
though yeah it it was the reality
platform for a little bit that was like
a fun phase finding ourselves but the to
your point of singing from the same uh
sheet of music was everyone knew it was
opinion uh it was reality over opinions
like opinions have to go reality is what
matters and so all the content reflected
that yeah you couldn't leadership of
like hey here's how we think you should
run sales calls like it couldn't just be
like whoever on the team spouting off
howto content and this was again what
like years ago before we were even more
drowning in howto content but like you
were really focused on the problem you
had the problem locked in you didn't
give it a clever pithy name I regret we
didn't though but it turns out you
actually don't have to and that example
though and and I and I know looking back
being like the exception to everything
we've been talking about there's always
an exception to it but like I look back
and go I maybe it would have been better
if we had just figured out that that pH
I think it would have been better but I
think the fact that you were all on on
the same problem focus on it and every
bit of content tracked back to that
problem you didn't let it sway where it
was like oh we're going to interview
thought leaders and then share out their
best practices it just came back to the
and and it probably I would guess also
for people that don't understand this
outside looking in it's hard as [ __ ] to
get the data that you guys were pulling
out of your platform that is not an easy
thing it is not an easy ask so if that
like focus on the problem wasn't in your
DNA never would have happened like if
you could imagine me in active campaign
we had a wealth of information about
what subject lines work best how many
words should be in a subject L we could
have done the gong playay but for email
I was I I was wondering two days ago why
hasn't someone in marketing cracked that
code and been like here's the ideal
length for landing pages here's the
ideal subject line length here's the
right Pro like um like pronounce used
like you or I or we or like all that
sort of stuff like how come people
haven't done that now I know the first
barrier is it's super hard to get that
data but these are companies with tens
and hundreds of million dollars of
funding and revenue it's like how come
people haven't just done that it has to
come from the top down this is like an
Andy Rasin thing with his strategic
narrative which I've also Tak a lot lot
yeah he helped a gun I mean and we had
it top down a gun that's why we had the
DAT the CEO used to be a CMO so he got
marketing udy letteror was the CMO and
he was like all about the problem best
content wins or the most different
content wins not the best content and
that's how we got it and I tell this to
people because I get it all the time we
want to be the gong of you know Finance
or we want to be the gong data of this
and I go if your CEO is not bought in
and if you don't have like the head of
engineering or product whoever owns that
data set and that person pulling it it
will never work like you have to solve
that first building the strategy and the
plan all that is pointless until you get
that solved yeah it there's just no way
to make it happen it is such a big ask
like I said even when I was active
campaign I was like how many people have
signed up for get updates and it took me
like 6 days to get a reply if that is
how data is shared and stuff within the
company it gets really hard yeah but I
think a lot of times and you could call
this like product L marketing or product
L growth or whatever people have content
growth something well no no no I just
mean like taking the data out of your
product and like that is the content we
could dress it up but I mean Dev like I
ask every single person that I do a
discovery call with like what do you
like
what's your favorite content and I get
probably 50% of them mention one of two
companies one is gong oh can you guess
the other
one I have also asked and I would say I
get like HubSpot a lot but that's kind
of a fading answer I feel like HubSpot
is the answer when you can't think of
anything else it's IBM it's safe it's
like the textbook does anybody really
like is anybody really I don't I don't
know I I could I mean sometimes it
depends on who you're talking to and at
this when I'd be giving like random
answers sure so it's gong specifically
and this isn't any shade I get the
answer this just fact I get the answer
old gong a
lot uh respect um the which is true uh
and also Red
Bull about half the time people say old
gong or gong or Red Bull and I think
that's really interesting like there's
something there in understanding like
what people who have taste like and
things like that so it's a it's a piece
of it all right uh last question on
content IP and there's no wrong answer I
take no offense is this show read
between the lines content IP or just
content marketing it's not I would never
say it's just content marketing thank
you it's [ __ ] Apex of what we can and
should be doing was not hunting for a
compliment but flattery will take you
far on the show but I posted this I mean
even before we were friends like I put
something I was like here's a view of my
office I love like maximalist office
this space does everything for me like I
want every inch of the walls covered
with stuff I love that but in the middle
of it I have a giant TV and in the
background of my work I the photo I
shared on LinkedIn was just your show I
really appreciate that was cool that
meant a lot to me right but thank you
for making it because I think we're
drowning in the world of like [ __ ]
B2B interview podcasts and like having
something with production quality and
with all of this stuff and and well
researched question and all these like
you put a lot into this and everybody
can tell um so it is not just content
marketing thank you but is this content
IP no because it's not it's not a focus
like every single interview would have
to be focused on solving one specific
problem and I think right now like you
pull really good stuff out of everybody
but it's not like hey I'm going to ask
every single person the same question
Focus so that's
not to be clear like I if I answered the
question to myself writing these out and
I was like well the answer is probably
obviously you reink your life just sit
in prep no no well I'm like I like to be
very honest with myself like if someone
says something that it kind of hurts
like you know it's critique and like
before I get defensive I go is it based
in truth mhm and I was like my first
answer was like no this is not content
IP how do I know cuz I don't don't talk
about content IP too much I've done it
but I didn't design the show going
here's my faith you know faith-based
marketing problem and I'm building a
show to help with that I'm building a
show that I want to be entertaining and
educational or edutainment and I want to
inspire people like it has a focus it's
not on it's work oh thanks man it's
catching
on uh but it's not content IP like that
would have been my thing so I was
curious though I wanted to hear you
break down like why it is or isn't
because I think people will do the same
thing where they look at their marketing
strategy and go okay look at their
content like is this content IP or is it
not and why so that's why I wanted to
get your your take on it yeah I think
when you have that problem and then it's
like okay this problem our webinar
series is all about that our podcast is
all about that the email sends our
nurture sequence for cold leads our
winback campaigns our every single thing
kind of like SP like a hub and spoke
model has to be focused on that problem
and again like you all of these are also
like it's a two-way street right if we
Envision like a hub and spoke like
they're feeding out from the problem but
they're also feeding back into it we're
refining how do we talk about this is
this even the right name for it you know
you might try a bunch of stuff and then
be like well that's not I've I to be
fair I've probably tried four or five
different things oh really that just
didn't they just didn't resonate or like
I wasn't super clear or whatever else do
you remember what they were like your
throwaways or the ones that just didn't
work out they're not really throwaways I
guess they just I don't want to say
failed ones cuz I love that you tried I
feel like you it put so much pressure
and I think this is what kind of
dissuaded me was like it puts a lot of
pressure to like get it right and
perfect on the first try and this is
such a hard like I would put this at
expert level marketing to be able to say
I understand my audience deep enough go
through all the exercises you talking
about and be like here's the sticky
coined term for the problem so one of
the problems that I haven't coined but
I've talked about a lot is like the
problem with retainers especially in
marketing like the incentives for a lot
of companies run completely wrong great
for the agency really shitty for their
clients like especially in SEO where
like I noticed everybody did all the
work in the first two months and then
coasted coasted coasted and then did a
bunch of reporting in the middle and
then at renewal time they like ramped
the work back up yeah like being in
those machines multiple times and then
being on the receiving end when I was at
a SAS company hiring SEO agencies same
or cutting them in my case adopting and
cutting yeah because I caught them in
that that low-level plateau yeah and I
look at the you know you know how it is
you join sign up for 12 months what the
[ __ ] are you going to do in month six
and they can't tell you they're like
we'll figure it out well then we will
figure out paying you if we want to cut
the contract like so I like I push back
against SEO retainers a lot like there's
no just because you like I say a lot of
times just because you play the long
game you don't have to pay the wrong the
long game and like again that's like a
slogan it's not bad but like it's it's
not IP yeah we're work we're working on
it uh the but like that sort thing I
push back on these problems I don't have
names for them all yet cuz I also you
can test different things and test
different problems to see what resonates
but there's also two different pieces
here I call them like a business offer
and a marketing offer so the there's
other sides to this where like the
retainer thing is a business problem the
business model is broken that's
structure is broken has nothing to do
with the marketing and yes my business
can solve it because I work in Sprints
you don't have to work with me for you
know 12 or whatever months um I don't
know I test a lot of different things
but I've also tested like really pushing
back on which is something I'm also
equally passionate about of like people
let like keyword research and it's like
sort for like biggest keyword volume and
lowest keyword difficulty we sort those
two columns on the spreadsheet and
people are like there's your content
strategy and there are still a lot of
companies doing that and a lot of
really you know SEO agencies with really
good salespeople selling that
and like I'm the person that they hire
after those engagements where they're
like we paid somebody $40,000 a month
for a year and then oh it's as it's
breaks my heart and then I come in after
them and they're like oh we could pay
you uh 5% of that and you you also cover
us for a year yeah probably but like I
also like my I I know I don't even know
how much you charge I'm just saying the
I also put on the form I'm also very
public about pricing like the anyways
the so that sort of thing like I've
pushed back on a lot of different
problems but the keyword research thing
checkbox marketing is soon as I uh
posted it I think
um I'm gon to forget who said it I think
Mack readen uh replied like can I can I
get that on a t-shirt I'm like done done
and now I have so many like every time I
talk about it people are like oh I love
that thank like it's just like that's
the resonance is so much higher want to
confuse the market with like here's like
20 problems I solve right because that
takes the again the whole benefit of
content IP as we for once focus and if
I'm bringing a lot of Ip then like that
ruins the focus sure and the best
companies to the point like Clary gong
like all these companies who talked
about Kyle's again doing it copy or
operator they have one problem they
solve and they solve it maybe a lot of
different ways but it's still the one
problem 100% yeah so another thing I
wanted to talk to you about is what I
would consider a a incredibly powerful
skill but underrated for marketing which
is designing offers so this was
something you wanted to talk about so
I'm curious like so we can talk about it
however you want like it could be a
Content offer like one of these gu
templates like how you're designing it
or it could be like a services offer but
I just want to hand it to you and go
like got my notepad what up with the
offers so a lot of us came up in digital
marketing like I I would guess you came
up in digital marketing proper adult
professional digital marketing I did not
I don't know about proper I don't know
people would look at me and say proper I
came up in online marketing which is a
lot of webinars about how to do webinars
to sell personal development products a
lot of those like YouTube pre-roll gurus
and you know all it was a lot of passive
income type of stuff like I came up in
like the what's his name like Tai Lopez
world of that sort of thing the Grant
Cardone type of everything and those
people are masters of like offers and
offer stacks and how to blend all these
things I came up in the clickfunnels
world yeah and there's a reason that
clickfunnels now that I live in the
software world there's a reason that
clickfunnels is uh three times the size
of the second place landing page company
and it sure as [ __ ] is not because
clickfunnels has good-look landing pages
they are they actually don't awful yeah
they're horrendous but they work because
they focus on copy and a couple other
things and they really really work
because of the whole system of like
stacking landing pages and offers and
stuff the thing that's really cool about
that is clickfunnels became a master in
offer design and that's what I I feel
like I got my my PhD in offer design
just by like being a consumer of their
stuff and then studying it and don't get
me wrong Deon there is so much I don't
like about how they do things and about
the company and the people that work
there we could talk about that if you
want but like the offers that they put
out whether it's books or trainings or
scripts or video courses or the
conference like they uh there's like 30
of them of all these cool Innovative
things and the other thing that nobody
does in SAS other than them is they sell
them you buy those from them you pay for
their books you pay for and a lot of
times it's just at a break even cost for
them but now all their marketing is free
mhm so their marketing budget can in
theory be zero because we're doing the
marketing for them and all of it is
immediate Roi back in so there's no
question about like attribution or any
of that [ __ ] because like oh they're
paying for courses from us it's paying
for us to Market more courses and now we
have 20,000 people in our courses and we
built that list of 20,000 people who are
perfect to buy our software at zero cost
that's where things get really
interesting for me and I think in
software we always think that like the
software is the offer so everything's
push to like get a demo get a demo get a
demo start a trial start a trial I call
it demo Obsession that's not really a
great this is another silly piece I call
it the demo Deluge when you go to a
website and like up in the it is it is
but if you picture like a giant wave
coming at you of like just like a
tsunami wave of demo cuz you get the
like bottom slider and then it's in the
sidebar and it's in the footer but it's
also in the header it's shaking in the
corner you try to scroll away from it
the exit intent popup it's like get a
demo and trying to leave the website did
you mean schedule demo right I saw you
were not interested anymore did you
maybe want to spend a [ __ ] ton of money
and talk to sales so well so how can SAS
marketers create irresistible offers so
this is another thing if people haven't
read again feelings notwithstanding
about people processes companies I think
hundred million offers from Alex Heros
was one of the easiest ways I've ever
explained this Alex Heros clickfunnels
guy he wrote he had a thing called gym
launch I found him I have it in my bag
at my hotel right now and I'm reading it
he sold a book called gym launch which
was his whole program in a book same
thing Russell Brunson did it was even
made by the same people it feels the
same it reads the same and it is similar
Alex Heros type of stuff where it is
every single sentence is value over and
over and it's this thick book of how to
do marketing how to do sales it's his
whole program in a book
and I've been following him since gym
launch so when he rolled out $100
million offers in acquisition. comom I
was like oh [ __ ] he's going to like talk
about the behind the scenes of this
stuff and $100 million offers is great
like in I I haven't read it yet so this
is in terms of offer design he just kind
of you could take the whole book and be
like it's this fraction of like how do
we increase value decrease risk increase
the like percentage of likelihood that
they'll do this and then like reduce the
cost almost to zero like at least their
perception of it so there's that piece
of offer design but I think it's also
having secondary like I said there's the
business offer which is like here's how
much our software costs right and then
there's marketing offers that's what I'm
talking about and the problem with
marketing offers and the reason if we
want to dig underneath this of why don't
companies have marketing offers is
because most companies are top of funnel
heavy and bottom of funnel heavy if we
look at it over the course of like a
buyer Journey like there's a lot of [ __ ]
at the begin
almost nothing in the middle we're like
we can't track them when they're in
their consideration phase like it's you
know and every all the software say you
can like whatever but you can't because
you don't know when people want to buy
like things happen outside of your
control you kind of can't bdr them into
buying maybe sometimes but if I would
argue I would argue if you can they
probably already wanted to it's hard to
manufacture a need when there it doesn't
exist I would argue that if there's no
need then you don't have a comp
yeah but if I think you can't introduce
a problem that people knew they had but
you can reprioritize it so it's a new
top priority it's hard to do and I'm not
saying go to market is that your number
one way of doing it but there's like um
it kind of pissed me off I'm going to
tangent kind of pissed me off the
tangent are pissing me off but I've been
saying for years that no one gives a
[ __ ] about your product yet and then the
reason I get pissed off is the B2B I
think it was the B2B Institute or
marketing Institute something like that
someone fancier than the reader said the
new 955 rule have you heard about this
95% of your Market is not in Market 5%
is in market so you need to you know
that's your like balance act so when I
say no one gives a [ __ ] about your
product I'm saying 95% of people who you
could sell to don't care right now so
that's why that was my kind of
philosophy for why I invest in top of
funnel 5 years ago when most people
where most companies weren't and so the
reason I uh I get piss like now they
just have a number to the thing I
probably should have came up with a 955
R even if I didn't have the data but hey
I'm learning to coin things today so but
what I believe you can do is like so one
earn mind share with the 95 that's a lot
of things we've been talking about today
and all of the reader content then the
5% is like your bottom funnel that's I
intent keywords on uh SEO that's bottom
funnel content how hubs spot you know
did such and such with our company right
all that kind of stuff I think that's
more like final drisking right and I
also think that you can move the 95 to
the five and that is something that I
think people can start to do but they
kind of view it as like oh so it's like
ground and pound with like sdrs and it's
just like beat them up with like value
prop messaging and it's usually All
About Us hey us us look what we did look
what we did look what we can do instead
of like hey we know you here's this
checkbox marketing problem here's these
barriers you're probably running into
we've solved it I think that's how you
can move someone from 95 to 5 with an
existing problem that's just maybe lower
on their priority list or a problem they
didn't know existed and I think well I
think most companies just don't know
they have a middle of funnel problem
yeah so it's just constantly get a demo
come to a webinar sign up for our emails
and as channels get more and more
saturated I would argue like different
is better than better I think that's
always been true it's been one of my
philosophies udy gave me that one and i'
I've just that's like ingrained it's
tattooed on the inside of my head it's
so good well if none of your competitors
have a book why don't you have a book
thought Dave did this great I bought all
the I I'm pretty sure I paid for all the
drift books like they had a hypergrowth
book and like all these things um that
they put out there probably like five or
six books at drift and I remember I even
got pissed at them because I tried to
buy one it was a picture of a book and
of course they just email you the PDF
and I'm like I want the book in the
picture they're like oh we don't make
that I'm like don't show me a physical
book in the picture and then send me an
email with a PDF cuz I will buy the book
I want it on my bookshelf I want a
virtue signal that I have all the drift
books behind me in the recording on my
zoom calls like that there's all these
other like a physical book like we don't
even have to go down this tangent but a
physical book is so powerful 100% being
able to hand itug credibility signal
right like I think I've probably when I
mentioned Eddie's book right very good
copy out to Eddie schaner that book does
so much more he has a huge email list a
huge following on LinkedIn but everybody
having that book and that book being an
immediate like as soon as you see that
I'm holding the book we sit at the same
lunch table right we just became best
friends from that so there's all of
these middle of funnel offers that I'm
obsessed with and I think that more and
more when companies start do rolling
these out they'll find that that middle
of funnel starts to fill up and they
become the bottom of funnel becomes
really really easy yeah yeah well man
the cliche thing to say is I could talk
to you all day um but I can say that's
not true with you uh no
I'm we are talking all day I've seen the
schedule I want to go uh we're going to
continue so this is usually where I say
you know we wrap up but real quick I
want to do something different so first
tell folks where to find you so the
easiest place to find me is LinkedIn but
you could also Google me misspell
Brendan Hufford as much as you want
it'll still Google will take you to the
right places run an agency called growth
Sprints um but LinkedIn is where I share
almost everything that I'm learning
dayto day and that'll send you to
everything if I'm doing my job if I'm
good at this which I think I am agree
LinkedIn is definitely the best place
fantastic and usually I say man it's
nice talking to you and we you know
shake hands up our ways but we're
actually going to go sneaker shopping
right now so for folks who are listening
if you want to go jump over to the
reader YouTube page and you can watch me
and Brendon go sneaker shopping I
appreciate you man thanks for dropping
wisdom today thanks that's a wrap for
today and if you're still listening you
must really crave growth and I respect
that here are three ways I can help you
grow your content right now first
subscribe to the reader newsletter
you'll get actionable writing and
marketing advice delivered straight to
your inbox every Saturday morning two
make sure you hit subscribe on YouTube
so you get access to new episodes and
new videos when they drop and three if
you want to sponsor or hire the reader
you can send me an email at yo the.co
that's yo the.co and if you're enjoying
the show make sure to drop us a
five-star review it helps us get new
sponsors and grow I'll see you next time
[Music]