let's lead with that incredible uh and
what do you mean a safe place like
Dave's been in these like really
acrimonious interviews like like lesie
stall was grilling him on you know
what's going on in the world of
marketing well listen you don't get to
where Dave's gotten to without somebody
you know just nailing you with some
tough questions I was just going to say
I'm uh I was letting Dave know that he's
in a safe space because I'm a giant fan
of his work both uh both a drift and
with exit 5 uh and so I was just trying
to Prime him for that because I know he
and I don't know each other all that
well uh so yeah he's uh he's great and
I'm thrilled to have him on the show
thank you that's super kind of you I've
had people come on my podcast and I I
kind of say a similar thing I don't tell
them all that I I love them in the way
that you told me thank
you but um I love you thank you I love
you I love you too you know serious I I
I do feel like some people when they go
on interviews they're in this like of
like interview mode and like I I have to
tell people like look I'm not trying to
there's no gotas in my I'm not trying to
get you on anything I'm trying to have a
conversation with you so I think saying
something like that is like okay this is
nice it'll be a free flowing
conversation because I hate I hate when
I have somebody come on my podcast and
it's like they're in interview mode and
it's like I ask Craig a question and he
answers it and then he's like just wait
next question it's like no discussion is
is better so I appreciate that boom in
your face Craig yeah take that bow
from ABM to plg from medic to Med piic
the world of business is constantly
evolving we'll cover the who what where
when why and most importantly how you
get the
transaction I'm Matt Amon and he's Craig
Rosenberg let's get
started yeah I mean I you know and what
I really liked about starting that at
that point was Matt
moved essentially the loving intro up
front I appreciate that so full
announcement Dave Gart welcome to the
transaction by the way I had your book
so on on my shelf and meant to read it
you know how this goes we had Adam
Robinson on the show yeah like you know
that guy's just been destroying with the
founder brand thing sure and like Matt
and I had to go back to the trans cripts
because he had mentioned these things
that were like part of his like how he
figured this thing out and he's like oh
and you got to read founder brand I'm
like oh my God it's right here I read it
in one plane flight yeah I mean it's
like a blog post it was so good I mean
you know that right that was a great
thank you yeah Adam's become Adam's
become this huge advocate and he's
literally huge he's in if you've never
met him in person he's like three if you
stack three of me on on stools I would
maybe be able able to to dunk on Adam
but he's been advocating this founder
brand thing and um like I I wrote the
book and I just kind of wanted to put
something down and I really just wanted
to try to write a book and so it was
like more of just like a personal
project um I didn't have any big
expectations for it then a couple people
like Adam is one who've just like taken
on and I think it's like anything in
marketing or business it's like once you
name it it becomes so much easier to
spread and so I think Founders have been
doing this type of marketing forever but
then we started calling it founder brand
and Adam was the first one that I really
was saw advocating like oh you got to do
this founder brand thing you gotta do
this and he's just he's next level I
don't know if he he he comes up the most
insane hooks for his content it'll be
like it'll lead you to like sign up for
some webinar and he's like so the other
day 100,000 pound tree fell on me and I
was alone in the forest and but guess
what you'll never guess and I didn't
have any tools or knives or anybody to
help me and I had no cell phone service
but guess what I did and then he like
leads into this like amazing hook for
like sign up for his webinar he's so
sure you can write the book and I'm I'm
just giving him some [ __ ] because I I
know him and he's great but he has that
sauce like he has that like love him or
hate him he has the thing that was like
the premise of founder brand it's like
oh we're looking for so many ways to
differentiate our companies and I'm like
the founder can be one because usually
the founder is some crazy person who
started this company you know out of
some passion or some you know prior
success or some failure and so they
naturally have all these stories they're
often times like their personalities can
be all over the place because you got to
be a little bit crazy to go start a
company and be an entrepreneur and so
those ingredients then you have Adam
who's like a natural Storyteller he's
he's perfect at it I I don't think
anybody could just pick it up and do
that but he's kind of put his own POV on
there and that's why it's working it's
pretty cool yeah it's amazing I've been
uh I know we should start the interview
in a sec but uh so I've been you know
I'm doing um uh I'm at scale Venture
Partners primarily series a but even
with everyone I've been saying
you know you got to read founder brand
you said well look I put a name on
something that the founders were doing
already but there's a rubric for how you
tell your story yeah there's a way to
think about you know what you could do
with this thing inside of you they all
have the story inside of now can they
execute like Adam now man I'll give you
an example a Founder friend of mine is
about to announce a new company and he
asked me to just give some advice on you
know launch strategy and everything and
I said yes cuz I think he's great and
it's also fun to just my business is so
different now it's fun to like get back
in the weeds a little bit and so I'm
watching him and he's working with a PR
team and they're trying to do this
announcement
and ve well-known founder super
successful has a bunch of hits rais
money from Top
VCS none of the pre none of the presses
cares to write about them because it's
another AI startup and there's already
been a hundred of them and and so I'm
like who cares who honestly who cares
what does it matter what is an article
in Tech crunch matter what does that
matter because you have a following on
LinkedIn he's been posting like a bunch
of teasers like about launching his
company and they've all been going like
nuts like seven 800 likes you know
hundred of the comments I'm like when
you the launch strategy is literally
going to be you're gonna go to LinkedIn
you're going to say we're now open right
like you're gonna write your post on
LinkedIn you're G to drive that to your
website and that is going to drive quite
literally thousands of people relevant
to you in your Niche to your website on
the day of you launch I know why we want
the vanity of the tech crunch but I can
guarante to you that the tech crunch
article isn't going to drive traffic
like that would and so that's that's why
you do this and so now he has that brand
and so like it's why we've been able to
build exit 5 it's like if you can build
an audience online and go direct to your
audience like that is the goal I'm not
saying don't get pressed I love
marketing I think marketing is a game of
perception I think press absolutely
matters and it looks nice to have that
headline and send it around but come on
if you have a direct relationship in of
your audience you launch something new
you send an email to your list and you
post about it there's there's nothing
more more powerful than having that and
so that is like what founder brand is
now Founders are like well I don't want
to do that I don't want to be out there
I don't want to be in front of it okay
then that's fine then that means you
just have to go and look at the other
like 15 marketing tactics it's just it's
one strategy I think you can choose to
try to to try to build yeah I love it by
the way fun fact and then I promise I'll
ask the big question Matt no no it's
he's like he's already going yeah just
so you know Dave it's very I could just
be sitting here
going thank you for uh we'll send you
the check no uh but Matt it is important
to Matt that planes get landed on the
show True certain things that we're
supposed to get done we have to get done
but um per your point you we have a a
company
bland. I don't know if you've seen them
they do voice AI so they were not
getting picked up on the press for their
series a announcement but it was funny
because they have this young growth
hacker marketing lead Michael guy's
amazing he just kind of yeah yeah I'm
gonna I have this launch plan I'm GNA do
dude they launched via video and social
he did it just like consumer marketers
did he reached out to the
influencers he played this game so well
they have over 7.2 million views on
Twitter or X or whatever yeah it's
amazing yeah amazing yeah that's guess
what that's how I found out about their
announcement I work with them it was in
my feed because one of these guys that
you know big big influencer type wrote
this was funny he wrote we're all effed
right say sound so good now I'm like
what a retweet I love that I love the
non-traditional stuff it's great all
right so here's the big question that we
start every show with playing about to
land Matt is um you know what is
something or some things that the market
thinks they're doing right it could be
approach best practices is tactic it's
tactics methodologies Etc they're
actually wrong and they should be doing
something different you know what is it
and what should they go do about it all
right now we will knot our heads the
rest of the time please take it away
Dave all right I just had to jot down
some notes I'm not always great on the
spot but I can if I you know it's like
dance monkey what what kind of joke do
you
have say something funny do something
funny actually this is like the the
thing like I think my strength in
marketing is like uh creativ and
storytelling and writing and I would
hate to be in meetings when they'd be
like look bring Dave into this meeting
Dave Dave what do you got what do you
got I'm like the process doesn't work
like that like I'll I might have it like
tonight on a run or in the
shower um I think so maybe there's we
can see how much you want to talk about
but um I think AI is the big one for me
and I don't have any like new hot takes
like I hate to come on your podcast and
be like AI but I see a lot of marketers
that
kind of rolled her eyes at it right
rightfully so I think there is some like
ah this kind of sucks like to to the
point about that you just mentioned like
the guy saying we're all effed like it
kind of sucks like content used to be
such a thing is now all this content
going to be like generated by a machine
and like even if even if it's good even
if it's good I think there's something
as humans where like if the sales if the
email was sent from a human a human
genuinely crafted that like that got
open that got the meeting that feels a
little bit better there's just something
like we we created that and so I think a
lot of people are caught up in the
content and they're like this sucks and
so I don't want to like it and then they
go on the fact that you know chat GPT or
any of these copywriting tools like
everybody thinks AI for marketing is
like the the writing side they think of
it as like a way to generate content at
scale and yeah you're going to get a
bunch of shitty blog posts like from
chat GPT if that's all you do but on the
other side I see so many things that are
going to be possible for the role of a
marketer and I think of like myself as a
full stack marketer where I've always
kind of done a little bit of everything
like I could get a website going get a
landing page going video done ads like I
can do all that stuff I'm not the most
technical person but I can do that now
picture a world where I can generate
scripts I could use like something like
hey Jen to make a video Avatar and a I
could make a product demo I could I
could um fix a landing page on on my own
Danielle on our team at Exit 5 the other
day she she was like oh I was stuck I
don't really know CSS and I was trying
to mess around with the format on this
like website page so I went to chat gbt
I asked it to tell me I got the code
from chat gbt and I paste it into the
landing page builder it's like things
like that that I think we're sleeping on
it's not the like is this going to
replace my job right shitty content
thing it's like the workflows the tools
the technology um I was on a call
yesterday with a friend of mine who was
like a head of revops and he was like
what's possible because of AI and like
the marketing Ops stack and like data
analysis that whole world I think those
things are all super positive and so I
think that's something that I think
everybody's like oh AI whatever I just
think they're thinking about it wrong I
see it as like the next wave of
technology that you're gonna that's
gonna you know sit side by side with you
a as a marketer just like back in the
day they didn't have the tools that we
have now it's just going to be one of
those new new pieces of um you know
things that work alongside us and so I'm
super excited about it Matt your
reaction you guys are supposed to say
something yeah I know will sometimes we
look at each other well I'm not sure
he's looking at me by the way Dave
because of the video thing but at me or
was I looking at you I mean I try to
look at both of you guys at the same
time I use both eyes but uh I I mean
listen it's not controversial to say
like I agree with Dave here I mean the
reality is is like I think a lot of
people have poo pooed chat GPT or AI in
general just because like you know it's
very easy to understand like or very
easy to perceive I should say what is
being written by Ai and what is not but
I think the Dave's point it's the idea
that like you're going to get assistance
in other workflows you're going to get
assistance in building uh it's not just
the copy that you're putting out and I
think if you are trying to use AI to
write the copy for you you're probably
in a rough spot now that's not to say
that you can't use it to get ideas
started because sometimes the best way
to start ideas is to say hey I'd like to
you know I'd like to write a white paper
on this topic like give me a couple
controversial takes
uh that stuff works really well uh or
you know hey um I really like this
article can you pull out the three best
things about it um that's a good way to
get things started but you know as an
endtoend solution for copyrighting it's
it's not great but I think Point your
use Cas is your use Cas is that that's
actually been my number one I don't
really often use the the content that
comes from it but I use it a lot as like
my writing partner especially when I'm
talking about something that I might
have deep expertise in or I can't
generate topics easily and so I'll be
like hey you know how in you know I'm
just thinking about marketing like you
know how in cyber security this thing
happens and this thing happens well what
would be the reasons for that and I
could use chat GP to then do the
research and explain to me a topic that
I'm not an expert and I'm like oh
interesting okay now if I'm writing an
article for a cyber security company I
can have this amazing research partner
like I know I'm a good writer I know I'm
a good Storyteller but I might not have
the deep subject matter expertise of
that industry that's a perfect use case
that I think a lot of marketers can can
take yeah for sure I mean look I we have
a lot you know that this gets brought up
a lot on the show and like when you know
we're talking to go to market folks so I
get like there's a whole bunch of people
out there who are I not resistant but
you know it's and I don't know about
like full negativity but like you know
folks are saying like it's an a it's an
ore which is like well you know now
we're going to be uniquely human and
that's going to be the
differentiator um versus all the AI
products that are going to produce all
this you know content Etc and and that
shouldn't be an or like that's an an
like that's how you that's frankly by
using those tools you can be even more
you have the speed and the tools at your
fingertips to be more uniquely human
absolutely and think of the think of the
use cases as a marketer like I that's
what I think of or somebody in sales or
inside of a company it's like hey take
me um get a list of all the custom all
the new customers that we've won over
last 90 days take all the transcripts
from those calls take all the notes from
the Reps in the CRM take all the
marketing activity right and help me
come find some Trends and summarize you
know how these people are finding us
like boom there you go you have a one
pager of something to give you an you
know insight into your strategy or like
we take all the churn all the reasons
people churn from exit 5 we just use
chat gbt to summarize that data every
month and it's like it's just saved us
three hours right there we got the we
got the report it's stuff like that
we're not wasting time on on silly
things anymore you know it's really
interesting you guys we did like a a
quick
survey we do these things called
councils Dave in the portfolio where
it's like we'll have actually Matt
helped start them we have demand gen
folks we have product marketing we have
SDR we have revops and we pulled them
about their use of AI and I assume that
revops and SDR would be um significantly
more aggressive but actually product
marketing was really the number one sort
of AI user but here's the thing it was
like 70% of those product marketers well
roughly like call it 68% it was all
individuals using it in an ad hoc Manner
and then overall if you put all the
different functions together in the
polling it was like 58
59% of everyone was individuals are
using it in an an HW ad hoc matter
manner we saw less of like Department
wide formalized AI even the use cases
we're talking about today what we're
seeing is like you know this new AI
power user um being really good and and
and we'll continue to see that at least
now as people get used to it I think you
when people ask me what's like the the
uh gateway drug I'm like dude just go
use chat GPT or whatever you know and
like just start to play with it in terms
of some of the things you do I but I I
don't know about you guys I was
surprised that product marketing had the
highest sort of usage I wasn't surprised
that it was all ad hoc stuff but it's
exactly the use cases Dave has brought
up here yeah they're just they're just
plagiarizing all the copy and putting it
on the website it's fine that's not yeah
come on now but they T I mean we talked
about it's like market research you know
some of the things that they need to go
do in the past I mean I've been doing
like initial takes on buyer personas for
folks just using perplexity and whatnot
and it's just been fast yeah I mean you
could you could be like hey we sell to
it's like a thought it could be a
thought partner right in in like
personas and research it's like hey we
sell to Fortune 1000 CFOs um what are
the what are the some of the the take me
inside Mind of a fortune you know 500
CFO what are the some of the things they
care about and that that's not to take
that verbatim but it's like oh
interesting now I got some things going
okay all right cool so maybe we could oh
yeah we hear this topic a lot number
three what all let's start writing about
that like it's such an idea starter like
you should never uh you you can really
have writers block anymore because you
kind of always have always something to
get to get going I I love that use case
idea starter I love that actually mattz
was telling me about the sales team at
his last game
you know they were using one of the AI
tools right and you're saying how do I
sell to this company and this guy at
this company and it was coming with
ideas yeah prep a that's a very specific
question for prep yeah that's amazing
that we can get that and it's as an idea
starter I love that yeah I mean you know
you can do great things with it you can
write custom gpts so that it understands
your brand and it understands the
products that you sell and so you can
just you know once you've build that for
your sales team sales team can utilize
it to say things like hey I'm about to
sell to Dave Gart you know uh his
company looks like this can you tell me
you know what are what are some of the
most important things to a business at
that stage in that region in that
vertical etc etc and it can just you
know it just gives you a head start it's
just a it's a we're going Matt we're
going with idea
starter created here we're going with
that Dave I have one that I want to lead
you with but before I do that uh any
others on on your list a top where we
should be thinking differently yeah I'll
give you I'll give you two more I can do
quicker ones of these so one of them is
influencers um I think that I think that
there's a big potential for B2B
companies to work with
influencers and there's a couple things
in there number one the reason why is
because the economics actually are way
better in B2B because if I work with a
you know consumer influencer I start a
golf brand and I sell hats and hoodies
and shirts right I got to sell a lot of
damn product through that influencer to
try to make the money back right ver in
in BB um just using like a it's a kind
of a similar thing but like one of our
sponsors from exit 5 they got they did a
big sponsorship with us they got nothing
nothing nothing nothing nothing nothing
nothing this is not working this is not
working oh 150k uh dream account closed
they're like can we do more with you
right and so you just need one customer
uh and there's also other reasons to do
it Beyond customers and then I also
think what's interesting about B2B is
people think about it wrong they they
often will try to go find people that
have you know massive followings and
they're like well who in finance has a
massive following okay couple things
that that person's going to be way
expensive it's not going to make sense
for you to post content with them right
the other thing is um they've probably
already done a bunch of stuff already so
it's not new or unique I like the idea
of um so this this woman Natalie Taylor
she runs Market at capsule they're like
a Enterprise video AI editor they did a
launch and she said I'm going to take 10
grand I'm going to find 10 like micro
influencers like people who talk about
marketing and talk about video but have
like three to 5,000 followers on
LinkedIn which is a lot of people and
I'm going to pay them each $500 to do a
post for launch and so you end up
spending you spend 10 grand you get this
micro influencer campaign you have all
these people spreading your word I think
that's a cool example that I've been
talking about a lot because I think more
people are starting to come on that it's
why we get sponsors for exit 5 but I
think anybody that's talking about a
topic online we we go to social media
like LinkedIn and we write about
marketing and sales find those people
but then people listen to say say well
how do I find those people is there like
a database no you have to be there
participating watching the space getting
really close then you can know okay
here's the 10 people that I think will
be good I see a lot of people asking for
some Magic database of influencers
they're going to give you all the big
ones anyway you need to like pay
attention to your space see who posting
and then reach out um and then just
LinkedIn so influences one and Linkedin
in general I think I would
be I think the old school the old PR
strategy of just pitching and trying to
get press and trying to get people to
write about you is is doesn't work the
same way as it used to I would be laser
focused on trying to build our own
audience through the F through the
founders page and the key employees
Pages not the company page talking about
what we're doing every day it's not a
new strategy but I would just stop
trying to set a goal around it for let's
see what results this produces in three
months and just like commit to like
we're going to go to the gym for a year
and we're going to measure progress in a
year and we're going to all write and
share and and as you go you start to
understand how to measure it you start
to understand how to think about it
differently but if you obsess with
measurement and success of it out of the
gate you're never going to get going so
Ai influencers and Linkedin all right
let's talk influencers for one sec I
like this one um
so um I love what you said you got to do
the work and you got to be there to see
who these folks are that I I get this is
you know you want to create your list of
the people that you know move your
Market or move your function or wherever
um and then so you you gave that example
so they they paid like if you were
giving other advice on how you approach
the influencers what would you say to
that say hello my name is Dave can we
pay you
I would say hey Craig I would say hey
Craig um I've seen you you know you I've
been following you for a little bit now
and I see that you always post about
SEO uh I work for XYZ SEO company we're
launching a new product in a couple
weeks and we'd love to have you be a
part of that launch we're interested in
working with you on a partnership where
you would you would try out our product
or or learn about it and write about it
and we would pay you to post that on
LinkedIn on this certain date if this is
something you'd be interested in let me
know
you can you could literally you know
what you could do if somebody's
listening this you could take out chat
gbt on your phone you could hold it up
to the speaker play it on your computer
you could you could take exactly what I
said chat GPT will listen to it
transcribe it and then you can say
generate me three versions of that email
based on Dave script to make it better
so you could also it's a little there's
a little fun build on that so I would
say that and then the key here though is
the offer so what you have them post
really matters and so if you line up a
bunch of people if you L of a influencer
and you're like we're going to have
them post our blog
post not great right what Natalie Den
capsule did was she had each one of them
make a video using their product and
talk about why they think why they
believe in you know why they're bullish
on video marketing or something right
you can come up with a topic that's like
related so that they're going to write
about it in their own way and then you
have to have an offer in that it should
be like I did one one with a company
when they launched new product was like
sign up now it's free you know this is a
free tool you can use on your website
right now right or um we're working
right now with this company called
planful and their sponsored content is
they're driving everybody to a resource
that they wrote on how to build your
marketing plan and that's perfect for
this time of year because people are
trying to build their budgets and do
planning for marketing right now and so
if they work with influencers to promote
that they're now widening the widening
the reach of that I think you really got
to think about what is the thing like
the what is that audience's what is that
influencer's audience what do they want
and how can you know that and try to hey
we we know they love cheese pizza where
how do we serve up our version of cheese
pizza that day so they're going to go
actually want to go try it I think a lot
of people don't think through all of the
steps it's like we got influencers
they're going to post about it okay but
you then you got to put yourself in the
audience's shoes it's like what's in it
for me am I really going to click on
this do I have to put on my credit card
you all all of the things I think you
got to think about the full funnel of
that campaign and thing that last thing
I just mentioned is true for all
marketing it's why people in B2B think
webinars stink or or boring it's because
they don't think about the the actual
offer the delivery it matters so much
yeah I uh I totally I love that I you
know we had a guy on Mac Ren I don't
know if you've seen thisy yeah he was
just at um he came from uh Denmark to
Vermont for our first annual event yeah
we just we just hung out with him he's a
great guy yeah similar play he didn't
have to pay uh but you know he went to
uh you know he used a a consumer like
influencer
strategy um he talked about a lot I mean
he's done a lot of really creative
things but um you know uh was able to
sort of uh loop influencers in and um
you know have them go help uh amplify
them on LinkedIn where where he's
definitely sort of locked in which is
your number three on number three on
LinkedIn
so uh we've been big on this here
because we've seen it I mean Adam
Robinson is a great example but we've
seen lots of examples where frankly I'm
not surprised you brought up LinkedIn as
number three because if you took founder
brand methodology from the
book and linked I mean this is where
this these things come together right
you take this this sort of founder brand
play and you
gota uh I'm not going to dominate on
LinkedIn I mean I tell I make it really
hyper when I talk to people about it but
like if you're you know the likelihood
of your Market being on LinkedIn is high
if it's not I get it we can go do
something else but if it is like we got
to take this founder brand founder
Persona and start to really work on
LinkedIn and um so I'm I'm not surprised
you brought it up but like I like how
you said that by the way people like the
way you answer that is such a pro like
nonchalant like yeah if your audience
isn't there then we'll do something else
I think yeah I often will when I talk
about LinkedIn there's always you know
one out of comments well our hey hey
bald hey bald Tech bro man like uh our
audience isn't on
LinkedIn like I'm just going to answer
like you did next time it's like okay
then do something else like it Mark it's
just like this set of decisions like
where are we going to play like what are
we going to do where are we going to
play okay if your audience isn't there
but to your point there's I think
there's like a billion users or
something like that so they're they they
probably are on on LinkedIn for sure um
I think the the this this if I like
zoomed all the way out the me the bigger
category for me is I just think social
media is the way marketing happens in
our lives today everything is social
media right it's all the content we get
as people is from X LinkedIn Twitter
maybe you're on Facebook maybe you're on
YouTube right just because we're in B2B
doesn't mean that changes you just have
to change the approach and like think
about what people care about in that
world and so I think for a lot of B2B
SAS companies for whatever reason social
media is not treated like the main to me
it's always the main marketing channel I
think social media is always like well
we we hired a social media intern to
like post updates on our LinkedIn
company page when like what I want to
grab the screen and what I'm trying to
say with you all now is like no no this
is the marketing strategy it's not like
oh this little social media thing we're
going to post these cute updates about
our company no like this is the way I
would do marketing at a you know series
a series B type of company it's social
media marketing you just got to figure
out what works in your industry yeah
yeah yeah I think the old Playbook was
that is that social media was the sort
of amplification of everything else that
you were doing and I think what you're
advocating for now is like that's where
it starts and you can use other channels
to amplify that but like where the real
meat is is in social media and like you
can you know do some emails you can do
some some you know some Direct Mail
pieces that sort of spin off of that but
it starts there and that's what's really
different it's it's also insan you get
it goes so much deeper than just
marketing like you get company and
product level ideas from writing on
LinkedIn right you talk about Adam Adam
writes about something related to his
like R B2B product and it goes nuts on
LinkedIn that's a signal to him that oh
people are interested in this topic or
he could write about a new feature or
thing that they're doing so it's not
perfect data but now they have a signal
that like oh if we built something like
this people would come I think it's very
underrated as like a company positioning
product road map feedback tool that you
can get this direct feedback for nothing
you don't have to go out and do market
research and you can use those signals
to inform the rest of your
business it's awesome yeah I mean I
totally I have nothing to add to that
except thank you for bringing that up he
yeah that that that's really important
all right so you know I would bring up
one that I take a picture of this one
section of your book which is the
minimum viable Market you know like the
the the um
because what I the and we just had a guy
named David pus on who was like we asked
him again we had them on like a year ago
and we're like okay again what's the
thing the Market's missing he's like
dude like a tight ICP like a tight like
this there's you can solve real business
Problems by doing that and like when I
read your book I was like holy crap I'm
going to try it I don't have it in front
of me but it was like product mark
because you knew that was your wedge in
the Massachusetts area like you guys
like isolated this thing because you
knew you could get to them right and you
know you you had access to them yeah
people people hear that they're like
what does that mean how did you like
write blog post for product marketers in
Massachusetts like well we we didn't do
that we the network that we had was okay
we have a strong Network here in Boston
let's go find a product marketer at
every single company okay we're going to
start to write content now we want to do
content through experts we're going to
be the curator so I went and interviewed
five I cold emailed 20 product marketers
we got responses from like 10 I picked
five say hey can I do a 30 minute
interview with you about the role of
product marketing um boom then we go and
create that content and now those people
become the stars of our content we make
them look amazing they start to spread
our word they don't we're not trying to
sell them anything right they you have
to start somewhere and I think Craig the
reason people don't start with that
narrow ICP is because how I mean you
talked your you're you're in the Venture
world right how many Founders like well
yeah we sell to this one but we you know
we also have this use case and we can
also do this and that you know we always
want to show that our product can do
more even if that's true but for the
sake of marketing and getting going the
narrower the the ICP the better right
shrink down that audience to be product
marketers in Boston working in B2B SAS
companies because when you start there
you can always add more later you're
learning now you're growing now we have
momentum okay we have momentum among
product just to build on this example we
have momentum among product marketers in
Boston well you know who's pretty damn
similar to product marketers in Boston
like product marketers on in New York in
San Francisco okay now we have some some
social proof and some credibility to
move off of and so you can sell your
product to multiple personas which we
did at drift we started with product
marketing and eventually worked all the
way through the whole organization but
you have to start somewhere and I think
not being narrow enough is usually the
thing that gets in the way from getting
initial
traction yeah I I I I mean that is like
a it's such a key point I definitely
think the market doesn't think that way
for the reasons you just mentioned I
forget who it was it was just telling me
they went in and said went through a a a
narrowing
exercise and the C not in my portfolio
FYI but CEO flipped out well we could s
Everyone I this is a waste of time and
it's like exactly what you
just but that's what people don't
understand it's like the obstacle is the
way there it's like yes you could now if
everything was selling great and think
business was going crazy then keep doing
what you're doing but usually you're
it's not and so it's like hey we need to
revisit our ICP doesn't have to be
forever but why wouldn't you at least
try to like make progress because I also
think there's so much to like learning
how to win customers in one
segment that you can then apply to
different segments and different markets
and so start start there
get some initial traction and like at
drift we didn't do that for eternity it
was like three months one quarter we're
going to focus on this and then we're
it's like juggling we're we're start
with one ball okay now we're gonna add
now we've proven we can do that can we
add in two yep now we got two we' proven
we can do that can we add in the third
oh shoot when we get to three things
start to fall down it's the same the
same with that approach yeah and once
you guys got wins because I remember I
was an analyst in space and like the
stories were like well the cro came in
and said no we're getting drift yeah
it's not like they were Mark you know
necess like quote unquote marketed to in
the traditional cro way there were use
cases out there that were successful
that their their cro Peer who
experienced that was like you need to
get this and it was like because you
focused in and got you know you you got
success in a place where you know that I
mean just even the logic behind starting
in product
marketing um was was like I don't know
I'm not sure that's the first place I
would have started with Drift But it was
your wedge right in and then you guys
you know created that success no it was
really it was the genius of David who's
a Founder he was like he was obsessed
with
um Warren Buffett and Charlie moner and
they kind of their way of thinking is
like you always invert the problem and
so the problem that the company was
trying to solve was like we are making
this chatbot and we need to get it
installed on the company's we
it okay so how do we do that well demand
gen's not going to do it sales doesn't
have the key to the website engineering
doesn't really handle oh you know who
owns the website at a lot of these
companies the product marketing
team and so the BET was that if we can
get product marketers to know us like us
and trust us when we have a product for
them they actually have the keys to like
go in and install this and then we can
try to expand within the orc but that
was like such a lesson for me and like
damn that is that's how you build a
strategy right there and
yeah yeah for sure can can we talk about
drift for a minute just because actually
what you would say is can we continue
this
conversation oh yeah yeah that's right
good next next question yeah let's talk
about it so I have a I I mean I have a
theory on drift and uh first of all I
have nothing but respect for the
business and I think it you know I was a
customer multiple
places but my Theory on drift is it's
one of the companies that and there's a
few others that I feel the same way it
was driven so largely by the
marketing uh that um it's it's almost
hard to quantify and what I mean by that
is sure the product was great but was
the product really revolutionary like I
you know I bought it and I was like okay
it's simple we installed it we set it up
it wasn't all that complicated like and
so I guess the product is Good from that
perspective it's easy to use but like
you know I had live person before I've
had other chats like they they didn't
have the chatbot aspect but like okay
okay okay good product um you know is it
a complete and total Game Changer I
think like it had a run where that space
like was you know became a very
important part of pipeline generation
but the thing about drift that I
remember is not necessarily like the
product itself or the process of
purchasing it it is like I can remember
vividly you know the brand the the logo
Mark the word Mark I can remember being
at serious decisions in Austin Texas
when the entire Booth was pink the whole
thing like the booth was pink the text
was pink the carpet in front of it was
pink the people were in pink like just
such a well executed brand design and
it's like sometimes I'm like oh yeah I
remember when I bought Terminus or I
remember when I bought you know this
product a HubSpot a maretto or whatever
and like H yeah yeah it worked this way
and I don't really remember drift as a
product I just remember the brand yeah
and it's been so it's been so long since
a brand really dominated a marketing the
marketing Z guys the way drift did so I
just want to get into that like I I want
to talk about the way you branded it and
it it it wasn't just a visual obviously
like because for lack of or well I think
the truth is is that you and David
invented this like hey podcast for
companies because that was such a big
deal right like you just it from the
outside looking at it looked like you
guys said hey this is the way people are
doing marketing in B2B it's boring it's
driven by email it's driven Maybe by
like SEO and digital ads what if we just
flip that on its head by by 90 degrees
and just win a completely different way
and just everybody's going left we're
going to go right like was that the
charge there because gosh it felt like
it
was absolutely I remember the very first
conversation that I had with
David maybe like interviewing or early
joining the company he was like we need
to build a brand for this
company and the reason why we need to
build a brand for this company is
because no one's going to care that we
exist because damn it there's this who
knows how many tools there are now but
this was like 2015 2016 we're building a
mtek tool go to Scott Brinker's
landscape and there's 13,000 other sales
and marketing tools so everyone's going
to right out of the gate be like how are
you different how are you better blah
blah he's like we're going to win by
we're going to win by building a brand
and you know his thing about brand was
he was obviously had a great eye for
design and like the visual brand that
and he worked with many people over the
years who helped shape that um but he
also understood that brand is not just
like the visuals and the identity now
that plays a part in it because when you
build when you get people to know like
and trust you and it looks sweet that's
like I'm going to wear your hat I'm G to
wear your hood right and so but he also
understood that we needed to get people
to know like and trust us through the
other side of brand which is content
right it's how we communicate with our
markeet and so he obsessed over
copywriting he was the one who saw me as
a writer and pushed me I was gonna I was
trying to become like a growth marketer
he's like dude you're an amazing writer
and Storyteller for us to be successful
and for you to be successful triple down
on that skill set don't worry about the
growth you can hire somebody else to do
that part and so he pushed me to like
really understand website copy our email
we were the only company at the time
that was like to your point about
standing out at the booth we just sent
plain text emails for all of our
marketing emails and the open rates and
click rates were insane because at every
other company it was a battle with the
creative director because the emails
from the company were not on brand and
it's like well our emails got opened and
read he read them because they were
conversational so brand was also a a lot
of little things like that or his idea
to start um a podcast for the company
not talking about anything that has to
do with the company it was called
seeking wisdom he's a proven
entrepreneur he's gonna talk to me about
books he's read lessons he's learned and
that just kind of morphed into this like
reality show where we ended up talking
about the company it's things like that
that built the brand the visual identity
is like a stamp on it to make it
memorable but the brand is built through
that content and communication that was
his strategy from from the beginning um
I know where you're going in the in the
beginning of that was like did the was
the marketing better than the product
and I think there was a time where they
they were both equal but then I think
just they stopped innovating the company
got got bigger I think if it was like
that same 50 to 100 person and they had
the the hunger and the energy to do all
that stuff I think the product could
have definitely kept up but yeah there's
probably you know probably the marketing
was outpaced the product a little bit
just from a a perception standpoint and
then the hard part about being in that
space
is M maybe the product was better or
maybe it's worse I don't know there's it
the chatbot thing became such a
commodity that like
everyone had everyone had them and
everyone was doing them and so it's
really tough to like feature
differentiate and it's like I remember
we'd get so many questions on the sales
side about like how are you different
than intercom or then later how are you
different than qualified and all all
these other companies it's just like
this endless game of how are you
different than x which is also why the
most important ingredient for a company
is that differentiation and that
positioning and that was a part of it in
the early days but you know things
things change the market evolves and now
I think about what's what would have
been possible if we had the wave of chat
GPT and AI that we have in
2024 if we had that in
2017 at
drift man I would have a lot bigger
house by the way he didn't mention the
incredible
videos I mean that's how I knew Dave
before I knew Dave yeah but there was
nothing incredible was literally me on
my iPhone talking and to the the camera
just to what we talked about social
media
earlier oh look somebody in B2B
understands how social media works and
nobody else is doing this and Linkedin
just launched a new feature which is
video I would post a video like a
regular post M would get like 5,000
engagements I post a video and get
50,000 100,000 right yeah and so they
were pushing this stuff early and I'm
sending these screenshots to David and
showing him the analytics he's like you
just got to go all in on this like just
do a video every single
day that's what I did
by the way that's a also a credit to
Dave on the um yeah the founder side by
the way like that's actually not that
that's not always the Instinct like
oftentimes there's a there's some kind
of friction or fight around this kind of
creative stuff here now granted you were
showing the numbers but like still like
good for good on him lots of really good
moves that you yeah but like what what
does I guess though but what does me
recording a video on my iPhone on my
commute walking to work and posting it
costs it costs nothing there no time of
doing that that's a false belief I think
yeah but there's a lot of really
terrible video being created in
particular folks that aren't sort of
natural and keeping it real so to speak
I mean yeah you just be walking the
streets and filming yourself that's hard
for folks and they often they over like
I don't like overly produced video I
don't like stuff where it's like overly
scripted no but I think we KN I think we
knew like we knew that and it's like oh
okay I'm I'm natural and comfortable on
camera like let's do that right it
wouldn't what where what what's Su when
you see a company who's trying to do it
and it's super cringeworthy it's like
okay you have two options are you gonna
train that person and make them better
on camera or should maybe just video
Maybe video is just not your thing like
to your point about like Craig your the
the audience isn't just isn't on
LinkedIn okay maybe video is just not
thing and so I think there's just this
I'm just riffing on this it's like this
meta lesson of the marketing like I
think within a company any marketing
strategy any any marketing tactics can
work but you have to look at the
ingredients of what you have as a team
personalities funding timeline goals for
the company all those stuff matters it's
like yeah we all do it I write very
definitive takes about marketing on
LinkedIn but there's so much Nuance
inside of a company right whether
they're bootstrapped or profitable or
this and that Venture back right maybe
they just you just got to understand
where you're going to play with based on
the ingredients we have and I think that
was one of the things that we did really
well at drift in the early days was turn
those ingredients into an advantage
David was a well-known founder with a
strong presence I talked about it in the
book but that was like the first PR
Channel when I started it was like where
how are we going to start to get
attention to this company it's like oh
founder has 60,000 Twitter followers and
everyone knows him on LinkedIn let's
just let's start there because the
ingredients were like right in front of
us right that's awesome by the way
speaking of video issues um I'm noticing
that you know I don't shave Dave so like
I like to keep a little bit of stubble
but because my mustache is getting so
gray it looks like I have I'm watching
on video it does look like I'm growing a
mustache do you agree with that take or
uh yeah it looks nice though I think it
works for you I appreciate it yeah
Matt's concerned oh my God okay Matt
land this Matt take the plane is
oh the play again Matt oh man try to
keep it natural here and have fun Matt
yeah I've got I've got I've got my own
mustache problems like all right CRA
just during that whole during that whole
Soliloquy I just gave Craig was just
staring at himself in the camera looking
at his yeah that's not but yeah no I
have been sort of glancing the the
braininess like the the the chin music
and the the mustache is standing out I'm
G to have to work on that um you're like
my my 12-year-old in the
mirror um so so yeah sorry guys I mean
look it's the I mean man that he landed
multiple planes here Matt I figured I
could ask for a little feedback on the
mustach no no no no no it's a fair
question it's a fair question you should
ask Dave is Dave is a well-known
mustache expert and it's very rare that
we have you know s a person with that
level of expertise on the Pod you're
well within your rights yeah I love
um by way in your with your um uh are
you getting a lot of Founders to
subscribe to your stuff and come to your
events because it feels like they I mean
there's so much on the founder side that
we can learn from you and and in your
community um not not not really I think
that's I'm not really focused there I
think if I was like really turning up
the like I think I kind of wrote this
book about founder brand and then ended
up getting really into and busy with
exit 5 and so that's the main thing is
building that I have thought about oh
man there's a business I could do more I
could have the founder brand podcast and
YouTube and newsletter and all that
stuff I'm just I'm just not interested
in doing that right now and so I haven't
and so I think by nature of doing exit 5
there's kind of you know one out of
every 10 person is maybe a Founder who's
curious about B2B marketing but I'm not
really I'm not really doing anything to
attract an audience of people interested
in the founder brand top and then plus
since that book came out dime a dozen
now have started founder brand agencies
where they you know ghost right for the
founder listen to them da I almost got
into that world but um we have a really
good thing going with exit 5 and I I'm
worried about getting myself distracted
and I think it's very I'm very
competitive and like I always am kind of
looking for the next thing and I'm
trying to force myself to like just be
patient and just work on this thing
right now and so that's kind of what has
all my time and attention
yeah you're doing I mean like I I I'm
actually that answer didn't surprise me
I didn't know that wasn't the leading
question that just did because Matt I
don't know if you remember I was like
I'm gonna go talk to Dave and see if we
I can get him to do a webinar with us
yeah I got on with him and we're
catching up and I go hey do you want to
do a webinar Dave's like no not
really he's like I'm gonna do what I
want to do and be really successful at
it I mean that was that was I don't
think that conversation was with was
with you was that a an AI bot
conversation that we wer you did send me
someone sometime and I was like why
don't you just join exit
5 I don't know if it was you or somebody
else but this one guy asked for a call
and I got an intro from
somebody and then basically he just
wanted to grill me about how I set up
exit 5 and how we built the community
and how many this and that we have and
I'm like this was a strange call so I
got out of that one quick but I don't
think that was you but yeah no that that
doesn't sound like me no I want to find
the paper
[Laughter]
trail all right well dude this was
awesome I I uh I mean I honestly like
it's been fun watching you do your thing
from Thrift to Exit 5 and hey why is the
podcast called the transaction because
we talk we talk about all kinds of
different GTM uh strategies that get you
to land your next customer nice um so
you know we we got I've covered
everything from plg to ABM here and um
we've actually had quite a few uh sales
uh folks on here talking about you know
how to be successful closing deals uh in
the current landscape and like you know
tips and tricks for for selling as well
so we just try to cover everything GTM
related just with the idea being you
know whatever it takes to get the next
transaction nice that's cool well yeah
thanks for having me on this was nice
fun to chat safe space RI on from
marketing ideas yeah I love the safe I
mean honestly I know I was teasing often
times Matt just to let you know of when
I'm teasing you it's actually because
I'm complimenting
yeah yeah isn't that called
gaslighting is that I you know I've
heard oh man anyway Dave thanks man and
we really appreciate you being on and
that was amazing and this is the TR yeah
thanks guys um appreciate it I'll talk
to you later all right see you Dave
thanks for joining us for another
episode to the transaction Craig and I
really appreciate the fact that you've
listened all the way to the end what are
you actually doing here for show notes
and other episodes please visit us at
the transaction pod.com like And
subscribe on Spotify Apple podcast or
any other place you get your podcast
from either you have walked away from
your podcast device or this is playing
somewhere in the background someone in
your house would really like for you to
shut this off now
[Music]
oh