y the next
episode yo I'm Devin Reed and I'm on a
mission to build a bigger and more
inspired career as a marketer Creator
and entrepreneur after 10 years in sales
and marketing and leading content for2
billion doll SAS startups I know one
thing real growth takes more than basic
tips and tricks and learning from the
best will help me reach my potential
let's ride so I'm traveling America for
candid street level conversations about
creat creativity marketing and playing
by your own rules you'll get practical
advice to grow your career confidence
and income and have fun doing it are you
ready this is read between the lines the
show for people who want to achieve
phenomenal
[Music]
results my guest today built a
multi-million dollar content Empire and
it all started with one podcast I'm
talking about Nick selski
Nick is co-host and co-founder of 30
minutes to president Club one of the
fastest growing sales podcasts on the
planet now they're active and growing on
LinkedIn digital events newsletter and
they just launched their first book
earlier this year which sold over 30,000
copies Nick is a personal friend of mine
and one of the savviest marketers I know
so today we're going to break down how
he achieved all this success in just a
short couple years you're going to hear
how to design unignorable content offers
that motivate people to like download
And subscribe practical tips for scaling
into new channels without spreading
yourself too thin or burning valuable
resources along the way plus content
distribution tactics so you get as many
people as possible to engage with your
content every time you hit publish are
you ready let's
ride shout out to our sponsor goldcast
they are the B2B video content platform
they know that video is the most
effective medium for engaging audiences
and building longlasting brand
relationships and they do more than just
host amazing digital events they
recently released content lab which is
an AI powered video tool that I use to
turn long form content into branded
Clips in minutes not hours and it's cool
because you can use your digital event
footage or upload video files to open
your account go to goldpass doio or hit
the link in the show notes now on to the
show so your podcast has gotten millions
millions at least four million downloads
which is phenomenal and where I wanted
to one thing I wanted to talk with you
today and I want to start with the
podcast is you and Arman and I know you
have other employees now too you guys
have a true content Empire multi- CH
Channel you quit your day job and you're
doing it full-time so as Arman I think
Sean at least a couple other people you
have like multiple people employed by
this business so I say content Empire
because it's profitable and it spans a
lot of uh depth and width I think like
you know in terms of like channels
correct yes so I want what I really want
to talk about is how to avoid what I
think is one of the biggest mistakes in
B2B marketing which is thinking that you
have to be everywhere all the time all
at once and you guys did a great job
which is we designed a podcast we
designed one program Channel and we
invested in it we were maniacal about it
and you designed it very intentionally
grew it and then you started being very
selective with which channels to invest
in still are exactly so I want to talk
about that today yeah okay so let's
start with the show give folks for who
who haven't heard it yet kind of just
like the the quick intro to like what 30
minutes the presence Club sure is yeah
yeah so it's a sales podcast we
interview different sales leaders and
sales people where it deviates from your
typical B2B sales content is there is
lots of sales content out there that
talks about the what to do you've got to
have a strong cold call you've got to
sell value if you want to be great at
sales you got to have a lot of empathy
Devon and all of that stuff is true but
at least for me when I was a new
salesperson I listen to these podcasts
saying you got to be a great listener
and I think well then what the hell do I
do when I show up and like the CIO is
like all right I got 10 minutes tell me
what you got I'm like what do I say in
that situation how do I listen my way
through that yeah and so the whole focus
of our content is exclusively on the
actionable practice iCal howto content
for almost exclusively like B2B sales
professionals um and so we talk about
everything from like how you would
design a comp plan as a VP of sales like
the step-by-step breakdowns of that to
what you say when you open a cold call
um so the content is very very
practically oriented um and we have a
number of different channels like you
alluded to earlier so most folks know us
for the podcast which is getting over 2
million plays a year we've also got a
really really popular monthly webinar
series um we've invested a lot and this
might be something we dig into in
growing our sales newsletter we're now I
think we just cracked 90,000 subscribers
on the newsletter um we've been really
really focused on that channel because
it helps us drive to the other content
um I don't know what your original
question was but hopefully that gives
you a sense of like what the media is
about I'm looking at the judges and
you're getting an 8.5 on that answer
you're doing great what would have made
it this is actually a great sales
question what would have made it a 10 I
made it a 10 was you jumped ahead a
little bit on the channels but that's
okay no I'm messing with you no no I'm
kidding so I know the show been on it a
couple times some people said it's the
best uh episodes of the series not me
just a lot of people um I'm kidding
obviously people delayed laugh delayed
laugh because you know Q Applause um I
would say your show is hyper tactical
yeah and so walk me through all the
decisions of okay me Arman your co-host
you are going to make a podcast why did
you choose podcast of all the channels
that you could use to reach salespeople
okay
so I'll give you the
appropriate level of context on this my
first sales job like a lot of people it
was one of those sales job where they
say here's your phone here's your
territory get selling and I had no idea
what to do I had no idea who to call
what to say how to overcome objections
how to book meetings but I worked really
really hard and I did okay um and it was
really frustrating because I was a high
performer my whole life but um the
technical skill of selling is not
something that you typically get taught
in your high school college education um
and so for me I had started listening to
podcasts um when I was in college
because I would drive a lot um like we'd
go to wrestling tournaments and I'd
listen to podcasts while we'd be driving
there and there was one podcast that I
really loved called Bigger Pockets which
is actually a real estate investing
podcast and a lot of 30 minutes to
president's Club is modeled off of
Bigger Pockets Believe It or Not which
is a real estate podcast um I would ride
my electric bike to work because my wife
and I could only well then girlfriend
now wife we could only afford one car
and so I'd ride this ebike 12 mil each
way and I had a big speaker on my bike
and I would listen to different sales
podcasts on the way to the office and so
I got a feel for what was out there um
and I was frustrated with most of the
content out there there was occasionally
like a gem here or there but I didn't
get like the I I was really looking for
like sales training in the form of a
podcast and so I think there was that
planted in my head of like oh okay like
this is a medium that I like to use to
learn I consume a lot of these I feel
like there's sort of a gap in the market
and then the reason that we picked it to
start with was we knew it and it was
also the middle of the pandemic and
Armand and I were like we Armand and I
were college wrestling
teammates so like he and I we started
like beating each other up on a
wrestling mat and after college actually
because of this Bigger Pockets podcast
he and I were investing in real estate
together we were buying rental houses in
Texas and every single week he and I
would have with Sean also so Sean Sean
actually it's funny let me go back a
little bit Shawn people don't see him in
the content Shawn has been with us since
day one Shawn wrestled with us in
college he does all of like the backend
operations for 30 MPC and so we wouldn't
be able to operate the business without
all of the connective tissue that Sean
like the connective glue he does in
making stuff happen I think one of the
most powerful skills for marketers
entrepreneurs is how do you design a
Content program or a channel that has
longevity and impact and that's what you
guys have done picked you picked podcast
because it sounds like you one people
were inside y people commute or maybe
just commute maybe not to work but
they're on the move you can get them
there you picked highly tactical because
personally you realized I'm not getting
a lot of tactical coaching and advice in
my sales career yes so that seems to be
kind of like a lot of personal
experience and as you're listening to
other shows you're spotting a gap like
you're seeing an open like Niche an open
field where you're like hey I can do
that but also I think people don't think
about
the Channel that I can do well yes like
if you like you know don't don't go into
blogging if you're not a great writer or
maybe not right away right don't go on
to podcast if you're not a good speaker
I'm guessing you and Arman leaned into
podcasting because you've done hundreds
if not thousands of sales calls
definitely by now yeah so you know what
I mean I'm just trying to kind of like
almost like triangulate and figure out
like what were the AHA moments that made
you go this is how we're going to design
something that we really believe in
so I'll talk about some of the design
design decisions that we were really
intentional with the first one
was we looked at the podcast through the
lens of what I call Value density first
I need to understand why would people
listen to a sales podcast at all and I
think there's a difference between
entertaining content and educational
content right so I'm not listening to a
sales podcast for the same reason that
I'm watching Love Island right one of
them I'm trying to my brain off
decompress relax whatever the other one
I'm consuming cuz I want to get better
at my job so that I can make more money
and I think this is where a lot of
people mix things up in B2B marketing is
like I see a lot of these like cold call
competitions on face or Facebook gosh
LinkedIn recently yeah and I'm like I
think those like they're creative
they're interesting they've got great
graphics but I don't think a lot of
people want to consume those because I
don't want to watch somebody else cold
call in a competition like I I want to
get better at cold calling so anyways
you're kind of saying like basically if
I'm in the mindset of getting better
don't try to give me entertainment
correct it's like if I want
entertainment I'll go to podcast smart
list or I'll go to love Island like
you're you're very they're very
compartmentalized for you yes and I
think for sales people that's also very
true for that Persona that's right yeah
and I guess it helped that we were that
Persona so we did a couple things by
Design which is your original question
piece number one from a value density
perspective we cut every episode by
probably 30 to 40% meaning we would
record a full with the guest half of the
interview would never see the light day
it would go right in the trash it would
be the the the pieces like all right
Nick welcome to the show and it would be
the guest being like thank you so much
for having me here I'm really excited
for this one Etc like the audience
doesn't care about that they don't care
about your gratitude um it's true like
you're laughing but it's true no I'm
laughing cuz the way you worded it is
funny but I do the same thing where I
prep everyone and I go I will tell them
about I will tell my audience about you
in the intro before you
going it and I'm I age and I just like
the
way so we literally would cut I remember
in the early days with the show we would
get a transcript of the show and we
would go line by line by line and if the
guest restated a point we were cutting
one of those points if they
overqualified their answer oh that's a
good question well it really depends on
your scenario and your sales cycle
length and you know the Persona that
you're selling all that's getting cut
and we're going right to like the answer
it is really really tight I remember in
the beginning like we would start the
show and Arman would be like so Nick how
are you doing today and I would always
give the same answer oh I'm really good
I'm excited for this episode cut that
the audience doesn't care now we
probably over rotated on that a little
bit but that was by Design the design of
the show was if if the guest is not
saying something that somebody can do
say or write that very day it does not
make it into the final product that even
extended to there's a lot of episodes we
have not published and that can get
really really awkward but our first
responsibility is to the audience and
making sure that every time and anytime
they tune into our episode they are
getting premium content um and that's
hard it's really really hard we have to
push guests we have to have
uncomfortable conversations with
prospective guests we've got to really
put extra resources on the editing but
the end product I think is the reason
that we've grown so uh I have two
stories on this by the way and I'm going
to I'm going to I'm going to compliment
you on this because a lot of creators
and marketers think about building their
brand yeah they don't think a lot about
protecting that brand so you guys are
really intentional on designing this
show and look it's like it's highly
tactical I love what you say if you
can't say it write it or you can't do
say or write and the reason I can rattle
it off so much is I still when we prep
guests so like we when now when we
record we do a 15minute like we we book
an hour with a guest the first 20
minutes are us prepping the guest like
we're giving them hey nothing
theoretical no what or no what or why
content we want how we make them fill
out a pretty in-depth like you've done
it it's like a so that was my story that
was my story so I want to applaud the
protecting the brand so I I wanted to
spend time on the designing the identity
because it's like okay now we have our
formula highly actionable 30 minutes to
presence Club is aspirational correct it
tells you how long you're spending 30
minutes like I I'm appla like the 4our
work we actually so it's brilliant yeah
so but my point is okay now you have it
and you're like okay now we're going to
start making episodes yes now and I've
ran B2B podcasts two that weren't mine
and this is obviously mine this is my
third one and I was a guest on your show
yes and I remember vividly you and our
one of the two being looking at like me
and the camera and like we don't want
theoretical we don't want mindset we
want this this and this and I was like
wow yeah no one does that yeah no one is
maniacal about the quality of the
content but the identity of the content
and I loved that because one I was like
cool one I've listened to the show so I
already kind of new but most guests
don't listen to the show as we know
that's that that happens but I was like
wow I love that these guys know their
identity and they're sticking to it so
that was like love that and I've I've
kept that myself like from that moment
forward I was like I have to keep this
like protection mindset yeah the second
one you said was like what do you do
when the guest flops yeah now it happens
and it's a thing that no one talks about
because it's like how do you tell here's
the Trap you're in B2B you're in a
corporate in-house job you got the SVP
of operations from your customer yep to
come be on your show and they're not
good now they might just candala never
been on the show Mostly what it is is
they just didn't do a great job yeah it
happens yeah we all have Bad Games bad
days whatever yeah but in that scenario
how do you tell a executive client you
weren't good enough for our program it's
very very hard to do now I had someone
so cuz i' I've bought uh three or four
sponsorships from 30 MPC your show and I
had a guest that we we I won't say you
know who obviously but we sent we sent
them over and I remember you like I
think you called me and you're like Dev
kind of like tough news like so and so
recorded and um you know we're not going
to be able to use it yeah and I remember
just being like back to that moment like
he's protecting his brand and show
because if you allow this uh content to
go out that's below the bar yeah you're
starting to dilute your brand and you do
it once then what happens you do it
again you do it again you do it again
and I like the way you handled it which
was like look I'm open to giving them
coaching and having them come back again
and record and I thought that was just
like brilliant as a marketer so I want
to like applaud that but call that out
because it's so important well so
there's sort of two two elements there
one
is ounce of prevention pound of cure
anything that you can do upfront to
mitigate against having a
a Bad episode um is better than trying
to walk it back with somebody and so
that's part of the reason that um like
we screen guests before we bring them on
the show like I listen to other podcasts
that they've been on or someone from our
team will we have them do that prep
document and if it's not like where it
needs to be we'll we'll tell them yeah
um and then we also have that pre-show
for a reason where we'll like we're
feeling them out on the pre-show like
we're yeah I mean we're taking them
through like the like we're talking with
them live about the game plan for the
interview but if they can't get
actionable in their we'll we'll ask them
okay like you wrote this for your
actionable takeway talk to me about
what's behind that and if they're not
good like we've called it out before
we've even turned on the recording so
that's all The Upfront stuff that you
can do yeah let's talk about actually if
it's not good you actually end up
recording yeah and um it's not a good
episode actually one more thing that
I'll note is we actually get the benefit
of because we record for almost an hour
and we are going to cut it down to 30
minutes you usually can get if you
record with somebody for an hour you can
get 20 minutes worth of usable content
God willing especially while what you do
is if the guest is like not so great
let's say it's me and I'm like I'm
fumbling I can't give you good answers
you start speaking up more Devon you as
the hosts start injecting more you start
sharing your own stories and that makes
the usability like a little bit longer
um but if you do have to cut it yeah
what we did was we I I called you like
that's not an email that's a that's a
tough conversation but it's not just our
brand it's your brand right you were a
corporate client that was paying because
you wanted to establish some thought
leadership for your people and I think
what we said is like hey like I don't
know if this was the best reflection of
your brand and you want to protect that
also and so it's hey like we can give
this person some coaching so when they
come on next it's better um or maybe we
find a different guest um and I think
you as a marketer respect that CU you're
like wait no we want to be represented
well and so yeah those are not easy
conversations to have but the problem is
the audience the only way that they tell
you it was bad is by not listening
anymore and there's sort of a lag on
that versus I would I would rather
choose short-term discomfort over
long-term dysfunction or failure of the
show well that goes back to your
discipline that you're talking about
before the show actually I'll tell you
Armand is the one who is far more
protective of the brand than me it's
actually good we have a healthy tension
of like I'm a bit looser of like ah come
on like let's get this person I think
they're going to be good and he's
definitely more protective and so I
actually think there's the good amount
of tension there um definit the cop cop
bad cop yeah
definitely um I love ran um no so I use
the word maniacal for myself because I'm
maniacal with my brand protecting when I
was a Gong the gong brand and so I said
it to you it's the first time I think
I've ever said it to another like
marketer like this is mancal in the good
way so I like that a lot I think it's
pretty clear in the design MH before we
get to distribution I want to know about
how did you know that it was working
like what you know so you've got the
identity you're protected it you're
producing I don't know for how long but
at what point were you like hey this is
like we' kind of like caught content
Market fit like this is really
resonating and it's starting to grow
maybe even more than you expected but
like what signals did you see and you're
like Hey we're really on to something
just the
podcast
honestly I I hate to say it but it was
kind of from day one it was like kind of
in the first month we were at like first
week it's 1,000 downloads first month
5,000 I don't know I'm just sort of
directionally there a lot more than
maybe was it more than you anticipated
Sur yeah yeah it was and the growth was
really really awesome now we got lucky
in that we launched the show May 2020
and so everybody's listening to podcasts
everyone's posting on LinkedIn for the
first time there was a massive Spike
there but like we started getting really
really awesome feedback from people I
started getting a dozen messages a week
of like oh you're so changed my life I
was one of those messages I'm pretty
sure I don't know exactly when but I
remember reaching out and being like
dude you guys are like on to something
so I mean I think we worked really
really hard we we were really really
intentional with the design um I we knew
we didn't want to just one of our other
guiding philosophies is you can't be
perceived to be better until you're
first perceived to be different and so
we spent a lot of time in that upfront
design to make sure things were
different I also want to be clear we
were really intentional with the initial
like promotion distribution plan which I
think we'll touch on want get tell me
about the yeah tell me about it cuz I
think uh well I'll let you go ahead okay
biggest problem with podcasts is they
actually are really from like a
discovery a podcast Discovery
perspective perspective it's really hard
to find new podcasts like if you go on
your phone and you go on like apple and
look at the charts like you're not going
to see B2B podcasts there it's tough and
I I tried when I was researching this
show like okay what are who's my
competition as I'm designing this show
yeah and I yeah it was hard to find them
somehow like you found the couple and
you're like okay Chris Walker okay Dave
Gart like everyone kind of knows them
yep and then yeah it was it was actually
hard to find what I ended up doing was
just asking marketers hey what are the
top five podcasts you listen to or any
podcast you've listened to that you
didn't like and you never came back and
so like Word of Mouth to me is like the
way we find podcasts probably social
media that's right so podcast Discovery
is tough and word of mouth is actually
that's the number one way that our
podcast grows at least according to the
Spotify analytics I looked at last year
the hardest thing about growing your
podcast is going from like it's the cold
start problem it's going from zero
listeners to your first 100 it's a lot
easier to go from 10,000 to 10,100 than
it is to go to Zer so for us it was like
how do we get this in front of people so
we used like our sales chops arm and I
when we launched the show we both
committed to each other that we were
going to text we were going to
personally text in a drip
sequence 200 people in our Network 100
each no 200 each wow 200 each and the
yeah the first 50 it's easy right it's
like guys I wrestled with it's like
buddies from high school cousins next
hundred a little a little bit tougher
like co-workers from two jobs ago the
last 30 I'm like hitting up
ex-girlfriends and I'm like hey
launching a podcast hope you've been
good would you mind giving it a sub when
it comes out like so awkward but we did
actually a twostep drip where the first
one I don't know I I think this was like
it was It was kind of crafty it was like
the first ask there wasn't anything
anybody had to immediately do it was
just hey we're launching a podcast in a
couple weeks when it comes out would you
be open to giving us a fstar review and
sharing it with your network you don't
need to do anything today and so the um
positive response rate was much higher
because there was no immediate action
people had to take just a quick
agreement got you yeah now now you're
locked in you already said yes so two
weeks later I'm like hey you know how
you said yes to that thing it's live
here's the link will you share it and so
we got that like initial burst and
Armand and I also we intentionally like
we kind of went on like a podcast tour
we went on a couple other sales podcasts
and we tried to game everything to all
go out the same week or maybe same month
to get like an initial burst um but that
was really by Design so yeah yeah it's
not a really great answer to question of
like oh this was the moment but I think
that was because we put a lot of upfront
work into making sure it got a lot of
eyes on it that's smart it's smart it's
it's like it's simple in a good way
which is like but most people won't do
it most people wouldn't think to do it
like oh that's a either that's a lot of
work or it's like uncomfortable to like
you said after that first 5050 it's like
how bad do you want it like do you want
your show to have as many eyeballs as
quickly as possible are you okay you
know maybe a little slower roll and an
easier path well you said something
earlier about how you think most most
B2B marketers think that they have to be
everywhere and you think that's like one
of the biggest mistakes people make sure
I think this is an Alex Heros thing um
he talks about it's kind of hubris to
believe that you can compete on 20
different Battlegrounds and you're going
to win all of them if all of my
attention is focused on the one
Battleground the one front of the
podcast and I'm not worried about
webinars or newsletter or live shows or
anything else I'm just focused on
podcast I'm going to beat 12th of Devon
Reed even you might be way better at
marketing than me right but if you've
got 20 things you're working on and I'm
just focused on one I'm going to win on
that specific Channel and for Content
that matters way more than other places
because um I think there's sort of like
a power law in terms of the way content
gets consumed where the best quality
content gets 90% of the downloads and
every other podcast goes to a graveyard
where it gets 12 people listen to an
episode so I want to turn it back on you
okay and I want to ask you I think you
started with the newsletter if I'm not
mistaken I've been reading your
newsletter for a long time technically
LinkedIn ah okay was L my first channel
sure okay if you want to go Channel if
you're saying from there it would be
newsletter okay what went into the
promotion plan for the newsletter I was
actually going to ask about this show
but I'm really curious about how you got
initial traction with the newsletter uh
o I wasn't ready for the the reversal I
try to flip it every now and theno
reversal take the pressure off me when
the guest is doing bad I like it doing
great um okay good question so for
context it was
2021 believe maybe 2022 and you were
fulltime other elsewhere so that's why
I'm going I'm going to give the context
that I was a full-time employ I was head
of content at gong and basically what I
had realized was I had become good at my
job
was starting to do well right and I was
doing two things one I was posting a lot
of advice and stuff about content
marketing content strategy on LinkedIn
yeah I've done it for a while yeah and
people that were either at my I say
level in terms of seniority or higher
were reaching out and dming me and be
like hey can we get on 15 minutes 30
minutes to pick your brain pick your
brain pick your brain I got a lot of lot
of brain pick lot a lot of brain a lot
of offers for the brain to get picked
and so I was like okay what if instead
of doing free 30 minutes which is really
terrible for me now it was really good
at first because it built my confidence
yeah totally I'm like I was a Content
strategy manager a title I had made up 6
months prior and now directors and some
VPS of smaller companies are reaching
out like hey can I get advice and I was
like and you probably showed up and
they're wow like you're saying basic
stuff and they're like oh man like how
do we work with you more well I was like
I remember the first person who did it
um was a director I won't say which
company but but was a director he
reached out and he was like can we get
time I'm like sure cuz it was it was one
of those early conversations where I'm
like sure I'll whatever and um he was
like how are you thinking about creating
content and I said the first thing I
start with is emotion I think about what
emotion do I want my reader to feel yeah
and he was like Dr he was like taking it
back he was like oh my God I had never
thought of it that way yeah and this guy
been doing it for like eight years and
so I was like I don't know if that makes
me bad/ crazy or if am actually decent
at this and this is like an Insight that
could be shared broadly so the first
part was I should stop doing free 30
minute sessions and make and charge
people candidly for my time I also was
starting to have kids so I'm like time
is spread thin I might as well make
money but I also figured why should one
person get this advice for free when
hundreds or thousands of people you know
I could help more people basically at
scale so I thought okay great let me
start the newsletter now the other the
other thing I should say is I thought I
was going to write a book so I was like
I'm going to write a book cuz I've
always wanted to write a book as a kid
I'm like I'm going to be an author and
I'm like every Saturday morning I'm
going to go to my office and I'm going
to write like a thousand words for this
book and in a few weeks I'm going to
have a book yeah think it was week three
grab my laptop I start walking upstairs
I'm like on stair five and I go I really
don't want to go do this yeah and so I
was like okay how do I continue to share
this insight to help people how do I
ensure every week I'm writing something
and I can hit some sort of like quota
uhuh so I'm still building a a um body
of work that I can turn into a book so
that's then I was like I'll do the
newsletter so that was a whole lot of
context the answer to Distributing it
was literally like I don't know I had
like 40 50,000 people on LinkedIn and
I'm like I'm just going to launch it
into that audience like and I did I got
like 1,500 in like the first week or two
and it was probably like your super fans
or the people maybe I did a decent job
promoting it but it was really like I
mean we could probably find the post it
was literally hey I have a newsletter
now here's what I'm going to talk about
go subscribe I think I just did a couple
of those and got to like that first 1500
2000 and then it's just been a I say
slow meaning slow methodical and organic
growth since then yeah because I've also
cut a lot of people I remove people that
are dead or not engaged because I want a
healthy list like I have 45% or more
open rate but I like I want like a
dedicated group of people who believe
what I believe want what I have to say
versus like how do I get to 100,000 as
fast as possible with a 14% open
just so I can go sell a bunch of ads
totally yeah I mean the other the other
thing you might consider though is like
as that grows the really powerful thing
about a newsl list is you can use it to
direct to something probably faster and
more powerfully than any other channel
like I want someone to sign up for a
webinar or take advantage of a sponsor
offering I think the newsletter is the
conversion rate on a newsletter is like
the equivalent of us running half a
million podcast ads one newsletter send
half a million podcast ads it's crazy
just like what it does from a conversion
perspective but list is the number one
marketing metric that I track right now
so now that I'm gone uh solo and I'm
fulltime with the reader now I'm like
okay I'm doing paid growth I'm doing
more organic growth I'm thinking through
it I'm starting to do more lead magnets
so now I'm like yeah to your point like
next year I want to get so I'm at I
think at time of recording around 15,000
I want to get to 30 next year in a
healthy way are you considering paid ads
for it I'm already doing I just started
paid ads last week dude the paid ads I
mean we're acquiring people for I don't
know $130 for a subscriber and are you
on LinkedIn or like through the through
the like um I run them Sean runs the
paid ads no we run them on like we run
paid ads on Instagram we run them on
Facebook I think I don't think we do
LinkedIn because it was considerably
more expensive super expensive $0 I'm
pretty sure it's meta is where we're
seeing the most success and so we have a
ton of different lead magnets and so we
just run paid ads against those and it
what completed the funnel for us is when
we've launched our book so it's funny
you're talking about the book I
experienced that same pain in the prep
document you sent me for this you were
like what was one of the big growth bets
that you placed yeah doing the de voice
too I like that
that's couple offes deeper um it was the
book dude it was Armand and I decided we
were going to write a book on cold
calling I know I'm going to be really
rude of a host can we go really quickly
sequentially through the channels
because I think if people right now just
hearing this they're like okay they had
a show then the
newsletter Qui but just and then we'll
get to the book yep so podcast crazy
growth immediately then you what was
your second channel so okay I'll give
you the growth story of like timing and
channel because I think the book is like
your big recent thing that was the most
recent so okay so we're back in 2020 we
launch in
um May 3 months go by we originally like
we were not going to sell sponsorships
we were like that's lame like we thought
sales guys didn't want to sell
sponsorship no we thought we were going
to sell
um like Consulting gigs so we sold one
Consulting gig it was we rewrote a
company's entire outbound sequence
strategy like we built multiple
sequences for them um for
$3,000 which don't WR so much work
though it's a lot $3,000 is like that's
a depreciable amount of money I'll take
three grand all day except when I ran
the math on what Arma I made dollar per
hour and I'm like dude we could probably
go get a job at pets and make more than
doing this um and I'm like we spent
multip Saturdays and Sundays on Zoom
meetings together like rewriting copy it
was brutal so we're like screw that and
the reality was Devon like this is now
November 2020 people are just throwing
money at marketing stuff and they don't
care about attribution they don't care
about if it's effective there was a big
budget increase because they had to move
it from inperson events to digital and
so digital got flush with cash yeah so I
mean we sold one two three four
sponsorships just for podcast ads and um
then someone was like Hey dude like if
you guys did webinars people pay a lot
of money for those lead lists and I'm
like okay so Arman and I debated that a
lot because that was probably the first
point that we felt tension between
what's right for the audience versus
what's right for
sponsorships and we were really
skeptical of webinars and frankly we we
still kind of are um the great thing
about webinars there a lot of our
content is sales related content and so
it's tough to do a sales podcast about
how to write a great sales email without
being able to see that email you can do
that in a webinar format there's also
something about like the live Q&A that
people can do in a webinar but um so we
launched webinars next so we did podcast
webinars probably six months after that
and the first one we did we almost 2,000
people sign up and I remember being like
wow and people are like hey can we
sponsor those I feel like that I was one
of those people I think done one or
something and I remember like like yeah
we did like 2,000 and I was like so I
will take all that you have to all that
you're selling I'm buying so so we did
that newsletter came right after that
because we realized that newsletter and
webinar worked really well in tandem
because when someone signs up for a
webinar they opt into the newsletter
list but if they don't hear from us for
another quarter until the next webinar
comes it's kind of like they're not used
to seeing us in their inbox um so we set
up a newsletter Cadence in the beginning
though it was once a month like we only
sent a newsletter once a month month and
we were talking about this in the
pre-show it was hideous we made a
decision with the newsletter and this
goes back to the educational versus
entertaining content we made a decision
with the newsletter that we wanted the
content to be valuable before it was
like
well-designed I don't think the first
editions hit on either of those you mean
aesthetically designed to be clear
aesthetically designed correct yeah
although I don't know how much we we had
like seven different sections in the
newsletter like this week's mindset tip
and this weeks cold call opener of the
month and yeah um so it took us a while
to iterate but also I don't regret doing
that cuz we got something out there so
anyways okay launch the podcast first 6
months later we go webinars uh in tandem
with newsletter and we stuck with those
channels for maybe three well three
years how many more years probably two
more years before launching anything
else obviously we had LinkedIn also what
did you take from the podcast yeah to
the webinars and to the emails to make
them successful and and what I mean by
this is like a lot of times people have
like a gem they have something that
works and then they're like we're going
to go launch this new channel and they
start from scratch yeah instead of like
hey why don't you take 60% of that first
channel that's working what you know is
hitting and then just like um molding it
to the new channel you know what I mean
so like where the webinars like pretty
much designed like the podcast and then
a little sounds like a little bit over
time the newsletter was designed like
the podcast which is like highly
actionable super concise yeah
it was all meant to be value Den in fact
the webinars we had a point of view of
like no 60-minute webinars we did not
want 60-minute webinars they were going
to be 30 minutes the name of the show is
30 I was like it's right there
you the problem is if you actually think
about a webinar you got to start two or
three minutes after the hour starts cuz
people show up late you've got to like
let people know this will be recorded
ask your questions in the Q&A box um and
we can consistently got feedback from
the audience of like we want these to be
longer and we actually liked that we lik
that we eventually switched to 60 Minute
ones because um yeah it made the content
better so I think we wanted the
constraint of we want to leave PE leave
people wanting more yeah but at a
certain point we're like these will be
better 60 minutes so I think the the
focus for us was like what what gives
the audience the best experience what
gives them what they are looking to do
which is in this case learn how to sell
you're going to there's a sorry I know I
I signaled I wanted to talk I apologize
um I got excited because there's a
lesson in here which is a lot of times
people will say oh we had drop off at
minute 50 or the consumption rate of our
podcast isn't as high as we want and the
number one thing I hear is let's make it
shorter yeah let's make it shorter yeah
people's attention spans are short we
need to make it shorter and I like that
you're saying value density I say
potency but I like value density more
which is like look now I'm not trying to
be the Joe Rogan podcast but it's the
most popular show in the world that I
know of at least in America and it's 3
hours long M Bollywood is the most
popular movies in the world and those
are 3 hours long Godfather Three two or
three hours long so I'm like don't tell
me that the content's too long tell me
that it's not good enough tell me that
it's the pace is slow or you know what I
mean it's not value dense enough where
there's a moment at minute 20 to 25
where we should have cut it going back
to so that's why I love it's like hey we
stuck to the brand identity 30 minutes
and our audience is the one that said we
want more correct versus starting with
60 Minutes being exhaustive and dragging
on and being like a crap we should
probably actually go to 40 45 minutes so
I think that's great that you guys were
listening in that way well so one more
point that I want to make
is around the different content work
streams because I don't know I think we
kind of glazed over it it was the point
that you made earlier Devon about taking
on too much and I made the point about
like I don't want to have to fight on
every single Battleground there are
channels that we have purposely
neglected because I don't think we can
win those channels and I don't think we
can win them based on our team's current
capacity and the reality is is every
team has a certain amount of capacity
and you have to decide I would rather be
the best in the world actually this is
one other thing this came from the book
good to Great Jim Collin I was waiting
for you we talk about this a lot I was
waiting for you to bring this up um he
talks about the Hedgehog Concept in the
book I forget why it's called the
Hedgehog concept but he talks about the
three elements that must be true in
order for you to have a worldclass
business one you have to have something
that is economically feasible meaning
you can make money doing it doesn't
matter how good you are at it it doesn't
matter how much people love your show
Devon like if you can't pay for your
grocery bill like you can't do this
anymore right so that's one piece there
has to be an economic engine behind it
number two is you have to be the best in
the world at it not just good not great
like you have to really believe that you
can be the best in the world at that
thing and for us it was like okay we
think we can have the best in the world
podcast we think we can have the best in
the world webinars we think we can
newsletter we tried we broke that once
where we did like bespoke YouTube videos
and it almost broke us dude it was
really it was like it was a whole extra
work day of work for me to like concept
film we had to get the editing team
doing it like it was too much and it was
a totally separate work stream which I
want to comment on in a second yes yes
it was too much and so we actually
stopped doing custom like you can see it
like we now we publish podcast on
YouTube because um video podcasts are
exploding there was just an article in
the Wall Street Journal about this more
and more people are watching podcasts
than they are listening to it so I'm
glad we're here with cameras on um but
you have to be the best in the world at
it and then the third piece is it has to
be something that like you actually
enjoy and believe in and if those three
three things aren't true like you don't
really have a business that's like
longterm going to be great so that was
point one that I wanted to make which is
like I think we glazed over it but it is
really really true you are better off
narrowing your focus and being the best
in the world at the Battlegrounds that
fit those three things for you and then
two one other thing that I would
encourage folks listening to this to
consider is to think about the work
streams for those different domains for
us we actually had a fourth Channel
which would be LinkedIn which you talked
about earlier yeah every time I had a
podcast guest on we would carve out a
video clip of them saying something
particularly astute or me saying
something that was like a great sound
bite well that fueled our LinkedIn
growth and if we had a really really
good guest on the show where we like wow
this person was world class great hey
you're going to be on our next webinar
and we're going to run back what we just
did here and so what and then the
newsletter it's like great hey here's
the top eight takeaways from this
episode that we have now there's two
pieces one the content's already created
for us from the guest yes two we've got
something to F fuel the newsletter three
newsletter is now driving people to
consume the podcast and so it's not four
separate bespoke channels that have
nothing to do with each other we call it
the connective tissue strategy of they
all sort of work together in a way that
allows us to produce more great media
with less um effort from our side it was
a flywheel you figured out a flywheel
because you can't do content Island you
can't have the social person out doing
their social stuff disconnected from
everything else you can't have the
podcast just doing its own thing so I I
like that you I like that you did that
did what I could so are you on you I
feel like you guys are on YouTube now
investing pretty heavily well I maybe
maybe I caught the we got started flash
flashing the pan and then I assumed you
invested a lot so it was literally every
Friday Arman and I committed to doing a
video we had a whole editing team Arman
spent like I don't know 40 hours over a
couple weeks like listening to all these
Mr Beast videos and like learning a
specific editing style and we we did it
and we like we got some good initial
traction but I'll be honest
like like we were not able to sustain
all of the other things that we needed
to do Y and we decied to Pivot our
energy into so we still publish the
podcast so podcast now we record video
and I just got like a whole teleprompter
setup so when I'm doing it like I'm
looking guest size um as opposed to like
making it look like a zoom where you're
like looking up at the camera and up and
down um so that's going out on YouTube
we eventually want to do YouTube but we
need to create more back office leverage
in our business because the sort of
tough thing about our business is like
I'm in the content but I'm also selling
all of our sponsorship deals Arman in
the content he's running all of like the
marketing for our business Sean's doing
all the marketing Ops and he know
customer success but like we all have
two or three jobs and we can't afford to
pull me off of sales to do more content
otherwise we're not going to make money
right so
right probably almost a broken record
podcast yes webinars yes don't tell me
newsletter but LinkedIn was in there
somewhere but we'll just LinkedIn was
around the podcast yeah so like those
are that was your distribution that was
kind of your distribution strategy we
did two in tandem actually if you think
about it podcast and Linkedin launched
around the same time you uh webinars and
newsletter around the same time yes
LinkedIn was a really intentional piece
of podcast and you asked about
distribution we always carved out video
clips and we made the guest promote we
didn't ask we made them how do you make
versus ask and I and I I ask yeah
because I do the same thing on my show
now thankfully all my guests post but
all my guests are usually like active
soci but I did this when I was running
the atong which I went to the editor and
I said look I need a of them looking
cool or sounding smart ideally both yes
because if I give that to Nick
afterwards he's going to it's like uh
tapping into your ego a little bit like
who I look really good and cool I'm
going to post this but in in B2B land
like in-house not everyone posts
obviously so how do you make someone
post we probably have like a 90%
compliance rate with guests sharing the
show yeah the way that we do that is one
we talk about Atomic habits earlier I
think it's I forget what they call it
it's like a commitment contract or a
commitment device at the end of the show
when the recording's done the cameras
come down the mics are away rapport with
you and the guest is at its highest
that's when you ask you say hey man this
was awesome Nick you crushed it like
here's what's going to happen next I'm
going to get this over to the editing
team they're going to chop it up they're
going to put some work into this thing
like really build up like we're doing
some work here right The Day The Show
Goes live and this is planning to go out
on August 15th right I'm going to make a
post sh's going to make a post we'll
have a newsletter blast go out to all
the reader subscribers hey if we get you
that video clip like two or three weeks
in advance would you be cool posting on
LinkedIn also everyone's going to say
yes everybody's going to say yes cuz
they're feeling so good about things and
you just showed it's kind of a sales
thing like there's a reciprocity the
give forget they're going to say yes
well now you've gotten their commitment
yeah and so now when you follow up and
you got to just you have to be
disciplined and following up with them
hey here your Clips like still good to
make a post and then if they don't you
guilt them hey here's our newsletter
blast attached here here's my LinkedIn
post yeah exactly and like PE people
will the other thing is like if you have
a big name guest don't ask them to post
ask to be looped in with their marketing
team um and and get that them to help
amplify it so yeah it's nothing like
fancy I think the the commitment device
thing helps quite a bit though have you
read influence by chal um I've skimmed
it I think because you did a webinar
with them with gong years ago I did I
got to meet him uh Robert chalini for
folks if you know me you know I've said
this a thousand times if it's if you're
hearing for the first time the number
one uh marketing book that I recommend I
got to go through it it is that good
when I think of like when I started to
really get it in marketing and and like
seeing success it was in tandem with
reading this book really so there's two
there's seven laws of persuasion you've
just listed two which is reciprocity and
commitment yes and they've even done
some behavioral uh studies behavioral
psychology studies of hey if we call you
two weeks before asking will you do this
thing and they say yes there's a 70%
increase or 70% likelihood that they
will comply later when the actual ask
comes so earlier when you were telling
me the text yeah same thing brilliant
same thing now you're doing the same
thing you're also doing Unity which I
think is Robert chini's eighth law he
did he had an eighth one for his you
know when he that's a great way to
continue your books going exactly which
is Unity which I think is something to
the same effect of like hey I did it
Char's doing it we all did our part It's
kind of your turn you don't want to be
an outcast yeah you don't want to be an
outcast and you kind of I would feel
like a jerk if you had sent to me but I
wouldn't make you I wouldn't be mad at
you for making me feel that way and
that's the subtle difference which is
like a lot of times hey I'm really
trying to get someone to post I'm really
trying to do something and it's easy to
kind of like Point your finger or finger
wag at someone and guilt is a really bad
motivator yeah I think intrinsic guilt
is a great one yeah well what we'll do
is we'll also be like hey this was like
this was a cute like well hype it up
it's like this is one of our best
episodes if we have like real download
you told that to me you said that to me
de this was the greatest episode we've
ever had can you uh all your guest that
mind doing a newsletter blast um yeah so
that's that's sort of our approach I
love it okay now I cut you off earlier
like a jerk I've been cutting you off
like a jerk actually no I've just been
not staying on track you ask a question
and I answer a totally different it's
okay it's okay I'm D I'm you're you're
you're doing great most of this will be
kept like 10% of the conversation will
be and it'll be you talking and me being
like y my intro some stuff I said in the
outro um you were talking about the book
then I asked what big you know uh the
the prep question was were any big
growth plays which is me trying to get
stories out of you yeah and it sounds
like the book was one of them which is
also not a channel I guess you could
argue that it you don't think a book's
media uh is it a medium I guess like a
channel yeah yeah I wouldn't I wouldn't
even fight on that Hill I'd go fine my
thought is like a book is a project sure
cuz it's a one-off and then you
obviously promote it but tell me about
the book because I thought and I texted
you this I said brilliant that you did
it cuz I'm sure your audience like sales
books sell like crazy yes I'm sure
audience was asking SL demanding for one
and you very smartly partnered with gong
to do it so walk me through why did you
write a book and how did that go a
variety of different drivers some like
lifestyle like yours of like we thought
it'd be cool to write a book another
of there's this if you think about our
audience Tam there's pretty much anyone
who works in sales or sells something
like we have Consultants lawyers Etc um
yeah um but there's if you think about
like our audience Tam there's a segment
that listens to sales podcasts there's a
segment that joins webinars there's a
segment that they're only going to be on
LinkedIn and there's a lot of companies
in saleson boarding not many companies
on sales onboarding you're joining a new
company they say hey go listen to these
podcasts or sign up for this newsletter
almost every Salesforce they're like hey
you're going to read this book before
your first yeah Challenger
sale SP selling right and were like this
could be a way for us to infiltrate the
teams and go way deeper
and we saw this as a massive audience
growth play and a way to go much deeper
with our audience the other thing that I
think folks sometimes Miss with B2B
content or sort of like what you and I
are doing is there's the depth of the
relationship your audience has with you
and I think LinkedIn is you can have a
really really big LinkedIn following but
it's not the same is like if I listen to
Devon every single week on his podcast
or I watch him you start to get to know
that person and a book you just go way
deeper um and so we saw it as a way to
like deepen the relationship with the
audience and then also frankly
established some credibility which one
of the weirdest things about growing
bigger and bigger and bigger is dude I'm
still selling every single day I sell I
Prospect I negotiate I'm giving demos of
our sponsorships I'm like figuring out
how we're going to renew and expand I
sell every day and I see people are like
oh 30 NPC they're just sales influencers
and I'm like dude like like that's it's
just not true like don't get me wrong
we've built an entire engine to amplify
me and Arman but like we're still
getting in front of customers and
selling and so it sort of irks me
sometimes when people are like oh those
guys don't sell anymore because it's not
true have you gone on Reddit have you
looked yourself up on Reddit oh it's a
great way to ruin your afternoon it's a
really really great way no yeah you
don't I just don't do it anymore um and
I lean a lot on the David goggin there's
a clip of David gogins I think on Joe
Rogan where he's like Joe you will never
let me you will never meet a hater doing
better than you you will never meet a
hater doing better than you and it's
true it is true because I don't know I
see these people are like oh you know
the best sales people don't have time to
be posting on LinkedIn and I'm like yeah
and the best sales people don't have
time to be posting hate comments on
Reddit either bro um but look like the
reality is that stuff's going to exist
and
it's weird though like you probably get
it also where like you'll get 10 really
really awesome messages of people being
like your stuff really helped me and
then you've got one Anonymous jerk and
it like really hurts you it's all you
remember is the one yeah and it's easy
to say oh let it roll off your back but
like I don't know one of the best
investments I ever made was starting to
go to therapy a couple years ago like
help me a ton as a person anyways book
it allowed us to like you go read that
book dude like it's a really good book
yeah and I was like you I'm like yeah
we're going to write I told Arman in the
beginning I'm like we'll probably get it
done in a
month oh my God BBY took let me guess I
bet you it took at least six months to
write in I probably co-wrote the book
together so he wrote a section I wrote a
section he wrote a which actually
probably made it take longer than just
writing yourself in a way yeah better in
one way probably harder than another if
you want to go fast go alone if you want
to go far go with others yep every day 4
hours a day both of us for 10 months
straight wo I was close I said so wake
up right for for 4 hours then go do your
full job running a business the next day
do it again and it was painful Dean I
remember Christmas Eve last year I'm
staying at my in-laws place in Orange
County and I wake up early I go to a
coffee shop I put my 4 hours in I wrote
the section on um what we call a problem
proposition which is our response to a
value proposition we talk about pitching
to problems rather than pitching value
in a sales pitch and I write what I
think is some of my best work I'm like
reading it out loud to myself I'm like
oh this is freaking good I sent it to
Armand 10 minutes go by 20 minutes go by
he calls me and I'm like for a little
you give me uh compliments uh verb and
he's he just like in a kind way just
rips it up man just RI like he's like
it's not structured right it feels
rushed like and it it I'm like it's
Christmas freaking Eve man you're like
and I was so angry at and he'll tell you
the same we it caused a lot of conflict
because not in like oh we're yelling at
each other but like it's really really
hard to align with somebody on here's
the best practice we're going to present
and here's the structure and the flow
and the writing and writing is deeply
deeply personal and we beat each other
up and I'm so freaking glad we did
because it is the best work he and I
ever put out it is better than the
podcast it is better than the newsletter
it is the best the it was the hardest
thing that I've done in my professional
career it's also the best content I've
produced so usually the case that's
usually the case the things that are the
hardest to do yeah and uh they come out
they come out the best but and you're
most proud of them I'm really proud of
that n work we've sold almost 30,000
copies in uh it came out in August
months ago yeah we're doing we're doing
pretty good with it and you did a smart
play which was uh relying on on
relationships and uh well the the gong
was one but the the one of the ways you
got the word out was I imagine I was one
of a couple hundred people that you hit
up your guest
and you said things to me as you tend to
do clearly all your guests you know hey
thanks so much for being on the we have
this book coming out would you be open
to promoting it and I'm like of course
you sent me a copy uh and I did one one
I would have done it like I think if you
had send it day before I still would
have because like you guys are you know
my friends I want to see you win but you
did a very good job and I thought it was
very smart like I felt a very was very
small but I felt like a part of the book
and the promotion because I'm like oh
yeah like my small contribution to one
episode helped them build this big thing
that helped them lead to this other
thing and I'm taking zero credit it just
felt like kind of back to like Unity
like yeah I'm like it's like rooting for
your team like I know I don't play for
the Warriors but when they win I still
say we and so I think it was like a
similar thing um I was very pleasantly
surprised to see a Gong badge or little
uh whatever you want to call it on the
um on the cover so for those who maybe
don't know gong is a revenue
intelligence sometimes called
conversation intelligence Tool uh I
worked there for a few years you did uh
and they uh record sales calls and give
you sales insights you use their
database to give you guys some depth
some data what was the reasoning behind
that partnership there is a lot of sales
advice that sounds good in theory but
does not work in practice and we wanted
every piece of advice that we gave in
the book to be datab backed because we
thought it would make the content better
and we pulled the audience cuz we were
torn we were like are people going to
think it's like sponsor like oh gone
like we pulled the audience we were like
if we partnered with somebody who could
provide data to support our claims like
would that make you like would you would
you put more credit in the book like
would you would you feel better about
this overwhelmingly people were like yes
please we want to know data back to what
works and it made the book way better
like we found out data around like when
you leave a voicemail in sales it
doubles your cold reply rate I saw that
I really like that one yeah so we were
able to like come to conclusions that
like our first chapter about voicemails
was all these um opinions about why you
should leave voicemails and our
anecdotal experience but then we were
able to just like we actually were able
to delete a lot of the chapter and be
like look at the data here's what it
says here's how you leave a great sales
voicemail so yeah we partnered with them
on that front um I'm happy to share more
about it if you'd like I like it man
yeah I have a question for you which is
you followed 30 minutes of president's
Club since it launched right you've been
following us since day three you've been
a multiple time customer you see where
we are right now what advice and you've
given us advice in the past we didn't
really talk about it our first
newsletter Edition you gave us some like
constructive criticism um what had been
pushing you to do the newsletter it was
I was telling you guys to get into email
right and uh that's not like and I told
you so it was just like it's like when
you see your friend doing something good
you're like go just go in this direction
I promise just trust me and then you
guys launched it I'm pretty sure I
bought out what did didn't I buy I think
I the one negotiation thing I think I
did really well maybe in my life was uh
uh persuading you and Arman to give me
exclusivity you got exclusivity on the
newsletter for a full year and we were
like so this is actually one of the
tough things about sponsored content is
sponsors want to pull on your content so
hard and it's even harder for us cuz you
talked about protecting the brand and
I've got someone they're like look I'll
give you $80,000 to do this and we're
like we're going to like you and Jen
talked about it on your episode about
like the reputation piece and the year
of diluted LinkedIn Brands like dude I
don't sell LinkedIn posts anymore I do
not sell sponsored LinkedIn posts um and
so we were like hm okay Devon wants
exclusivity for a year on the podcast or
on the the newsletter this could
basically fund us growing this channel
for a year and we know he's in aligned
with us in terms of good content
line out of exclusivity but it was was
pretty smart we worked with somebody
that we liked we made money the content
was the best in the world it was oh
that's the Hedgehog concept it it was
win-win and the reason I did it was uh
the exclusivity for context was like you
can't put other competitors on the
channel while I'm on the channel and the
reason I was so big on it was and I
remember negotiating with it was like
you guys were like you know if we do
this then we can't do that I'm like yeah
yeah but you haven't proven it yet and
in back of my head I go I know it's
going to take off but I'm still like I'm
like a uh like um you know those like
music managers that like lock you into
bad contract so they know you're going
to be a star I I I I did pull that a
little bit but I did what you said which
was like I know it's win-win I would
never do anything that I thought was
like bad for 30 MPC but it was like I
know this is going to be great I want
exclusivity so when it becomes great I
have that first mover's advantage and I
also knew rightfully you were going to
charge me way more at renewal because
the channel would blow up so like yeah
I'll get that going um so my question
was like What if you if you worked for
30 MPC I was like Deon Come On Come
Aboard we need a we need a VP marketing
we need a CMO would be a little what uh
yeah you know we need we need a CEO what
what would what
would how would you spend your first 30
days how would I spend my first 30 days
I'm I'm going to give you the I'm going
to I'm going to uh redact the answer I
know 30 MPC would hate which is like I
would get input and I would think right
I just give you the Tactical stuff the
first thing I would do is uh a very
diligent audit okay and the reason why
is I have a framework for growth which
is you can optimize or you can build
okay so I want to look at what we're
doing today and say what can what are we
doing that should get cut for you guys I
doubt that's much but it's more of like
where's there fat that I can trim to
make us leaner and to optimize what's
already working so maybe it's like if
the podcast is the the gem I'd say you
know and you guys did this so I'm giving
an example like hey it's works so well
with I what about a leadership podcast
like I would scale and optimize what's
working yeah the other side and and by
the way that's going to give you
shortterm fast wins whenever I'm
starting a new role that's what I want
to do within the first 30 maybe 60 days
I need a big public win or even a medium
visible win then I go into build mode
now build is the big bet that's read
between the lines for the reader right
so then I'd say okay great based on the
growth that we're seeing the
profitability and where we are in our
content maturity where is one the market
and like the world going and two where's
their Green Space that our audience is
being underserved that we can win at
Hedgehog mindset where can we go be
great and if we're missing anything like
hey we need another voice we need more
whatever resources I'm like great let's
think in what if land like what could be
big and then fill in the how and that is
a long-term bet that will have huge
upside but maybe in 6 or 12 sometimes
even 18 months but that's your build
program and so that's how I would break
it down as your new CMO that's good are
there things that you see from an
external perspective that you know you
would change for us I liked the
leadership podcast Edition which
obviously we've done are there flavors
like that give me give me one layer more
tactical I would I would revisit YouTube
because and not and not that's not the
easy answer that is I thought you guys
were still doing it and when I saw the
flash pan or flash in the pan however I
was like yep that's where they should be
so I would revisit that and I'd
understand why did it I'm going to say
fail but you know what I mean why did
why did we not continue what what do we
think the upside is and I personally
think like I'm 80% sure In This Moment
yeah that that's what I would bet
because it's where you guys can be great
the Channel's still booming salespeople
watch a ton of YouTube and so like
that's where I'd probably bet um and I
would resist the common CMO things of
redoing the website or launching some
big inperson event I think you guys
would be great at iners events but they
take a lot of time they're very
expensive and I think based on what I
know about your goals for the business I
don't think that's the direction that
you would need to go for long-term
success yeah yeah we've done them how I
do would you hire me after that good I'm
like all right I got to set you 1
through 10 how would that be how would
you rate that answer how
um I thought your second answer that
that that latter one where you were like
the YouTube the event I think the
YouTube piece is right yeah I think the
hardest thing for us is
like you see the the the front office of
the content and it's the back office of
all of the Ops and running the business
that gets in the way of us having the
bandwidth for it and so I think you
would come in and you would say oh okay
I actually think what you would fix
first would be the guts behind the scene
what slows us down the most is we've got
a web of different contractors doing
things for us
that it's hard to find really good
people and that bogs us down more than
anything where I can't just say great
here's the raw footage make it great
like Armand has to handhold um folks all
the way through and that keeps him from
being able to do more content to build
on that I actually did this before in my
career which was uh it was a Gong hyper
growth we've got headcount I had a
headcount to grow my content marketing
team there's a shift where overall
marketing they just moved some
headcounts we had less I gave my content
marketing role to Ops to hire an
operations person because I was
confident that's what was best for the
marketing team and myself long run which
was like look I could get another
creator for output but if the plumbing
isn't up to par it's actually going to
hurt more later so I'm like take Ops
take this person make everything make
the whole Foundation better and we'll
have a bigger impact on a l well it's
now now we're really heating up but I
feel like the Ops piece is the content
Ops is a really underrated element of
content marketing and folks don't
realize how much of an impact it has on
the brand on the final product like
you're not putting together like the
logo or the episode art for an image
like you might be thumbs uping it and if
you have someone that sucks and can't
put together something that looks good
that's going to hurt your brand and it's
going to distract you from prepping for
the next guest interview dashboards
don't work so you can't make strategic
decisions links don't work so your
conversions drop all those things matter
but they're not really like sexy they're
not public facing but it hurts when you
say hey we send an email to 82,000
people we had a 8% click through I went
to a dead link oh it happens it happens
and so it's like that's content Ops to
me and we had we had one guy uh Vince
shout out to Vince love Vince Vince was
on the operations team but he was half
on my team half on I know Vince Vince is
awesome content Vin is a badass man yeah
and that was like one of our superpowers
was like we had someone who understood
the content strategy and understood the
operation strategy and could like
straddle both and made sure paiges
looked the way they needed to performed
the way they needed to and like that was
a big driver for us yeah oh it make me
happy you bring him up cuz I like that
guy well man it's cliche to say um but I
could talk to you all day so instead
what I'm going to say is man this was
one of the best shows that we've ever
done so here Nick this is what we're
going to do we're going to chop this
episode up I'm going to post about it
sh's going to post about it and uh we
would love uh if you would post about it
and we'll give you a heads up about two
weeks in advance and I'm going to do
newsletter blast does that sound like
something you could commit to you know
what I think uh we can help promote this
one for sure Fant thank you for having
this was fun it was fun to not talk
about sales for once cuz that's what I
spend 98% of my media appearances doing
you did a great job despite what you
made have you despite what you think of
yourself you did great job uh but no man
thanks for sharing your wisdom I really
appreciate it thanks for having me all
right that's a wrap for today and if
you're still listening you must really
crave growth and I respect that here are
three ways I can help you grow your
content right now first subscribe to the
reader newsletter you'll get actionable
writing and marketing advice delivered
straight to your inbox every Saturday
morning two make sure you hit subscribe
on YouTube so you get access to new
episodes and new videos when they drop
and three if you want to sponsor or hire
the reader you can send me an email at
yo the reader.com that's yo the reader.
and if you're enjoying the show make
sure to drop us a five-star review it
helps us get new sponsors and grow I'll
see you next time