Uh in our last conversation you
mentioned you really want to give one
aha moment for the listeners. So what's
one mindset shift or move our listeners
can take to level up their content
starting this week?
>> Oo okay to level up their content style?
Um
so one content insight you can do this
week stop making your top offunnel
content like very heavily
definitionbased. The moment somebody
enters your ecosystem, they should
understand what your status quo is on
the category. So when we think of top
offunnel content, you think of like what
is this or this statistics or topic
whatever immediately indoctrinate people
the moment they enter your ecosystem
from the top of the funnel and start
injecting more opinion into top of
funnel. Right? It's not just a what is
payroll, you know, what is what is
payroll management? It's how I feel
about payroll management, how payroll
management should be ran. Here's how
most people do it and here's why we
think that's wrong, you know? So, just
like indoctrinate. That's that's that's
what I would say you could do this week.
[Music]
A couple of years ago, I was working as
an in-house product marketer trying to
figure out how to get our blog to
actually do something, not just bring
traffic, but real leads. That's when I
found Lache on LinkedIn. Her posts felt
different. No buzzwords, no jargon, just
straight up value on how to write bottom
of the funnel content that brings people
ready to buy. I remember saving so many
of her posts that I literally had to
refer to them while planning my content,
what my team was working on, and her
stuff literally gave me a lot of clarity
when I had none in the bofu side of
things. And now we are here 2 years
later and I get to talk to her on this
podcast. Lasher Lewis is the founder of
bofu.ai and probably one of the most
practical voices in content marketing
today. She has helped brands boost block
conversions, build comparison pages that
actually work and most importantly
connect content to revenue. So if you're
working in B2B trying to turn content
into real results, this episode is the
deal. Lashe, welcome to Behind the Reef.
How are you doing today?
>> I am wonderful. Thank you for the
amazing introduction. I am super excited
to be here. Um, I really hope to be able
to give a lot of value today. So, thank
you. And I'm super excited.
>> Thank you so much. And I'm super
excited. So, let's do some real talk on
why Bofu still gets missed. So, let's go
back to basics for a second, right? A
lot of teams still overload their blogs
with tofu content and wonder why it's
not converting. What like what your
opinion on that?
>> I feel like it's like one of the most
common problems that teams are facing
right now. And a lot of times when I
create LinkedIn content and I talk about
these things, the marketers that are
actually on the ground doing the the
boots on the ground work get to see it,
but I'm really talking to leadership
because that's where a lot of marketers
get the most push back. So even if they
do want to do the bottom of funnel
thing, they have to go through two or
three people just to even get approvals
on being able to write this type of
content, you know. So a lot of my
content is geared toward typically VP of
marketing professionals, CMOs, like
higher level professionals mainly
because well two types of content. So
the visual style content is for the
marketers to grasp and understand. the
more like platitude style. Okay, here's
my thoughts on the industry. Posts are
more Seale directed again because
culture is dripped from the top down,
not the bottom up. So, you need to have
the people that are leading the company
have a culture of, yeah, we're not going
to focus all of our attention on top of
funnel because we know while it
generates traffic, it's not the best at
generating actual leads and inbound
leads. And so it's just about setting
that expectation of like you can you
can't have both, right? You can have
both, but you either need to change the
strategy and focus more on bottom of
funnel if you want inbound leads or if
you want more top highle demand style
generation stuff, that's when you go top
of funnel. But you cannot go top of
funnel and expect bottom of funnel
results, right? And every part of the
funnel is important. It's just knowing
what part of the funnel does what and
then based on that, that's where you
shift your focus. Yeah.
>> I have a follow-up question on that.
Like, why do you think BFU content still
gets ignored and why most B2B teams are
still not doing the right thing with
Bofu content?
>> It gets ignored because so you know how
people say, you know, don't judge a book
by its cover. It gets ignored because
the cover is pretty boring, right? So,
when you look at bottom of funnel
content, typically you'll see like lower
search volume and which creates a
sequence in people's heads of like,
well, if it has low search volume, I'm
probably not going to get that much
traffic from it, why am I wasting my
time with this when I could go after a
search term that gets 50,000 searches a
month and be able to at least capture
even if I could capture like 10% of that
traffic, that would be amazing for my
company, right? And again, it all
depends on the goal. That's amazing for
your company if that's what your goal is
to do. Top high level awareness. But it
doesn't matter if you rank for something
that has 100,000 searches a month. If
the intent is not there to purchase
something, they will not purchase
anything. Versus if you focus on a
bottom ofunnel search term with let's
say 30 searches a month, if the intent
is there that will convert, I've seen up
to three times higher than top ofunnel
content, you know? So I think it's just
a matter of like it's different for
them. Again the the usually like seuite
level individuals again VP of marketing
type of individuals are very like now
now now how can I get the most this the
most that I want the most leads. So, you
know, theoretically it's like, okay, let
me focus on the thing that has the
highest search term cuz, you know, it
makes sense that that would get me
leads, but there's a nuance in a level
deeper that they need to go and say
intent over volume is what I always say.
So, again, you know, if somebody's like,
hey, I want to drive inbound leads, and
I bring them back a list of keywords
that are like 10 or 20 searches, and
they're like, hey, well, you know, these
are a little low. Do you think we're
going to? I'm like, yeah, of course we
are. Um, also I just think it gets
ignored because it's not cute, right?
It's just it's not as exciting as like
seeing 50,000 searches a month in age
roughs or 10,000 searches a month versus
seeing 30 searches a month, you know?
It's just not as exciting. So, people
tend to ignore it and say, you know
what, let's go after the big stuff when
honestly the little stuff is usually
easier to rank for um and um much more
high intent. Yeah,
>> I think looking at the numbers that Bofu
has versus TOFU, I think the excitement
is where it lies at the top of the
funnel. But I think the real work that
gets actually converted, the real
numbers that should be getting converted
are at the bottom. So maybe it's boring,
maybe it's not that exciting, but it
brings money. So I think you need to
focus on that as well. And it's
important and you need to do that right.
>> But also it's hard too, right? like it's
easier
to create top offunnel content. And the
the reason it's easier to do that is
because the knowledge level of the
reader is probably handinhand with the
knowledge level of the writer. The
knowledge level of the reader is pretty
low because they are not really problem
aware a little bit. They're trying to
figure it out. They're not solution
aware. So, it's like it's easier to hire
a random freelancer and say, "Hey,
create this article for me on like what
is payroll management?" Like, what is
it? You know, because typically what
they'll do is they'll go around Google
and pull things and say, you know, hey,
compile this together or they they'll go
to GPT and say, hey, I'm trying to
create an article on payroll management.
Can you give me an outline? Something
like that.
>> Exactly.
The reason it's easier to do that again
because the knowledge level of the
reader is low. But when you start to
move toward bottom of funnel, the
knowledge level of the reader gets
higher because they're more solution
aware. So they've probably been tasked
by somebody in the company to go look
for a solution and now they're reading
through blogs. They're they have a
nuance understanding of what their
problem is. And if the person that's
writing the content does not have a
nuance understanding of the topic to the
point where they can speak to it in
written content, the reader is going to
be able to smell it from a mile away,
you know? So, it's just it's nuances
there. And I think that's why a lot of
people shy away from it. They're just
like all this for 30 searches a month.
Like, I'm not um so I think there's
layers of why people don't do bottom of
funnel. Yeah.
>> Right. And I think one hack that we
could get into that system to actually
get it done with the right people, I
think get your blogs edited by sneeze.
They would have better idea on what the
topic is and why it's important to have
more specific uh you know takes in that
blog or whatever content that you're
creating for bottom of the funnel
instead of just writing generic uh
product knowledge or the industry scope
itself. So I think the subject matter
expert can add valid points to that and
make it more working in the motion I
guess
>> and with AI like there are ways to
create little workflows around this
right so if you have an interview you
know with a subject matter expert you
take the transcript run it through an
LLM and say hey can you pull out the
differentiators can you pull out some
key points that I can include can you
pull out some quotes that I can include
in the content that's what brings
content to life, you know. So, totally
like I I still think interviewing
subject matter experts is the play. Now,
I have ran into the the concern before
of like, oh, the subject matter experts
are so busy in my company. How do I get
an interview with them? So on and so
forth. So, it's like, yeah, and again,
it goes back to that point of like
bottom of funnel needing this stuff and
people are just like, well, is it worth
doing it? And things like that. So, you
know, I definitely feel like uh
interviewing the subject matter experts
is huge. If you can get an interview
with them, great. If they have written
previous pieces, try to like pull from
that. One thing that I would do is like
when I would have the interview with the
subject matter experts, like I would
just put everything in a dashboard so I
could have it to pull from for future
articles because bottom of funnel is
really just saying the same thing over
and over in slightly different ways for
slightly different use cases. But once I
have that information just stored away
and consolidated, I I'm usually pretty
good from there. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I think I have a lot of questions
to ask on the AI workflow side of
things. So, we definitely have to get
back on that topic. But I do have some
questions around the blog conversion
rates that you have reached. It's
reached till 30% for a lot of teams,
which sounds wild to most people like
how have you done that? What's something
that you always look for in a content
audit?
>> Right. So a lot of companies I work with
have some type of blog already. So I
always tell them it's easier to start
with something than from nothing. So if
they have bottom ofunnel content that
they've written, somebody in house has
written, another agency has written,
we'll go through that first and work on
increasing the con conversion rates from
those pieces first. And then once we do
that, then we say, okay, what net new
pieces can we add to this? you know, so
I definitely find that it's quicker
starting with pieces that they already
have and then so I have frameworks for
how I run things. So essentially I'm
looking at the piece, running it through
my own framework and saying, "Okay,
here's what we need to add. Let's
reposition this a little bit." Um, and
some of the clients that I worked with
have seen like massive conversion rates
from just making the content more
productled, right? Cuz I think I think
that's one of the issues, another issue
with bottom of funnel. a lot of issues.
But another one is like not making the
content entirely productled. It's I see
a lot of people shortcut the bottom of
funnel process. But when you make it
productled, what what does productled
mean? Well, describe your product. Like
what does it look like? What are the
screenshots? Can you give me any gifts?
Like give me contextual examples. Show
me how it works. You know, and a lot of
people just skip out that with that.
They just have a section that says like
features and it lists like three or four
features. It's like that is not
productled. You know what I mean? Like
productled is like you showing me
demonstrationally
how the product works in relation to the
use case that we're talking about.
That's how you show me productled
content. But it's just like again it's
tricky. It's difficult. Takes a lot of
time and teams are just bogged down.
Like they do not have the time to do
this stuff. Um and that's like the
common pain that I find amongst teams.
like they just don't let me rephrase
that. Maybe it's less they don't have
the time, more of that they don't have a
system in place to do this.
>> Exactly.
>> Yeah. I think I would also like to
believe the latter one because if you
have the systems then I think you get
the needle moving fast. I think that but
I think with AI things should be scaling
a little bit on that front. Everybody is
using AI to write content right now but
not everybody is doing it right. So I
think that connects to the previous
question on what's the biggest mistake
do you see people are doing right now
and how AI can help solve it.
>> Yeah. So the biggest thing that people
are probably doing wrong right now. So
there's been like So first of all
there's been a progression when AI first
kind of like hit the scene I would say
maybe like 2 years ago something like
that when it got really indoctrinated
people were producing like 200 articles
in three weeks and calling it a content
strategy. Right. Obviously that's not
the any real SEO knows that's not the
right way to do things. Um from there
people started like and I and I kind of
caught this two years ago. I was trying
to build a solution for it, but people
started recognizing that okay, the best
content is not written purely from
writing an input into an LLM. Like we
need the the LLM needs to be trained on
my company like my use cases, my
persona, my industry, capabilities, pain
points and features and benefits and all
this stuff. And I think the natural
progression after that was like okay
teams were starting to upload internal
documentation into GPT and using that to
like prompt things and you know pull
from that and I think the but to go back
to your question I think the biggest
mistake is just like people not taking
the time to do deep customer research.
That's the mistake. Even before you hit
GBP, like and maybe you can use like AI
to help you with some of that customer
research, not do it for you, but like
create workflows around that. So, for
example, like if you have sales calls,
record those sales calls and get AI to
find the commonality amongst the sales
calls. Like what are the pain points
that are being repeated over and you
know what I mean? So like just building
internal workflows to be able to help
you capture knowledge in a way where you
can take that knowledge and then create
a real customer ccentric content
strategy from it. If there's a mistake
that people are making, I would say it's
focusing on SEO and not focusing on the
actual customer. Like that's the
mistake.
>> Yeah, I think that would be the biggest
red flag when you are even viewing it
from a 360 angle and then that's where
the mistake is. That's where the leak is
happening in the the funnel as well.
>> Totally. Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, you have talked a lot about AI
and workflows. So, what does a great AI
powered workflow actually look like? And
I think you're building high performing
content, right? So, how is your internal
AI workflow looking like and what's one
thing that you can suggest people to get
started on today?
>> That's a great question. So, I would
tell people like don't listen to me when
it comes to this because I went over the
top. I got really cute. I built my own
platform. I did all this stuff. Nine
times out of 10, a lot of people do not
have the time to do that. So, I would
say that's another thing. But what a
good workflow looks like, it's it's
steps, right? So, like step one, we
gather internal documentation. I'm
literally running you through the steps
that I do, but this is what it looks
like. So, step one, we're gathering
internal documentation. And I'm talking
about like ICP docs, battle cards,
positioning decks, anything that
describes what the product is, what it
does, and who it serves, I'm gathering.
Then from there, I have workflows where
AI parses through the information to
pull out the things that I need to be
able to create bottom ofunnel content
like pain points and features and
capabilities. You know what I mean? So
like that's it. It's it's layered in
steps and then typically from there I do
something I call frameworkbased
prompting. Shout out to one of my
followers who gave me that verbiage, but
it's like so spot-on. So the reason that
my first drafts are really really good
is because I'm the I'm prompting from a
framework. So for context, when I ran my
consultancy from 2023 to March of this
year, 2025,
before I switched to bofu.ai, so so
authority plug was the first
consultancy, highly productized, and I
was like working with teams on a done
with you basis. We would plug content in
the frameworks, publish it, boom, that's
how we do it. But I took those same
frameworks and uh taught AI how to
produce from those frameworks. So the
first draft of the article that we're
getting is the framework. From there,
that's when I'll have an editor come in
and like edit up the piece from there.
And then once it's in a good spot, then
we'll publish. Right? So it's it's a
multi-layered process, but it's very
meticulous. I've to taken my time to
build this because I'm trying to build
nuance into AI and not just say scale
this, scale that. Like it needs to be
nuance built in you. So, I think a good
workflow is a connector. It doesn't
replace everything. It just fills in
gaps where your team needs the gaps
filled in. You know, it's not the end-
all beall. You should always have a
human in the loop. And that's like just
how I think about things. But yeah, I
would say a good AI workflow is just
your process, but like AI built into a
couple of different areas. Um, you know,
and just to be able to help kind of, and
I hate this word cuz it's like so vague,
but like streamline the workflow cuz
companies use it so terribly but just
like lies that type of workflow, you
know. So yeah, a good workflow is just
like multi-layered step system that
takes raw documentation to me and puts
it into high converting content like
that's what a good flow looks like at
least from a content perspective. Yeah.
>> Okay. I think that three-step framework,
the AI workflow that you have just
mentioned would I think it's going to be
a blast for people if they use it and I
would love for people to actually
comment and say what worked after they
try it in their own AI workflows. So,
thank you Lashe for sharing. It's going
to be helpful to a lot of people
actually working in content uh spaces.
>> For sure. Yes.
>> Yeah. So I really I'm really curious to
know your can you share a bit about your
journey from authority plug to bofu AI
like we definitely we didn't talk about
it but I would love to know your
experience as a founder and leading that
change I'm sure there must have been a
lot of pivots you must have seen a lot
of different challenges as well but then
do you want to share your story your
journey from there to here
>> sure so
I started in well first of all I've been
doing content strategy for like close to
15 years now. I count when I started at
15 years old and I was building
websites. Like I was teaching myself
content strategy then but I didn't know
it. In 2023 I was like you know what I
want to start my own consultancy. Trust
me the decision was not very
straightforward like that. It was very
like I had two jobs and got dropped from
one because I hated it and had to lot of
stuff in between. But I started that
first consultancy in 2023. I had got on,
if anybody knows, the Exit 5 podcast,
which is like the biggest place in B2B,
and Dave was gracious enough to get me
on there. And then everything kind of
blew up from there cuz on that pod, I
was talking about bottom of funnel and I
really brought something to the
forefront that other people did not talk
about for whatever reason, you know? And
I'm like, hey, you know this thing
bottom of funnel, here's how you should
do it. Boom. started booking sales calls
from there and I built my entire
consultancy in notion. So I had built a
really highly productized process where
it was like step one we do this, step
two we do this, step three we do that.
And I noticed a gap in the market late
2023, really early 2023, but I didn't
act on it until late 2023, like
November. And the gap in the market was
like
AI tools don't work from your internal
documentation. And that's probably the
reason that people can't write bottom of
funnel content. Like there's no AI tool
that can write good bottom ofunnel
content was my thought. And honestly,
that's still my thought. I still have
not found a tool that can write good AI
bottom of funnel content. But I have
something I'm working on to help close
that gap so we can
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> That's great.
But but at the end of 2023, I was like,
"Okay, you know what? I've productized
this consultancy quite a bit. I was
growing to the point where I was like, I
was going to have to hire somebody." And
I was like, "I really don't want to hire
anybody. I'm scared. I don't know if I'm
a good leader." Bunch of internal stuff.
So, I was like, "What if I could take my
process and just like AI it, you know?"
So, that's when like the concept of
bofu.ai was born. and I was going to
turn it into a product, but and this is
probably a whole another episode, but
like changed too many variables at once,
right? I changed the pricing, the offer,
the it was just like too much. And while
I was getting great feedback on the
tool, for context, it was totally built
in KOD, like it was very like bare
bones. I was getting amazing feedback,
but nobody was giving me money for it.
And I'm like, there's something going
on. And then I had lost a deal to
copy.ai, AI. And I was like, me as a
consultant, why am I losing a deal to a
software company? And then it dawned on
me like, well, that's because you
created a software and you're trying to
charge advising prices for it. And I'm
like, ooh, okay. So, I had to take a
step back. This was like August,
September of last year, 24. And I took a
step back. I'm like, you know what? Let
me go back to my old dashboard in
Notion. Let me just do the thing like
that. I've started selling, picking up a
little bit again. And at the top of
2025, dawned on me, I was like, you know
what? I had seen some stuff on LinkedIn,
had followed a couple people and I was
like, what if I instead of turning
Bofu.ai into a product, what if I turned
it into a consultancy? Like what if I
just did it like that? Done for you
workflows for companies, bottom of
funnel specific. And
>> it literally just kind of took off from
there, you know? So I, you know, it so
it's definitely trial and error, but
that taught me so much. And I think the
biggest lesson I came out of that with
was understanding the difference between
being a product and a tech- enabled
service. And I got those two mixed up
and confused. I was like pitching it as
a software when I was actually still a
service but I was a tech- enabled
service. I was putting more on the tech
than I was the actual strategy. So, I
kind of like flipped that on its head
and now I put more emphasis on the
process and the strategy than I do the
actual, hey, I have AI helping me do
this stuff in the back end, you know?
So, I think that was the biggest lesson
I pulled from that whole downturn of
2024, not being able to sell this was
positioning is everything. Like, you
have to watch how you position stuff cuz
just slight positioning can literally
turn the dial so much. Yeah,
>> exactly. and enable you to do a lot more
than that.
>> Of course, 100%. Yes.
>> Thank you so much for sharing that and I
just got goosebumps because it just
happened in a couple of years, right?
It's not like a long lost story that
that you know you'd had a ureka moment
and it just happened in a couple of
years. You have seen the change. You
evolved. You pivoted the way you should
based on market trends, based on the
feedback that you got. So I think it's
really inspiring that you actually did
that and all the best to you because it
looks exciting and if there's anything I
know who's the bofu queen everybody
saying it's you and it's true you know a
lot and not just saying it for the heck
of it but I truly believe that because
I've used the previous frameworks that
you have shared and it has worked. So
it's not just words, it's actually
practices that really worked out for
people like me like who were the
consumers of that content. So just keep
doing on what you're doing and it's
looking really good.
>> Thank you. Yeah, I I honestly it's just
my way of paying it forward cuz I thank
people as many chances as I can like of
like putting that attention on my
content and even caring about what I
have to say. So no, it's it's of course
like that's my way of paying it forward.
any way I can help somebody that's still
in house type of freelancer, whoever
that person is.
>> Yeah.
>> I want to I want to be able to help them
as in as many ways as I can. So, thank
you so much. Like that's literally what
I'm here to do. Yeah.
>> Sure. And I know uh in our last
conversation, you mentioned you really
want to give one aha moment for the
listeners. So, what's one mindset shift
or move our listeners can take to level
up their content starting this week?
>> Ooh, okay. to level up their content
style. Um,
is it content in general, like bofu,
like top of funnel? Like what's because
I want to make sure I give them good
advice. Like I don't want to just give
you terrible advice.
>> We can start with top off the funnel and
then we can focus more on woo. Yeah.
>> Okay. So, one content insight you can do
this week, stop making your top offunnel
content like very heavily
definitionbased. The moment somebody
enters your ecosystem, they should
understand what your status quo is on
the category. So when we think of top
offunnel content, you think of like what
is this or this statistics or topic
whatever immediately indoctrinate people
the moment they enter your ecosystem
from the top of the funnel and start
injecting more opinion into top of
funnel. Right? It's not just a what is
payroll, you know, what is what is
payroll management? It's how I feel
about payroll management, how payroll
management should be ran. Here's how
most people do it and here's why we
think that's wrong, you know? So, just
like indoctrinate. That's that's that's
what I would say you could do this week.
Like start indoctrinating.
>> Yeah.
>> From a top offunnel perspective. Yes.
Yes.
>> Perfect. Yeah. I think we all start a
top of the funnel with just the basic
definitions of what is this? But then
let's shift to the very important thing.
What about bofu?
>> Yes. Oh, this one is a tough one because
it's crazy. It's easier for me to give
top ofunnel advice. So, I would say if
you are having trouble Well, first of
all, here's what I'll say. Start making
your content more productled. Like if
you have product screenshots, include
them. Another thing I would say is like
start communicating with your teammates.
And I don't just mean people on the
content team. I mean product marketers,
some people from sales, you know what I
mean? cuz there are different elements
that you need from each team in order to
be able to create a good converting
bottom ofunnel piece, you know? So,
start reaching out to people even if
it's just like, "Hey, how can I help
you?" or "What did you learn today from
your sales calls?" People will
appreciate you even caring about what
they're doing. Um, but but start if you
can start developing a little bit of
crossf functional communication amongst
the teams because that's where the
alignment is. Like that's where the
hidden gems are in cross functional
communication. Unfortunately, most
companies are not crossunctional. And
again, like I said in the beginning,
that culture of crossunctional
communication works from the top down,
not the bottom up, you know. So, I would
just encourage people to just reach out
to, you know, reach out to people on
your team. Again, if it's somebody from
sales, say, hey, you know, like what are
the most common pain points you're
hearing? I want to like put that in the
content or say, you know, is there
anything you need from me? Because a lot
of the times I found with a lot of
companies, companies have taken my
bottom off ofunnel content and
repurposed it into one pages for the
sales team. Everything is connected
each other. You know what I mean? Some a
lead might come in or a prospect might
come in, they'll say, "Well, hey, I've
been looking at this other product. How
do you compare against them?" Again, if
you have a bottom of an article, you
versus this person, you grab that piece
and you send it over to sales so they
can send it to the prospect. You know
what I mean?
And that's why cross functional
communication is so important. Um just
reach out to somebody. Like that's my
advice. Reach out to somebody from
sales. You know it doesn't have to be
like you know super uptight or anything.
Just keep it really like relaxed and say
you what are like some of the pain
points you're hearing on the calls and
then take that insight and bake it into
the articles you're producing. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I think I hope people just don't
skip to this part because that was the
juiciest part of the entire podcast. But
I had a great time lash and thank you so
much for sharing a lot of the key
insights on wfu on tofu and AI content
strategy.
>> Thank you so much for having me on.
Really hope I was able to provide value
to somebody listening. Hopefully
somebody resonated with like my rants
that people like to listen to. So thank
you so much.
>> I'm sure there are at least there are
more than 10 people who would take it
seriously. That's good to know people
take me seriously cuz sometimes I
>> love about talking to Lashe is how she
takes something that often feels complex
and overwhelming and just simplifies it.
So whether it's using AI the smart way,
building high converting comparison
pages or shifting your mindset from
publishing to converting, this episode
was packed with real and actionable
insights. So thank you so much Lache for
your time today and sharing so many
golden nuggets here. Thank you so much
again for having me.
>> Absolutely. And if you're a marketer
sitting thinking our blog looks good but
it's not driving anything, now is the
time to get started. Lache, thank you
for not just sharing tactics, but giving
us the permission to expect more from
our content. If you enjoyed this
episode, send it to someone who's stuck
in tofu mode. And if you try out any of
Lach's tips, let us know how it goes.
Thanks for listening to Behind the Brief
and I'll see you in the next