so hello and today we will have our
customer appreciation event and while we
we're organizing this event we as also
last year we needed to find a speaker
for the event and you all know that one
of the main marketing platforms that we
use is LinkedIn and also our customers
are on LinkedIn so I said wouldn't it be
great to have someone educating our
customer telling them what is for them
on LinkedIn and how can they make the
best out of it so I was searching for
someone who is a let's say professional
uh on LinkedIn and fortunately I found
Richard who was so kind to say hey guy
David I'm going to join your event and
be one of your speakers today which is
my pleasure to introduce Richard to you
today and Richard may I ask if you would
just briefly introduce who you are and
what you doing of course yeah yeah my
name is Richard vlom I'm Dutch I'm
living in Spain uh I have a background
in sales and marketing uh and I started
a business just connecting back in 2009
MH uh which started as a social media
training and consultancy agency B2B but
we did all kind of platforms so we did
LinkedIn Facebook Twitter or now it's
called X yeah um and and that's actually
how I started in the business also uh
about giving training uh on LinkedIn
yeah yeah okay that's interesting so you
and your business as an entrepreneur
it's then more than 15 years now yeah
yeah at the end of this year I started I
think it was December 2009 so I have a
15 year anniversary at the end of this
year um one of one of the milestones in
our business was 2015 M where I decided
to focus 100% on LinkedIn Okay so until
then we did like cross cross social
media yeah and in 20 15 I thought no
it's it's better to be a specialist mm
and to go full 100% on LinkedIn than to
be a generalist um and and that was
actually one of the best choices I made
in the past okay in my entrepreneurial
Voyage all right okay I see yeah that's
interesting to know because as you said
there's other platforms and so
interesting to know what made you choose
why go for LinkedIn and I've already
asked so 15 years already roughly your
business and you explained why you went
for LinkedIn and after all these years
so 2015 so 8 to nine years now what
makes you still passionate about
LinkedIn so the reason why we chose
LinkedIn is there were basically two
reasons first of
all I think with the speed of all the
development it's impossible to be an
expert in all the social media platforms
I mean I knew something about Facebook
but it's impossible to know indepth
Facebook for recruitment Facebook for
marketing Facebook Facebook for I don't
know entrepreneurship and then you have
all these different
platforms um and the second reason is I
always have been a big fan of LinkedIn
MH uh I've started to use it in 2005 so
I was very early uh I saw it as my
living Rolex with all my contacts um and
I I spend a lot of my time in linked in
uh catching up with my network inviting
people so so it was more like it was
almost a for so was very easy and I saw
in the market that there were a lot of
B2B companies 8 n years ago exploring
LinkedIn thinking how can we use it so I
just jumped into this back then niche
market yeah of being a 100% dedicated
Linkin agency okay would you say if you
say niche market do you feel like it's
still in Niche or do you feel like it
has
become no it's not it's not a niche
anymore no no no no I I kept tracked in
Holland in the beginning of the year I I
noticed so I started in 2009 and there
were three people back in 2009 in
Holland that provided LinkedIn training
three so in 2015 when we went to
LinkedIn there were uh 2,000 people and
now only in Holland there are over
10,000 people providing LinkedIn
training just just in Holland really
yeah a lot of them they focus on
entrepreneurs so they teach people how
to make a profile or so it's it's like
what we say lower Market yeah but it's
not a niche and also even in in Germany
you had Crossing no exing that was very
strong at the beginning so I knew back
then in 2015 we didn't had a lot of
German clients or Austrian clients
because they were all like n sing but
I've seen also in Germany now that it
really took off and a lot of people we
actually have a lot of requests from
German companies now like okay our sales
team our Market team you know we need to
really boost LinkedIn so N I think
worldwide is really established now
which is interesting social media in
general and me personally also um I'm
kind of between the generations let's
say the older generation is like a
social media not for me and then the
younger generation they say like okay we
grew up with it right so uh nothing new
for us and we kind of have to moderate
for businesses especially also for let's
say the older generation so why do you
need social media for business right and
which you say apart from 2015 was there
any other specific event that made you
build your business around this platform
yeah yeah so before I had my own company
I was working as I have always been in
working in sales MH and uh my last two
years I was a sales and marketing
manager for an education company in
Holland so we provided trainings and I
was doing sales but we had 80 trainers
and I saw when I went with them to new
clients that they were very passionate
talking about their knowledge their
expertise yeah but I really hated it to
sell it and I still think and maybe
salespeople will not like me for seeing
this but I see a lot of sales people now
they don't like to sell MH but when they
know that the client is in need of what
they're offering they like to
really um engage with the client and
tell like how the solutions work yeah so
we don't like to sell but we like to
talk about our Solutions if we know the
client is receptive for it yeah and uh
back then I realized that LinkedIn is
actually an ideal platform to position
yourself towards your clients yeah so
instead of selling you're now going to
be bought by clients so they are going
to send you a message say hey I saw your
posst about your packaging method and we
are in need of that can we make an
appointment so you can flip the script
when you use LinkedIn very well and that
was actually when I thought like hey if
we're going to teach people how to do
that then we make sales a bit more
easier mhm which was a great explanation
why we are on link and that was the same
idea exactly exactly exactly yeah so
among all the other platforms you said
2015 was the way you chose uh LinkedIn
as your go-to platform um what makes it
for you different to the others and what
do you think what will it become or how
it will look like in the
future yeah that that's a that's a
question I could talk for like an hour
uh first of all what makes it different
it's it's funny because for me ledin is
not social media anymore mhm so for
example whenever we are in training with
salese and especially you mentioned the
let's say a bit older
Generation Um sometimes we get a
question yeah why why do I need to be on
LinkedIn because you know I have my golf
club I have my network and I don't do
social media the first thing I tell them
like that's good because it's not social
media it's it's your digital footprint I
mean if your sales people are going to
meet a new client probably your client
is going to Google the person who's
coming and the first link will will
probably be LinkedIn so I'm always
saying like Okay I myself I'm very
passive on Facebook MH I don't have
Instagram uh I can't remember my login
for X so a lot of people think because
I'm in the business that I'm a social
media I'm not I'm I'm very focused on
LinkedIn um and I really see it in this
way different compared to other social
medias as it's your digital footprint
whether you're going to apply for a new
job whether you are in sales but people
Googling your name will very soon find
your LinkedIn profile as the first link
the future I'm not very clear about it
um because especially people who have
been on LinkedIn for a longer time I
mean there's so we are over 1 billion
members since the covid pandemic a lot
of salespeople realize okay that's the
platform to go to sell my stuff MH so as
a result a lot of things are happening
there are shifting we see different type
of content MH we see more pitches sales
messages we see decision makers becoming
reluctant to respond okay if I sent
seven years ago a message to a a sales
director yeah and say hey I see what
you're doing let's have a discussion on
how lingin can help you they would
respond and they would say okay yeah now
I don't get a on this type of messages I
don't get a response anymore because
they get so many pictures and so many
people trying to sell yeah um so they
still have the mass I mean 1 billion
people 99.9% working population but I've
also seen that some people are getting
like less enthusiastic about the
platform because of the massive spam and
the massive messages they are getting so
um it has become a Microsoft company
okay yeah H Microsoft botling in in 2016
so they're going for the big bucks okay
but the risk is that if the average user
the non-paying user is leaving the
platform
mhm the recruiters will have a problem
the marketeers will have a problem and
the sales people will have a problem so
for me the future is about how do they
keep the average non-paying user active
on the platform if they can fix that
there's a very bright future but there's
also a risk that if they leave or become
less active that the whole value of the
platform will decrease so it's
interesting
yeah um I haven't thought about that
this way um and it absolutely makes
sense I also didn't know that LinkedIn
is a Microsoft yeah they bought it in
2016 for $26 billion so imagine oh yeah
we were in the wrong business yeah we
are definitely in the wrong business so
well that that's quite interesting let's
just say it keeps struggling or
struggles even more would you say that
there would be other Solutions other
alternatives to LinkedIn I think that's
that's their
um maybe that's their biggest luck mhm
because there is no alternative mhm I
mean uh you know you had Instagram then
came Snapchat a lot of user from
Instagram went to Snapchat and back and
you had AIS or Twitter now you have
threats but for lin I mean in a B2B
environment there's no alternative yeah
Google has tried it a few years ago I
think it was called Google Plus MH uh
didn't work many platforms have tried
but LinkedIn
reached uh the mass user I mean one
billion that is impossible for new
platform to generate those those members
that are willing to leave so much uh B2B
data about their work experience
education so I think for the upcoming
years there's no alternative mhm that's
the the unique point they have MH still
they need to keep the people satisfied
on the platform yeah yeah which will be
interesting to see um and I agree I
wouldn't know either who would you go to
if you won't go on LinkedIn no h that's
what I said you know in D region you had
a lot of people using sing next to
Linkin so you still had like sing if you
would do only business in Germany and
the LinkedIn for International Business
um you had those similar networks in
other countries M they were all
literally eaten by ledin yeah they're
not existing anymore so there's no
alternative okay well let's see from
your perspective what will be the
biggest challenges uh the biggest
challenge not specifically for LinkedIn
which we've talked about already but for
you for your business
to train educate people on how to use
LinkedIn yeah that's a that's a very
good question that's a question that
we're always trying to ask ourselves
because I think the biggest challenge
not only for us but for a lot of
companies is to make sure you stay ahead
of the of the big pack yeah to
differentiate yourself to position
yourself as as being unique to your
customers because like I told you if you
go on Google and you go like LinkedIn
training for sales you find hundreds
thousands of companies providing it so
why do they choose us I know why they
should choose us but to get that message
across I think that's that's one of the
biggest challenges M and I think the key
to
that are your clients MH I can I can
honestly say that we we don't have a
sales team we have trainers they all do
their own acquisition but last year for
example 85% of our new customers came
via existing customers mhm those are our
biggest salese yeah um because they are
nonrelated to us they're very happy
satisfied with the results they can tell
other clients this was a challenge M
this is what we did MH and they sell us
much more easier than I can do or any of
my trainers can do so how to
differentiate yourself is one of the
biggest challenge how to stay ahead also
in terms of knowledge so we invest a lot
in okay how do we get all the latest
features the latest knowledge and how do
we uh transform that into trainable
tactics trainable strategies but also to
make that visible to the to the market
that that's a big a big challenge mhm so
referral word of mouse is very important
for you yes definitely okay where do you
see
opportunities for your
business and where do you see risks in
the next
years um opportunities and risk well I
think they're all around us but um
opportunities is we're trying
to not position ourself anymore as a
LinkedIn training agency but we're
trying to position ourself as a digital
lead generation agency so that means
that LinkedIn now is the main
platform but it would also mean that if
LinkedIn for some reason would not exist
anymore in two years our business model
would have like it would have been gone
yeah so what we want to do is we want to
teach our clients
more how do they Embrace digital tools
digital platforms to interact with
potential customers to do lead
generation and how do they train
themselves in adapting their strategy
into upcoming opportunities new
platforms new tools MH because
especially the world of B2B sales has
changed a lot I mean we have a lot of
now a lot of sales people use zoom or
teams to do their intake with clients we
have a lot of sales intelligence we have
ai um so that that's massive opportunity
for us
it also allows us to become less
dependent on one platform LinkedIn and
it also allows us to have I think even a
stronger relationship with our clients
because then you really position
yourself as um a counterart for
everything that has to do with modern
lead generation if you talk about
risk obviously if something happens with
LinkedIn and I don't think they will
stop but I've also seen LinkedIn is now
providing training they never did that
they never did that they started like at
the beginning of this year they started
with sales navigator to have some people
of themselves train their customers we
also do sales Navigator trainings but we
have now seen that some of our clients
say no we bought sales Navigator and
Linkedin is going to give us a training
um so so so those kind of things are
also risk and then you
have saturation of the market seven
eight years ago if I would have an
intake with a client I would ask like
did you ever had LinkedIn train they
would say no mhm now if even companies
that come to us and say we want to have
a LinkedIn training and I ask which
training do you had they always say like
no we had three years ago we had this
training or two years ago we had sales
Navigator training so there's also a
risk that the mark the market becomes
saturated or that people lose faith in
training because a lot of clients that
come to us they had training they were
not satisfied yeah and then I need to
tell them well if you pay me this amount
we do a training they but it didn't work
the first time so why will it work so
again we need to position ourselves as
being different mhm yeah from your
perspective there
is there is some maybe more increasing
numbers of content
creators still there's
people
um not engaged not creating content for
a different reason what have you
experienced from your perspective what
is keeping people away using LinkedIn
for their business that's an easy
question because I have some slides
today I'm going to share with the
audience about that so first of all some
people still see LinkedIn as a job
platform so some people say why would I
post something why would to update me
LinkedIn because I already have a job
okay and there is a misconception that
LinkedIn is a job platform because it
was never built as a job platform it was
built as a platform I know their mission
statement is to make people more
successful and productive by making them
Network
globally when the critical mass I'm
talking about 2010 2011 came to LinkedIn
recruiters then realized hey if those
people are there giving us information
about our education were it's a good
place to hunt and that was also the
moment that LinkedIn was like going full
in with recruitment
Solutions the big population the big
Mass came two years after that in
Holland it was 2012 and Germany it was
2014 so the people that jumped on the
platform they always thought that ledin
was a job platform because that was like
initiated in 0 yeah um so so that's one
reason people still think okay if I do
something LinkedIn my network might
think that I need a job uh second it's
uh people saying like I don't have time
to publish on LinkedIn you mentioned we
have more content creators it's still
1.1% that publish once a week I mean
that's insane that means that 99% of all
the members are not publishing one post
a week it's insane yeah um so people say
I don't have the time because I have a
job to do for me time is priority if
you're not convinced that Linkin is
going to help you in your business
you're not going to spend time obviously
um and then there's also a fact that
people still don't feel comfortable I
mean it's online so what if I make a
mistake what if I do something and it
creates uh negative responses or simply
they don't know how to write they're not
writers you know or they they don't know
how to create a video or so it's also um
uh the unknown I think that's that's
those are some reasons why people are
not using LinkedIn or not publishing a
LinkedIn at the moment which makes me
think of back of our beginnings here and
I mean we had the same
thoughts um the thing is what I've
realized and you are along your journey
you've realized it way sooner that if
you don't start at some stage you will
not learn all those things yes it takes
a lot of time at the very beginning but
you will learn to become more productive
more efficient and at some stage you
said like oh wow one post takes me in
hours per week now of a sudden you do
like three or four posts in an hour a
week so um you need to start in order to
become better at it with everything in
life I I I I totally agree with that I
think the worst thing you can do is try
to write the perfect post when you start
because you will keep looking at your
screen you will keep deleting your post
you will not in and um you you really
need to learn and the best feedback you
get you get from your audience if people
don't respond well apparently there's no
much value if people respond in a
positive way you know that hey my
network is is engaging and also the
learning curve I mean how do you expect
yourself to write better post if you're
not writing exactly yes uh and for me
it's the same I mean I now write a post
in I think less than five minutes M
writing I'm not talking about a design
or anything it used to take me half an
hour or maybe an hour um so you train
yourself yeah and based on the feedback
from your audience your network you also
are going to
optimize the type of post the type of
messages uh so I think U it's an
excellent advice to start uh yes you're
going to fail yes you're going to do
things that you might regret but in the
end it will make you learn how to
leverage this platform for yourself mhm
and while you say that one thing also so
that I have discovered is if you're
trying to create content you think about
okay what actually what is the
challenges what are my customer thinking
about and as soon as you start to create
content it is exactly what you say your
customers actually tell you in the
comments the way they engaged what they
think about or not you realize okay
that's a Hot Topic I actually haven't
thought about it so far but now I see
that okay that's something important
let's tap into that a bit deeper and
understand what is actually going on and
now a whole world of content suddenly
opens for you right it's true and it's
funny because um when sales people tell
me I don't know what to write about M I
always say like okay imagine you're
going to watch a football game of your
son and you bump into a person you've
never met another parent and you you
suddenly realize that he works at a
potential client M I said and he ask you
a question you're not going to say ah no
I don't know what to say you you have
your knowledge you know what other
clients are looking you know their
challenges so if you take that knowledge
that you use in your intakes with
clients in your private life and just
put them on paper you already have a
post exactly it's it's that easy but
people they just go blank when they need
to write it online it's like like U well
it's it's something that you need to
overcome and the only way to do that is
to go for it yes yes hard as it sounds
right it's it's also something cultural
yeah because we work a lot
internationally mhm and it's it's also
in Germany DH region
also uh France some countries it's not
in the culture to be as open online as
much I mean when we train Americans or
English or Australians completely
different cultures you know you don't
need to ask them like uh or or they
don't have the thing that they don't
know how to write most of the time I
need to tell them maybe that's better
not to write you know because they throw
everything online but but there are
cultures yeah where we have been thought
to be more prudent to be more like avoid
risks and that might also be an
obstruction in your learning cve yeah
that's a very very interesting topic and
I would agree yeah yeah it is if we take
a look at the other platforms um maybe
not so much about business like more
like the classical social media
platforms is there something you think
we could see and learn from these
platforms as LinkedIn users content
creators I think every platform has his
own users and its own Dynamics what I
find interesting for example is the way
how people position themselves for
example on Instagram is much more open
much more informal than we are used to
on link mhm yes funny enough I have some
people in my network on LinkedIn that
use the Instagram Style video on
LinkedIn and it's a huge success okay um
I think just because we are not used to
see that content on LinkedIn people jump
on that and say hey this is a nice video
um so I think the interesting point is
to see what are the Dynamics of each
platform also a good thing is that all
these platforms try to come up with new
features the first yeah I mean we had
Instagram stories LinkedIn jumped to
Instagram to LinkedIn stories which
wasn't a big success they killed it um
but it's it's for me it's interesting
and that's one of the main reasons why I
still follow some of the other social
platforms is to see what kind of
features are they bringing to their
platforms yeah what is the purpose of
the feature and how can we on LinkedIn
learn from that yeah yeah and we need
those people like you who are able to
kind kind of see what other platforms do
and kind of let's say at least show us
or give us an idea of how we can
actually use that on LinkedIn right yeah
and for me because I'm not on the
platforms myself or I'm very dormant on
the platform so what I have I have in my
LinkedIn Network I have a few Tik Tok
creators that are also on LinkedIn I
have a few Instagram uh experts because
even on LinkedIn they share the newest
Instagram news they share the newest Tik
Tok news so just by following them I
stay a bit like on top of the knowledge
and on top of the new features and I I
think that's also especially if you're
in marketing yeah I think that's really
good tactic to follow experts from all
the different platforms so you see okay
what are the platforms doing at the
moment mhm yeah very interesting a few
weeks ago maybe a few months um you
recently announced software as a service
tool for businesses to simplified get
more out of LinkedIn with their team y
yeah so uh yeah it's called narfi we are
about to launch it in the Nordic okay um
I'm one of the
co-founders uh I cund it with Norwegian
people and it's a tool that helps
actually what we discussed teams
individuals to produce content more
easily on LinkedIn M so you probably
know there are a lot of tools that you
can use for LinkedIn you have the tools
that provide you with analytics you have
the tools especially now with AI that
you can write posts
engagement but um what we are doing with
this tool is um you can you can create a
post okay so you can write a draft for
example and you can um use AI to
optimize it we have even implemented the
algorithm research that I always do so
you can optimize it for LinkedIn H you
can draft it so you can create a library
of posts you have drafted to use in a
later stage um but the most important
thing is that there is a collaboration
inside so for example imagine marketing
they know how to publish on LinkedIn and
they want to activate eight people yeah
and the eight people are like having
difficulties yeah like first of all
marketing can write a post share it with
the eight people and the eight people
can have a look they can change it and
they can publish it so like a ghost
writing yeah but also in the platform if
I'm one of the eight people I can write
a post and then ask for feedback from
marketing so I said okay I've read my
own post but please have a look before I
publish it m um so marke have a look at
it they can say great or they can make
some suggestions but they can also share
it with your other seven colleagues so
now your post is being rehar or being
posted by the other colleagues as well
um we also have an academy in the tool M
so that means that if you don't know how
to publish you just go to the academy
you click on the how to publish a post
and you get like an instruction on how
to do it not the tool but how to do it
on LinkedIn so it's a tool that uh um
enables employee advocacy makes your
employees more active on LinkedIn shares
content in a good way but also generates
a lot of IDs uh there is an ID Library
so if you say for example I'm working in
logistics or I'm working in packaging
this is my target audience then based on
AI the tool comes with some suggestions
okay maybe you can write a post on the
trends in packaging maybe you can write
a post about sustainability and it even
gives you like drafts so that's the tool
okay which in some way also refers to
what we have talked about already uh
what keeps people from engaging using
creating content and this tool at least
in you within your team would help them
to be a bit more engaged right yeah so
what it does in the beginning it gives
them like the safety net that you don't
need to publish without marketing hav't
seen it or without anyone giving you
feedback so you have the safety net of
your colleagues having a look um it
makes people create content in less time
I think that's one of the most important
things because time is our most
important asset everybody has to less
time and we need to do a lot of things
so if we can help you to create a new
post from scratch in five minutes as an
unexperienced content creator instead of
half an hour we save you time yeah uh
and then we have the the learning
abilities with the academy uh with all
the uh the tips we giving with the
inspiration we give in the tools so I
think it's um well we have a lot of
companies now testing it and the results
are are very very positive okay you'll
keep me updated yeah I
will apart from all the specific topics
about LinkedIn is there anything you
have in mind a big goal five years from
now
yeah um that has nothing to do with
LinkedIn or or with
um the current things I'm doing my my
big goal is to be able to do in five
years from now whatever I want to do MH
whenever I want to do it wherever I want
to do it m so if I want to be on Bali
doing things via my laptop or I want to
do scuba diving
inali that's in 5 years I mean I'm 47
now am I lying no 47 so in 5 years I
want to reach that point where I feel
free yeah to go where I want whenever I
want but also to to participate in
projects and work that I want um so
that's that has always been the goal
it's some people it's not Financial
Independence it's not it's more let's
call it emotional Independence that you
feel that you're free to do wherever you
want to go and and and whatever you do I
think that's that's for me that's one of
my biggest goals okay money helps with
that but it's not it's not
essential and I think it's that's quite
I mean the essential idea of being an
entrepreneur to at some stage be a bit
more independent abundant yes and and
let's be honest I see also on ledin I
see so many um how do they call digital
Nomads now MH uh and I know when I have
this discussion with my father who is
from a completely different generation
they almost look at them like they're
betraying us like they're not working MH
but I think the way how people approach
work especially the younger generation
has shifted completely yeah I also think
it's more they are more um it's more
healthy yeah because we are used to work
40 hours we used to like uh you know be
very loyal to whatever is they're doing
but they are always I think they're
almost every week every month asking
themselves they did what I want to do
and if not they make a change and I
think the ability to ask you that
question to make changes I think that's
something that we can learn from the
younger generation yes yes um and I love
to see the stories of young people that
are now on Bali next week in Australia
and you know as long as they make
themselves useful they have a job they
support or us I who are we to judge so
yeah I think that that's also
globalization digitalization of of work
it comes with a lot of opportunities
yeah I agree I mean we often forget that
the idea was that
we work to live and not live to work
exactly I use I use that a lot I use
that a lot I use a lot we we we we we
work to live and we do not live to work
no that's that's perfect I think we
forgot that along the way yeah
Richard um along all these years can you
think of something that you
would call your let's say biggest
mistake as an
entrepreneur oh I've made quite a few
mistakes um I and I think it's good
because without mistakes you don't learn
um I've come to the conclusion that um
especially in the training business
it's it's if you don't train you don't
earn money I mean it's not scalable MH
so I think one of the you could call a
mistake or the biggest learning is that
I'm now
looking what are opportunities to scale
your business yeah if you're in a
training business you have several
options like you can hire trainers go
big uh but what happens if you don't get
enough clients I mean I did it in the
past we had a company where we had 12
employees the crisis
came um and and we needed to pay all the
the salaries and we had no clients so I
don't want to go back there so now
that's one of the reasons why you
mentioned the SAS tool M that I'm
looking into scalable products yes so
this could be the SAS tool this could be
online courses I mean you create online
courses and you can sell them it's it's
scalable MH um but not being
open uh or not being aware that I need
to find an answer to how to scale your
business I think that's one of the
biggest mistakes I've made and I'm
catching up on that yeah we are all
guilty of that yeah yeah yeah well so
now I if I have now a new business idea
the first thing I do I reverse the
script and I go like how would it be
scalable because if if you think about
something that is not scalable yes it's
a noo yes yes so that's that's the big
learning yes yes
and we've been through some questions
already could you think of anything that
you thought okay if I having an
interview with David today I would love
him to ask me question ABC is there a
question that I haven't asked but you
would have loved me to ask
you
uh there are several you could ask for
example are any things you don't like
about
LinkedIn you could also ask if Linkin
was not there what would you have done
instead ah that would have been an
interesting one
yes so what what would have what would
have happened if LinkedIn it's very
funny because often I I I have my
discussions um and I say like okay if I
could
do my education again I start like being
16 17 Again there were not a lot of
things I would do differently but I
studied it's a funny story I studied
economics yeah because my two best
friends where I also played football
with they were going to study economics
and I would I in that moment I wanted to
study uh Geographics which was in
Amsterdam I was 18 I didn't see my
myself on on on being in Amsterdam alone
so I just followed them and did
economics and from economics I did sales
and from sales I did this yes if I could
back if I could go back to 178 years I
would become a vet
Veterinary okay yeah that's that's like
that's a thing that I know now but I
didn't know when I was 17 18 because I
like I like to be surrounded by animals
I like to to help animals so so it's a
completely different thing would you
would you love to turn back time no no
no I don't believe in turning back time
because we are where we are where we
need to be because of our choices okay
um but it's still like uh you know I I
cannot see a sick animal and I need to
rescue it okay I'm very bad at it but I
I I I try it okay okay okay oh very
interesting very
interesting as an entrepreneur so last
question could you think of something or
let's say is there something if you go
to bed wake up during the day that
really concerns
you it's not only my concern I see it
with a lot of entrepreneurs because I'm
surrounded with a lot of entrepreneurs
and I
think
the life work balance is something that
is really underestimated by a lot of
people when they think about going into
entrepreneurship and I'm saying again
life work balance and not work life
balance life comes first then work but
I've struggled with that myself because
you know it's very funny you become an
entrepreneur and if if things go great
you want to do more because you're
earning money you're getting popular so
you want to do more more more more so
you you lose your balance yes if things
are not going great the solution is
doing more because it's not going great
so I need to do more so I find a lot of
entrepreneurs having difficulties with
their life work balance because you're
never in a state where you can say it's
going steady and I'm satisfied if it go
steady we want to scale yes if it goes
bad we need to do better no I mean I've
dealt with it in the past I'm trying to
find the balance but I think a lot of
people um
are um
maybe believing too much the story that
if you're an entrepreneur it it only
comes with good things you know you can
work whenever you want you can have free
whenever you want you can earn a lot of
money no it's not like that it's it's I
I think a lot of entrepreneurs excuse me
are even working harder than they did
when they were just working as an
employee because you need to do
everything yourself yes so and I think
this is for a lot of people also people
who are um working at companies your
your your life work balance is something
that you should be very careful about MH
I think that was a great insight for for
those of you who are inter entrepreneurs
or consider being one um so everything
comes with his ups and downs of course
yeah and so this is it for today Richard
it was a pleasure having this interview
with you and I hope you enjoyed it as
much as we did talk soon