Hello, LinkedIn makers and movers. Our
guest today has been a welcome addition
to my feed over the past year. She
landed on my radar, I think in the
summer of 2024, popping up on LinkedIn
with spicy takes on B2B marketing,
especially around landing page
conversion. Ladies and gentlemen, I'm
talking about none other than Taz Bober,
the founder of Score Lab. But before I
pass her the mic, let's dig into her
background a little bit. She got her
start in journalism and media. She wrote
for an online magazine in Thailand and
then produced content for a news channel
in Iowa. Big world of a difference.
While at the news channel, she pivoted
into digital marketing, creating digital
products for advertisers, diving deep
into measurement analytics. She then
pivoted into B2B, starting with Mercer,
a massive HR services firm where she
managed over 400 client websites. From
there she bumped in into SAS leading
digital marketing for brands like Plex
in the manufacturing vertical, Telium
and customer data where she doubled down
on conversion strategy and about two
years ago she went out on her own and at
first she was doing all sorts of digital
marketing work but narrowed down and
recently rebranded to the Scroll Lab and
focuses exclusively on helping SAS
brands improving landing page
conversion. And around that same time,
she also went from sporadic LinkedIn
posting to about almost daily presence
and seems like she never looked back.
Her posts are informal. They're witty.
They're bold. They focus on obviously
B2B marketing, but and landing pages and
the occasional dash of personal life,
especially parenting, which I appreciate
going through some stuff. And it's
working. Her content gets really great
engagement. She's approaching 20,000
followers and her business is thriving.
One last thing, she recently launched a
podcast called Notorious B2B with Tim
Davidson of LinkedIn Fruit Cut and Fame.
Part part Saturday live, part TMZ, but
for B2B. And it's been a hit on the
feed. I enjoy it myself. If all of that
is not the definition of LinkedIn
famous, I don't know what is. So, let's
give a big LinkedIn famous welcome to
Taz Bober.
[Music]
Welcome to the LinkedIn Famous podcast.
The show where we get real about what it
takes to build a personal brand on
LinkedIn that gets real business
results. We're talking about driving
revenue from a personal LinkedIn profile
by sharing real and authentic stories
and points of view. I am Brad Zoic, your
host and the founder of Spectrimer, a
personal brand consultancy that helps
founders and executives get LinkedIn
famous. Join me for unfiltered
conversations from the trenches of
LinkedIn. We'll meet CEOs, go to market
executives, subject matter experts, and
company employees with blockbuster
LinkedIn results. We'll unpack strategy
and leave you with tactical advice to
grow your personal brand and demand for
your company's products and services.
All right, LinkedIn hustlers, it's time
to level up.
[Music]
Yay. Should we do an applause? That was
very good. I love when I get on a
podcast and they do the intro for me
because you like to hear what someone
else's perception is or what they come
up with based on what they find out on
the internet, you know, about you.
You're like, "Oh, oh god, what they what
are they going to bring back?" Like a
2009 Facebook memory. Like, please don't
talk about the outcome I posted with my
college friends. But thank you for that.
That was great. I love that. It was
great. Well, thank you. A lot of people
have podcasts, you have to do the
research on the person before they come
on and then ask them like, "Tell me
about yourself. What's the point? You
already just spent like half an hour
like stalking them on LinkedIn."
That's right. Is there anything about
your background that you want to double
click on? Um, no. I think the one piece
was I also was the first time I was head
of digital was actually for the economic
development organization for the state
of Ohio which was insane because our
targets were like trying to get Intel to
come set up shop in Ohio in Columbus,
Ohio or Facebook and all these big
companies to come here and set up either
headquarters or you know branches here
and so if you think about the sales
cycle there they could be years long
because you're trying to get them to
come in here. You're trying to help them
find like the right site, building out
places, promising jobs. So, that was
probably the most impactful, but it just
you'd want to talk about long B2B sales
cycles. That's it's probably still some
work I did there 5 years ago is probably
still working now, making its way to
closed one deal. Yeah. So, government's
a notoriously long worse than enterprise
sales cycle. Yeah. So, tell us something
about yourself that the audience
couldn't learn about you from your
LinkedIn presence.
Oo. Oh my gosh, there's so much. I'm
like, where do I even start? Okay, I've
lived in like seven cities across three
countries. I'm actually half and half
myself, a mut. I'm half Indian, half
Thai. Lived in both countries. Went to
school in Thailand. Yeah, in Thailand
begrudgingly, hence where I started my
kind of career. I was too young. I
graduated from high school at 16. My
mom's like, I'm not sending my
16-year-old daughter to the US by
herself. That would be a shark attack.
Um, you know, finally moved here, worked
for the WHO NBC TV station out in Iowa,
which was great. Was an AE for three
years. So, I actually did sales for
three years. Yeah, I was hardest job
ever. So, I was like, well, I need to go
back to marketing. This is way too hard.
Love that. And um what else would you
not know about me? Oh, I have been
recently I've only ever brought it up
once, but um sometimes when people are
like, "What do you want to plug?" You
know, and I'm like, "I have a Spotify
playlist of songs that I've been
collecting since 2014. You can like live
my life alongside me from 2014. If you
like a lot of ratchet hip hop, give that
playlist a listen while you're working
out or hanging out. And yeah, it's just
tas.
We will link that in the show notes.
I do ask people what they want to plug
at the end. You can I have other stuff
to plug too, but this is like my new
thing to plug. Awesome. So, let's cut
into your LinkedIn journey. And you
started posting around the time you went
out on your own. What was the story
behind that? Yeah. journey before that
May or April 2023. You posted every once
in a while, maybe once a month, maybe
three month gap. And what were some of
the things going through your head at
that time? LinkedIn was not on my radar
whatsoever. And the backstory is I was
working inhouse, very busy, 50, 60 hours
a week. I have two kids and worked at a
startup, head of digital and website
there. Very busy. no time for anything
else, not even myself, let alone posting
on any platform. But then I crashed and
burned hard. I was very burnt out. And
at that point decided I need to do some
healing for myself, which meant also
just taking breaks. So I'm like, what is
a creative project that I can get into?
And that's when my daughter kind of
entered the picture where, you know,
she's a very temperamentally sensitive
child. And I'm like, there's nothing
medically wrong with her, but I wish
that I had a resource as a parent of a
sensitive child of like how to handle a
lot of the crying and, you know, the
tantrums and things like that that are
not medically indu like she doesn't have
anything wrong with her medically. She
is just a sensitive child. And small
things like tags on her clothes would
bother her, but she could not
communicate that. You're not going to
find that in a kids book, right? It's
like, what's bothering my kids? Like, is
she fed? Is she dry? Like, yeah, she's
all of those things. What else could it
be? And so, I was like, okay, maybe I
should do this. So, I planned out this
entire podcast. I had 70 topics that I
wanted to cover. The first two episodes
were written. I had the intro script. I
had the thumbnail made. every everything
was done. I left the marketing part to
the end because I'm like, how hard could
it be? It's I'm a career marketer. Like,
how hard could it be to market a
podcast? Whatever. Turns out it's very
hard. So, I ended up looking it up and
it said, well, a podcast is a little bit
different from other marketing because
it is very audience-based and you know,
you don't just like show up. You have to
go and kind of create an audience
elsewhere and then bring them over. So,
like a house party, they're not going to
just show up to the creepy lady's house
uh that they don't know. You kind of got
to go mingle, make a name for yourself,
have people like and trust you, and then
come over. I was like, "Okay, that makes
sense." So, they said, "Well, one of the
best ways to do this is to start posting
organically." And I went to Twitter and
I had like one and a half followers. So,
I was like, "I'm not going to do that."
I went to LinkedIn and I had 1,200
connections and I was like, "This is
great." But it would be weird if I came
out the gate just talking about par
parenting stuff. My boss is going to be
like, "Are you what is going on? Are you
okay?" So, I just started posting kind
of self-development stuff. And so, the
first one I did was like how I changed
my life in a single quarter. And I had
done all of these things kind of helping
with the burnout. So, I was reading
books. I was waking up at 5:00 a.m. I
was working out. Like all of these
different things. And it got like a
hundred likes my first post. I was like,
but it's all people who know me and I
was sharing something a little bit
personal about my life. And that
dopamine hit happened. And I was like,
"Ooh." So then I just it was more
experimental where I was trying to learn
the platform rather than like really
focus on what the theme or the content
was. I was just trying to understand can
I do this, can I build this? And I was
going through the steps and using myself
as a guinea pig. And then I went to
YouTube and I was trying to search like
how to write on LinkedIn and like how to
grow followers and like all of this
stuff. And then that's when I found like
Nicholas Cage, Dicky Bush, and their
interview with Justin Welsh. So like all
these big dogs, right? And I had no idea
who they are. Like no idea. Listen to
his interview and I'm like, "Oh, th this
is like some hardcore stuff." Like this
is people do this stuff all the time. So
I kind of started to learn how to write
on LinkedIn. And I even took the ship 30
for30 like course. Yeah, I did. Nicholas
Cole, not Nicholas. Sorry, not Nicholas.
I'm so sorry. Nicholas Cage.
Nicholas Cole. Yeah, Nicholas Cole.
Dicky Bush. Listen to their podcast for
a little bit. Obviously Justin Walsh is
like the automatic person who comes into
the picture. So kind of like link
listened to the LinkedIn Bros. They had
a lot of like cool free resources on
YouTube and stuff. And then I actually
ended up taking their cohort and met
some cool people there. So just learning
to write for the platform because I'm a
digital marketer and website marketer by
trade. So for me it was just this is how
I would learn a new channel. That's just
how I would go when I was trying to
learn paid. That's what I did. When I
was trying to learn about websites,
that's what I did. So I just approached
it scientifically and strategically that
way. Learned to write and started to
like experiment with hooks and things
like that. And so I was I would post and
things were fine. Everything was good.
But then I slowly started like expanding
and meeting people too. People DMing me
saying they like my stuff and whatever.
And all this time I'm working inhouse.
And so I don't think my company really
liked it that I was doing it even though
I wasn't saying anything crazy or
whatever. But I happen to start meeting
people through the platform and just
having a few networking calls a week.
And so it just really started as a slow
burn. no intention of doing anything
other than it being a creative exercise.
So that's kind of how it started.
Interesting. And you were just having
fun, you know, getting the ideas out of
your head. Was there any challenging
aspects to that? Did it click right away
or things you had to work through?
Well, the biggest obstacle being I don't
know how happy my company was that I was
posting. And I wasn't even saying
anything bad, but I I perhaps I wasn't
doing the traditional like I'm just
going to make my profile a walking
billboard for my company and you know
their latest event or their latest
whatever which is what I was doing
before that and then not getting much
feedback because that's literally what
everybody who does not post on LinkedIn
does is just like post company updates
and you know kind of lick the boots of
whoever you are whoever you're working
for at the time. It was just not
something I thought of really. I
remember when one of my article or one
of my posts got picked up by LinkedIn
news and got circulated and our head of
PR in the team meeting. We always did
this like shoutouts segment in our team
meetings. So there's 30 of us on here.
We get to the shout out segment and the
head of PR goes, "Shout out to Tass for
her LinkedIn post getting picked up by
LinkedIn news and they're circulating it
like this is so great for us and like
obviously she works here and my tagline
at the time also said you know director
of digital and web at Telium and started
circulating this and she was like this
is going to be great for the company and
everybody was like yeah you know
clapping and stuff and my bosses were
And and that was the first time I
realized, oh, they may not like this,
but at the same time, there was so much
I was having fun and a lot of that
healing was happening. I wasn't doing it
during work hours. I was very respectful
of the boundaries, but now I wasn't
giving my afterwork hours to my job
either. And I don't know if that also
made it kind of tricky for them. It's
like, oh, she's not going above and
beyond anymore, whatever that is. And
so, um, so yeah, that that was kind of
like the first obstacle I ran into. Mhm.
But then as I started expanding my
network, started writing about stuff,
uh, people started reaching out to me
going, dude, you have all this marketing
experience. Why aren't you talking about
marketing? God, I'm so burnt out. But
then I was like, okay, I'm going to
experiment. So, I started sharing more
digital and website stuff, things that I
was seeing, experiencing. And that's
when the first trajectory of growth
started happening because they were like
oh here's this expert on digital and
website sharing her knowledge like it's
going good and the epiphany for me
happened where I was like oh people can
actually monetize things on LinkedIn had
no idea was companies were starting to
reach out to me for jobs and reaching
out to me for consulting work and I was
like oh I didn't even know this was a
thing and I'm like no I have a full-time
job I'm good but I'll keep this in mind
for the future and And then what ended
up happening was my company wasn't doing
very well. They got rid of a lot of
mid-level management people. It was
probably a good strategic move for them.
They didn't like I was posting. So they
were like, "Okay, we'll just add task to
the list. Cool. Whatever." So July 2023
that happened. And at that point, I'd
only been posting since March 2023. So
March, April, May, June, July. So like
in 5 months, a lot was happening. Like
I'd met tons of people. I'd had
companies reach out to me for stuff. And
I was I felt like okay if I do go
through a layoff like I feel like I have
some options. So it didn't feel
terrible. So when it did happen I took a
week off and then the following week was
like LLC was created everything was done
and I just said hey I'm going out on my
own. I'm offering like digital and
website consulting like it's on. But it
was so much easier then to talk about
the things that I wanted to talk about
and be very open because I wasn't
handcuffed anymore. And that's then the
second wave of like kind of growth that
happened and the again the unintentional
I guess discovery that I can be a little
unhinged on LinkedIn but now that has
become my entire brand as like the funny
hilarious
purple landing page lady on LinkedIn.
Yeah. I wanted to talk about that and
maybe broadly or almost the unhinging of
LinkedIn because something's happening
here, right? I'm curious what you see is
going on because lately Yeah. what kind
of cuts through the feed is is kooky,
you know, and it's either highly
controversial or like off-the-wall.
What's your take on why that's
happening?
It's funny because I've seen so many
opinions on this. So I'm like, is this
my opinion anymore or is it just like,
you know, a culmination of all the
opinions that I've seen. There's a part
of me that's like, you do you, bro. You
know, if you if this is your thing,
that's fine. I think ultimately it it
depends on what your goals are. Could I
post oneliners and meme content every
day? Absolutely.
But one, I'm also running a business and
so that that is something I have to
consider is I'm more in the genre of
like edutainment. So I would rather give
you something tactical and be funny a
little bit in there or with Notorious
B2B which is purely a fun project. I'll
post about that like once a week or
maybe twice. But then I also want to be
able to provide someone value by giving
them like landing page advice or
marketing advice and stuff like that.
for the people who are like posting meme
content every day or you know the tweet
style content that's becoming a big
thing on LinkedIn now. It's also called
weird LinkedIn. Shout out to Nick Power
who's like taken the feed by storm.
Sometimes you have to ask yourself like
okay if your end game is just I want to
I have a job, I have financial means.
I'm just here to like mess around, have
fun, meet people, build a network, that
kind of stuff, cool. Totally your
prerogative. But if you have this other
thing where it's like, okay, it's my
livelihood. Can I envision a brand
partnering with me for what? For me to
put out a tweet? Can I envision a
company buying from me? What are they
buying? Cuz I don't really share a lot
of marketing advice necessarily or
whatever that whatever your expertise
is. you're not sharing a lot of that,
but people like you. Is that enough to
like monetize it? Not that I'm there to
I mean, I say a lot of unhinged stuff
and I'm like, well, people either like
me or they don't like me. So, I think
ultimately that's the question to ask.
So, if you're just there, you have a
job, you're just having fun, whatever.
Cool. I'd mess around all day long if
that was the case, too. But I try to do
a good healthy mix of what that is.
Ultimately, I would like to just be like
talent
like me. I mean, I worked in media for
like, you know, the first half of my
career. And so, it's like I wouldn't
mind just being talent. I can do it. I
like it. I like talking on podcasts. I
like creating content. I like working
with brands. So, if that's where it
goes, cool. But I'm also really good at
landing pages. So, if you want to hire
me for that, you can do that, too. I
like that approach. Yeah. It just has to
be like something that's a little more
natural to you. You know, some people
are just really kooky and maybe they are
like really nerdy. They're like into
Pokemon and that becomes like part of
your persona is that you're just this
person that talks about that. For me, I
love rap music and so like I make a lot
of weird Kendrick Lamar references in my
posts and you kind of either get it or
you don't get it or and I like to troll
people in the comment section and not
always leave insightful comments because
I'm like people know I'm not just a
complete
bozo. Like they go to my posts and I
share a lot of I call it the LinkedIn
mullet where it's like it's all business
in my posts mostly and then it's party
in the back with the comments. That's
where I have fun. I like that mullet.
Yeah, I'm searching for my LinkedIn
mullet. There you go. How do you
approach your content today? Do you have
any sort of system in place or how do
you keep the train on the track? I will
say a lot of people like once you start
it, it's not exactly something. I mean,
especially if you're trying to grow a
business. Yeah. You know, I'm just going
to take a month off and come back and
Yeah. Yeah. Or a week even. The real
answer is that I don't actually have a
full-blown system. Sometimes it is a
thing where it's I have two young kids,
okay? Almost six and and almost three.
And the reality is it's busy in my
household. I only work 3 days a week.
And what I mean by that is I have child
care 3 days a week. So I have to shove
all my meetings, all my podcasts, my
content creation if I don't want to do
it in the evenings, all of those things
within this 3-day period along with
client delivery, client call, all of
those things, right? Guess what gets put
on the back burner? It's the stuff that
like I have to work on for myself, for
my business. I will always prioritize
meeting with other people, my clients,
that kind of stuff. So, the honest truth
is it's a good week when I have two
posts scheduled in advance or even have
something like I don't have something
for tomorrow right now. We'll see. I'm
going to edit one for a client. Maybe
that one will go tomorrow. I don't know.
We'll see. It just really depends on my
schedule. I typically aim for like five
times a week and I try to come up with a
system. So I use like a little like
backstage thing that I have in KOD where
I try to plan my content. And so this
backstage thing I have like a calendar
basically and I get to look at it and
I'm like okay can I plan out my weeks
because this is my ideal state. And so
at this stage after posting for what
almost two years a little over two years
I have 300 pieces of content if not
more. and people don't remember what you
posted six months ago, I will go back to
a post. I will see one of my friends
comment on it and then I will repost the
exact same post and that person will
comment on it like, "Oh my god, this
blew my mind." I'm like, "Yeah, I did 6
months ago, too." FYI, like I love to
call them out and just make them feel
bad about it. But so maybe a couple of
times a week I'll do a repost of
something that I've done and put in a
lot of work for a year ago or 6 months
ago. or I'll do an update on a old post
like, "Hey, I posted this back in 2023.
Here's how I've changed my viewpoint on
it." Uh, so I do something like that. On
the weekends, it's really hard for me
because I have my kids. And so I usually
try to do polls on Saturdays. So I'll
just ask people for their feedback and
then create a post the following week on
the previous week's poll and the results
that came from that as like kind of
feedback or what they think about it.
And then Tuesdays, Wednesdays, and
Thursdays are kind of my prime time ones
where I try to post something new on
those days because those are the days
that I've seen at least that people are
more invested in reading the content.
They're kind of mid work week and trying
to escape in some spaces. But so yeah,
that is my ideal world and my system.
Does it work like that? No. Like last
Saturday, I was like, I don't have a
poll. But I was like, you know what? I
do have a wad of freaking napkins in my
pocket. Why do I have this wad of
napkins? Oh, cuz I'm a parent. Hey, tell
me you're a parent without telling me.
You have a wad of napkins your pocket.
You go. Your turn. And people were like
all of these things, right? Like you
just live on a sea of crumbs or like you
know there's toys in your p in your
purse and you're stepping on Legos all
the time. So sometimes it is nice to
show people who you are as a person
because then they know, well, yeah, this
is not AI. This is not a robot that's
just continuously trying to sell to me.
This is a person who is just living a
regular life and yes, she has a
business, but she's also funny and she's
human and I could hang out with her on
Sunday at a barbecue or whatever. You
know what I mean? And that's of my vibe.
I like that. The top of the funnel
starts with you on LinkedIn. Couple of
questions in there. Yeah. Kota, is that
a is that a project management tool like
a or something like that? It's a notion
competitor, uh, but it's a little more
robust than notion is.
And I used to use notion, but I'm also
cheap and so I hit the thousand row very
quickly. But KOD's plans basically allow
you to use if you're a single doc maker,
they do it by seat. And so they give you
unlimited if you're just a single doc
user. But if you want to add a team
member, that's when you start paying. So
I've just been using it forever. I use
it for all my resourcehub stuff, which
is an organization of all of my posts in
this document by category because I
could not LinkedIn archiving is
terrible. Like if I want to go back and
try to find a post, I have to keep
scrolling. So I actually put all of them
in this thing just for my reference. And
I was like, screw it. I'm just going to
make this public. And uh and then I put
it out there and I have like 2200
marketers who have downloaded it and
like 5,000 views of it. So they keep
coming back to it to look at it and look
at all landing page content and
everything else. Oh, so your portfolio
is in there. My all my posts.
Wow, cool. The other thing I wanted to
ask you about is polls and that's a it's
one of those features of LinkedIn that
is not commonly used. I think there's
like a critical mass of followers where
it made sense to start using it because
I don't know. I think occasionally I've
tried to put one out there. I haven't
tried in a while, but sometimes you just
get crickets like nobody actually
engages with it. I had a friend of mine,
Eric Holland, on LinkedIn who was like,
he's like, "I hate polls." And I was
like, "Oh my gosh, I love them." He's
like, "That's because you get like three
to 600 responses on yours." I put a poll
out and I get two and I can't do
anything with it. And I think the
biggest thing is to strategically ask
questions. So sometimes, well most times
my questions almost trick questions
where it's like, hey, do you think the
purpose of a landing page is to convert?
Oh, hell yes. Everyone's going to say
yes because that is the conception in
the market. Well, guess what I'm going
to do? Write a post next week about how
conversions are dumb metric to measure
landing pages on, right? But then
sometimes it's also curiosity where I'm
like, hey, what annoys you the most
about websites? Is it no pricing,
irrelevant imagery, buzzwordy copy? And
the crazy thing was I thought
overwhelmingly it would be no pricing.
And it still won, but by very small
percentage, the actual second one was no
no relevant imagery. And I'm like, whoa.
So I did this whole post about people
not liking imagery and why most of us
use stock images, what types of images
you should use. So it gave me this
content idea to expand on and that's
kind of what I use it for. I did another
one the other day that was a trap and it
was like how many touch points do you
think it takes before someone becomes a
qualified lead and people were arguing
and it was great but I got 630 responses
in that one. Usually my polls are like
somewhere between two and 300. Very
fiery topic and people are in the
comments like elaborating as well. Yes,
people are pe I had 630 votes and then a
bunch of people arguing in the comments
about like well it depends. it depends
on where the infunnel they are and blah
blah blah like all of the stuff and I
was just like have at it bros we'll talk
about this next week.
So you mentioned you get a lot of
engagement. How do you handle commenting
on your own stuff and other people do
you make dedicated time for it? Yeah, I
mean I do I definitely think that one of
the keys on LinkedIn I tell my husband
all the time who is just now starting
he's trying he's posting out there and
he's starting to do it consistently like
okay he'll post three times a week but I
told him I'm like honestly the key to
truly like deep engagement on LinkedIn
because you can see I have a smaller
following than some other people but if
you look at the engagement rate like
people have made comments about the
number of comments I will get and the
reason for that is because of one word
and that is reciprocity.
So I spend a lot of time supporting
people without an agenda. So whether
it's commenting on their posts, meeting
people, I get I have three coffee chats
a week. whether this person can buy from
me. And that's not a criteria of mine.
If you say, "Hey, Tass, I really love
your stuff. I would love to grab coffee
sometime. I'm working through XYZ,
whatever." I'll say, "Cool. Hey, I'm
pretty booked out the next couple of
weeks, but why don't you find something
the week of this?" And that's how I keep
my three a week. And it's just spending
that time then really doing the
one-on-one thing where I'm giving them
my undivided attention and talking to
them about their problems whether
they're inhouse or they're out and they
want to start doing maybe they want to
post on LinkedIn maybe they want to
start a business maybe they're
struggling with like stakeholder
management in-house whatever that is
from listening to my podcasts or seeing
some of my posts and they want to talk
about it cool and that's the same thing
with podcasts people will reach my
husband just asked me this morning he's
like do you ever like screen the
podcasts that you get on? I'm like,
"No." And he's like, "Shouldn't you?"
And I'm like, "No, I don't give a I
don't give a crap if you have one
follower, one listener, or you have
10,000 listeners." I like talking to
people. I like coming on. And yeah, I
was like the first guest on this one
podcast, actually two now, because I'm
like, I don't care. I'm here. I love to
help people and be there and genuinely
like to be kind. And I think that helps,
you know. Yeah. Well, I appreciate you
being here sharing your insights and
perspective. I have more than one
follower, I think.
Good.
Talk about impact. And you've already
covered some of the impact. You have a
lot of engagement, you know, have grown
your business off of LinkedIn. Were
there any surprising or unexpected
impacts of investing here?
Uh, yes. I mean outside of now I have
lots and lots of friends even more so
than my real life friends. Some of them
are better than my real life friends
too. Just kidding. Love you all. I
honestly I did a lot of healing to you
know I think when you're in house like
you don't always get the validation for
your ideas and who you are. I feel like
a lot of things that I was punished for
either as a child or in work
environments where it's like she's too
loud, she's challenging the status quo.
She always wants to do stuff that's a
little bit outside of the norm and the
box and we just need her to follow
orders and she's a little bit too loud
or she's too boisterous. All of these
things like she's too ratchet, she's a
little bit unhinged.
All the things that people have disliked
about me or complained about me. I feel
like I got a lot of validation for those
things by just being myself on LinkedIn.
And what that ended up doing was just
helped heal a lot of those insecurities
of like imposttor syndrome and you know
and I go on there and I'm like I don't
know everything. I could write a post
about this thing today and then two
weeks later I'll be proven wrong and
I'll post about how I was wrong about
it. Like I don't care. And I think the
biggest thing is just the permission to
be imperfect. And people like that. They
like people who are real and not super
buttoned up and not super scripted. And
I used to freak out like my first two
podcasts I memorized every question and
every answer and then I would try to
recall exactly what I had written down
or try to read it and it was terrible.
And now it's like every time I talk on a
podcast like listen we'll edit anything
out that you don't I'm like no screw it
leave it in there. I want you to leave
it in there. If I mess up leave it in
there because I want people to know you
can mess up and still get back up and
it's okay. So LinkedIn gave me a lot of
validation there but I feel like I've
healed a lot of that. the burnout thing
too. It's given me a lot of ability to
lead a life around the life part of work
life balance. So yeah, I there's a lot
of benefits and like some of my now best
friends I've met through the platform
that I talk to every day, not about work
stuff, not about LinkedIn stuff, like
literally just about just like you would
as friends. And so I'm very very
grateful for that. you know, I can't I
seriously it's changed my life in many,
many ways. That's awesome. So, you're
admittedly a little unhinged on
LinkedIn. Have you ever had any backlash
on a post or criticism and how do you
handle that? Uh the only time I don't
get a lot of like people are again I
think the that's the one good part about
LinkedIn as a platform is that you can't
hide behind a username or anonymity
right like unlike Twitter or Reddit or
whatever. I refuse to call Twitter X by
the way but unlike the other ones that
have like these usernames and people are
really mean and stuff I feel like we
don't get as much of that here. People
might challenge an opinion and things
like that, but for the most part, people
stay pretty kosher. Or maybe there's a
whole side of LinkedIn like I'm not part
of, but at least in my little B2B
marketing world. People are generally
pretty respectful. I haven't had a lot
of crazy things. I think there's going
to be a lot more risk factor with my new
show just because we're going to be
talking about controversial things. I've
seen some people like get defensive
about some of the things that we've
covered and I get it. So, that's going
to be a fine line I have to walk. There
have been a couple of instances.
One being where someone did like a
public tearown of me and I didn't even
need to say anything. So many people
came to my rescue on that post and they
were like, "Dude, what are you doing?
You cannot plaster a woman's face on
this platform and talk about like how
she could be doing all of these things
better because you want to sell to her."
It was just like so insane. And if you
want to know more details about that, I
do cover it in like the second episode
or something on Notorious B2B in depth.
I like we show the post and everything.
So, just like we some weird stuff like
that. I've gotten challenged on some
perspectives, which is fine. I'm
completely fine with being challenged. I
just don't like any of the AI
commenting. I have not I have nothing to
say to that. So, I'm like, don't waste
your time doing that. I'd rather you
challenge me and pick a fight than leave
some generic thing that I can't respond
to.
All right. Oh, you mentioned a AI
commenting. Maybe that's something. So,
I have a little lightning round to round
out the episode. Okay. And some people
mentioned that in one of the questions.
These are rapid fire. You can elaborate,
you know, as much as you want. Okay. But
we'll start with what advice do you give
to someone who wants to start building
their LinkedIn presence today. Just
getting started. Or maybe it's your
husband. What did you tell? Again, going
back to reciprocity. So, as much as you
are posting on the feed, reach out to
people. In the beginning, I used to send
connection requests to people that I
thought were really interesting. I used
to like find people in my niche, either
ones who were a few steps ahead of me or
people in B2B marketing, reach out to
them, tell them that I liked their
stuff, just like treat people with
kindness, you know, have a lot of calls
and be proactive in that approach. Now,
it's kind of like the other way around
where people reach out to me, but I
always almost always say yes. People
will most likely say yes, too. Um, so
you should do that. be proactive and
actually try to it's a social platform
like have a relationship. Go network
like actually network, not just posting
and then getting mad when no one shows
up for you and they're like they don't
even know who you are. So reciprocity
always first. I like that. Do you have
that same approach to prospecting? It's
all inbound at this time. Um so I don't
do any outbound. Not that I'm against
it. I just don't need to at this stage.
I'm I would maybe later if we had to
expand, but even then I'm just not a
full-on as a person who was in sales.
I'm just a very soft sell person. So I
would not do that. I'd rather lead with
value than lead with the sales. So that
way, you know, I don't I don't do a lot
of that. But the reciprocity thing is so
important. Like you can build an
entirely successful business and never
post a single time. All the copywriting
partners that I have found for my
business, who help me with my client
work, who I pay consistently, they all
like out of them only one posts and
three of them I just found because they
were in the DMs. I would say in priority
order building the relationships
one-on-one way over even just posting on
LinkedIn. Got it. Are you an introvert
or an extrovert? I'm like a 99%
extrovert or something. I just took the
MyersBriggs again the other day and I'm
pretty sure it's like 90% something or
the other. Yeah, it's something insane.
Cool. I will say having talked to a
bunch of people on here who have strong
presence like yourself. You never know.
Yeah, I know. Yeah. Like Tim Davidson,
Mr. Fruit Cutting Guy, crazy shirts on
video. Introvert. Yeah, I met him at X5
event and he had told me that. I was
surprised to hear that because so off
the wall. What's a LinkedIn trend that
you wish would go away? Yeah, the AI
commenting. Oh my god, I can't handle
it. It's like, and I can tell
immediately because the thing is I spend
a lot of time getting to know people
one-on-one. So, when I see a friend of
mine who I'm used to and they are
speaking in a specific voice and then
suddenly that changes and it's more of a
generic voice, I'm the person who will
reply to almost every comment on my
post. If I don't reply to your comment,
it's cuz I have a problem with it. And
more than likely the problem is that it
is something generic that I can't
respond to and or it was written by AI.
So please stop it. It's not doing
anything. It like literally does not do
anything. So I have actually sent
friends messages saying did you use AI
to comment on my post for this? And
they're like no but I'm using a VA
or I'm you know or yeah I'm using this
tool. I've gotten really good responses
from it. I'm like what what good
response have you got from it? what
results specifically have you gotten
from it? And I'm like, the fact that I'm
even calling it out should give you a
big signal that other people are also
seeing this and this is not working for
you. Clearly, you hate AI commenting.
What do you hate more, AI commenting or
comment for my Oh, asset. Oh my god. I
don't like either one. But if I had to
choose, I still hate the AI commenting
because it just gives me nothing to work
with. At least the gating thing, it's
like, okay, you somewhat put in an
effort into this post and said you spent
7,200 hours or whatever, aka made AI do
all your research for you. Like, okay,
cool. You're like attempting something,
but I can't with the AI com. I have not
I nothing paralyzes me more. My mom has
been trying her whole life to get me to
shut up and all it took was an AI
comment. I should tell her. All she used
to every time I say something, she
should just be like, "Agree." And I'm
like, I don't know what I should say
about this.
It's a problem. Maybe they'll fix it. I
did recently see a post. I don't know if
it's true. This is like a post from the
guy Yasmin Alik, one of the super
creators, and he actually made a post
the other day that LinkedIn is actually
throttling people who comment too much
in too little time. I haven't seen any
of that, but I only heard one person
talk about it. Maybe, maybe a comment.
Maybe. And if that's the case, I'm
probably going to get kicked out because
I on average will leave somewhere
between 250 and 300 comments a week. I
don't think that's that much. That's 50
a day or Yeah, I mean, it's quite a bit,
but like I don't know what they're
flagging as automation. I don't have
like dedicated times there. You know how
people like I will work on LinkedIn for
1 hour in the mornings or whatever. I'm
like, eh, I kind of check it as I go and
like we'll see something and comment or
whatever. So maybe the frequency
throughout the day they're probably not
going to flag. But I do leave a lot of
comments. You know what I do get though
that could actually get me kicked out. I
always get the little popup that says,
"Are you sure you want to post this
potentially offensive comment?" I'm
like, "Well, I don't say anything in
there and it's like the word noob." And
then they get all up in arms about it,
you know? I'm like, and I always say,
"Yes, post it anyway." So if I'm going
to get if I'm going to get kicked off,
it'll be probably for something like
that.
Yeah, it's funny on the a comment. I
gotta think there's some detection that
they can see that someone cut and paste.
Yeah. Like immediate cut and put the
content in there, publish in a second or
less, then they know. And then if the
person did 30 of those in 30 seconds,
I mean, LinkedIn is cracking down on
automation. I know that. So, if you're
actually using automation, that would be
an issue. I would imagine that they
would have a way for you to for them to
detect whether you're doing it through
automation versus like naturally. Even
as fast as I am, I don't know if I could
leave that many comments that quickly. I
still do a little They're probably
looking at like predictive patterns. You
like hover patterns, you're reading a
little bit of a post, you hit comment,
then you go whatever. They probably are
tracking a lot of that versus like
comment, publish, comment, post,
comment, post. They're probably looking
for those like rapid actions. I agree.
And I honestly I kind of wonder if they
would fix it because you think about it
this way. They're looking for more ways
to surface more ads and all those like
commenting playbooks. You see how some
people show up in your feed. So and so
commented a on Yes. so and so's posts.
But yeah, well, I guess what we'll see,
they want more people to post so they
can serve up more ads. So anything that
allows them to serve more ads, they're
all for. Yeah. Yeah, they love they love
creators. If you were running LinkedIn
for a day, what is the first thing to
change? Well, they changed the most
annoying thing, which I really
appreciate, which is the scheduling
function to be able to modify it. Oh,
they finally changed that. I Yeah, so
you can modify the scheduled post to
whatever time, which is great. Like
15minute intervals. That was like super
annoying. My husband would love a
dislike button and like that would cause
such a scene. To have a dislike button
would be hilarious. I'm trying to see
what is the big thing. I think LinkedIn
like the feed is kind of weird to me.
And I guess in a way it's good because
you have the life cycle of your post is
much longer. So like when you tweet,
right, it has like a 24-hour cycle and
then it's gone. LinkedIn sometimes I'll
see a post and I'm like four weeks ago
like what you know? So sometimes you
want to see the freshest stuff. So their
sorting and filtering and like how their
introspace stuff works isn't great. So I
don't actually scroll the feed a ton.
The only reason I do it now is for
notorious B2B, but I'm very like
notifications based. So if I like
someone, I'll set a notification to go
to their content and interact. And
that's kind of how I keep my group
pretty focused. And then that way I'm
not consuming a ton of bogus. You know,
when you say notification, as in you
like ring their bell? Yes. Okay. I do
the same. Yeah. Who do you follow and
learn from and who is crushing it on
LinkedIn? Oo.
Well, I learn from a ton of people, so I
could list a whole bunch all day long,
but I am going to list I'm going to talk
about two people who I think deserve
recognition for their content. They're
both in the video kind of niche. So,
Connor Lewis is great. He does like
video breakdowns of video ads, which is
like kind of inception type stuff. So,
he's amazing. And he most recently on
the Exit 5 podcast as well. And then
Adam, I can't say his last name. He's
going to kill me. He's actually one of
my really good friends, but he's amazing
too in the video space, but drops some
like crazy knowledge bombs and also does
a really good job of unhinged posting as
well. So, very entertaining, good stuff,
but also like in that edutainment type
field. So, I'll drop two of them in
terms of like new people you should
follow. Um, and then I learn from a ton
of people. I'm very much in the B2B
marketing space, so they may not always
be like I don't follow a lot of like the
big broy,
who are they names now? Luke Matthews
and Yasman's. I don't follow any of like
I'm not I don't either. I don't Yeah.
Matt Barker and stuff. I feel like
they're good. Like they teach you how to
write on LinkedIn and then all the stuff
that they teach you there doesn't is
actually stuff that in my little niche
people like just turn off. They call it
like broetry and they don't want to read
it like that. And so I used to write a
lot like that and now I'm reverting back
to writing like more longer form type
stuff and just writing like a regular
person. They they advocate for the
perfect post that like fits in the
mobile view, which to be fair, I do
still I use a previewer that I don't log
into. So that's my LinkedIn conspiracy
is like I don't use shield. I don't use
anything that hooks up to my LinkedIn
profile because in the beginning I used
to help one of my one of my contacts
write on LinkedIn and and then it was
like she got shadowbanned and the only
thing she had hooked up at the time was
Shield. So, we took that off and then
she saw a slow climb that came out. So,
I have these like weird things and I'm
super weird about that. So, I manually
will pull my analytics. I will manually
get links to posts. I will not use any
automation to even put them in my
resource hub. None of that because I'm
so worried about that stuff being a
reason that I would get kicked out. And
then I have I show zero concern when I'm
actually posting comments and being
unhinged. I'm like, "Okay, if I'm going
to get kicked out, at least it's for
that." and it was like totally worth it,
but I can't for like the hooking up
analytics and automations and things
like that. I don't think they'll kick
you out. They like your content too much
and the ability to serve ads off of it.
Yeah, that I like it so I hope they
don't. Is there anything exciting
happening at the scroll lab or your new
podcast Notorious B2B that you want to
plug? Well, definitely come find me on
LinkedIn and task bober t last name
bober like sober and I have that free
resource hub and if you're not like into
landing pages and stuff that's fine if
you're more around like growing on
LinkedIn and consolidating your posts
and stuff you can go look at how I
structured mine to like have an archive
of my own stuff. It's kind of like your
own, you know, like yeah portfolio or
like you know your personal like diary
and documentation. like you're putting
in all this work to create content, you
should probably have it consolidated in
a place where you can maybe show your
children one day. My mom's go, "My
daughter will be like, "This is
embarrassing. Why did you even keep
this, Mom? This is the most cringe thing
ever." But maybe it's kind of like a
good representation of the work that
you've put in. I think the way I would
describe coming to LinkedIn and then
seeing its impact, you're not going to
see it from one post or two post or one
networking call or whatever. It's one of
those things that compound over time.
So, it's not so much about being at the
right place at the right time. It's
about being at the right place for a
long time. So, that's kind of what I
would tell people is like just keep
showing up. I don't care if I post
something and it doesn't do well. Like,
I have heard people will like take down
a post that isn't doing well. I'm like,
no, leave it up there. Do model. I said
what I said. It's up there. It's out in
the universe. like if it gets 30 likes
or 5,000 likes, they're gonna remain up
there because I want people to know like
you're not going to hit it out of the
park every time. And your follow account
really doesn't mean anything. All that
matters is the algorithm, the algorithm
and your reach there and how you show up
for your interests and other people's
interests and whatever. Who knows? You
can sit there and dissect the feed all
you want. Sometimes works,
sometimes doesn't work. Leave it
all up there, though. They're all
learnings. They're all learnings.
I love that. Thank you for dropping that
last bit of knowledge on us. Everybody
go follow Tad Bober. I'll link in the
show notes and then the Substack article
will also link her portfolio. And until
next time, let's stay connected.
If you enjoyed this episode, follow Brad
and Spectrime on LinkedIn for hot takes
and tactical executive branding advice.
For the readers in the audience,
subscribe to LinkedIn Famous Unsubstack.
And if you really love this episode,
leave us a review on Apple Podcast,
Spotify, or the podcasting platform of
your choice. Until next time, stay bold,
authentic, and keep on creating.
[Music]