The next time I build a SAS app, one
criteria of what I choose to build is is
there some kind of productled growth in
the product. And if I can't do that,
then I'm less likely to do it because
then I have to adopt this other ethos of
business I don't really care about.
If you're building a B2 SAS product or
AI agent, check out Gearart. They're not
just a dev shop. They're founders who
built and exited their own startups. So
whether you're validating an idea
already scaling, they know how to meet
you where you are. They've helped launch
so many products including Smart Suite
which raised $38 million. Right now,
Confessions of a B2B entrepreneur
listeners get a free strategy session
and 20% off validation, discovery, and
prototyping throughout September. Hit
the link in the description to claim
your slot.
[Music]
Hello and welcome back to SAS that app.
Today we are thrilled to welcome Tom
Hunt, founder and CEO of fame, a fully
remote 71 person team that starts and
scales the world's most profitable B2B
podcasts. Tom's journey includes
founding 17 startups, investing in more,
learning the art of growing businesses
through content and community, and also
happens to be the host of Confessions of
a B2B entrepreneur. You'll have to check
that out. Tom is very passionate about
the formula to becoming famous, creating
niche like insanely good content and
getting seen alongside many other famous
players. So, it's kind of a philosophy
that ties into today's topic, which is
productled growth in SAS. Tom, welcome
to the pod. Thanks for having me, guys.
I'm very excited. Now, maybe I should
admit now that I've tried a few times to
build a SAS and you could say failed or
you could say succeeded and learned
loads of things, but we can dig into
that in the episode.
>> Absolutely. Yeah, I like the second one
there. And uh with me as always is my
partner in crime, who I'm sad to say is
not wearing his doughut shirt today. I
was very excited about that yesterday,
Justin Edwards.
>> We got to split up the release order of
these podcast so I don't always show up
wearing the same clothes. Everyone's
going to realize I only actually own
five shirts, but
>> same spray cycles, man.
>> How about that? So anyway, happy to be
here.
>> Good deal. So Tom, completely off topic
to get us started, but do I have it
right that you have a degree in
chemistry, a master's degree in
medicinal chemistry? Yeah, I thought the
three years wasn't enough and I went for
the fourth and that's when I realized I
actually didn't want to do it anymore
within the fourth year. But I think the
point I remember is in the fourth year
you had to do your own project and I was
trying to build a protein that would
maybe interact with another protein. And
I was in the lab on my own for like the
fifth day straight mixing liquids around
and I was like wow I really don't give a
[ __ ] about this.
>> I find that super relatable.
>> Really? Yeah. And then well it gets
better because then I was like okay so
what do I do? Had no idea. And so then I
spent two years at a company called EY
which is a big professional accountancy
firm. And then I was like, well, also
don't like this, so maybe I'll go and
work for Accenture, another big
professional service firm.
>> That sounds awful.
>> And then it was two months into that and
I was like, well, yeah, I really don't
give a [ __ ] about this either. And so
then this takes us up to, well, start
2014, and this is where the story gets a
bit more interesting, I think, is that
I'm like, if I can't do chemistry, I
can't be employed because I've tried two
companies and I didn't work well either.
What do I do? I was interested in the
internet, but then I couldn't code. So I
was like, I need to try and replace my
salary so I can actually like be useful
in the world. So if you can't code or
you like the internet, then online
marketing is probably the the next best
thing. So I basically spent 2014
learning online marketing and then
ultimately did manage to replace my
salary with a tiny small Filipino
outsourcing company and then managed to
leave in 2015 and then now it's been a
decade of trying and failing to build
various software service companies.
>> Fantastic. I I feel like we're starting
to get a a stable. We actually had a
polymer chemist on a few episodes back.
So, I'm very interested always in how
you depart from there and arrive at
where you are.
>> If memory serves, the polymer chemist
also had motivational issues with his
job and stopped being a polymer chemist.
So,
>> yeah, but sometimes I think like maybe
I'll go back because I think having
business skills and marketing skills and
chemistry skills is quite a unique
combination. So there might be a a niche
for a chemistry business that's also
combined with online marketing and maybe
a bit of software because I've done some
of that. I know you guys are probably
the experts.
>> Yeah. You know who to call if there's a
software component.
>> Yeah, exactly. Meaning you guys will
lean on you for for your Filipino
outsourcing company. How did that come
about? Did you go to the Philippines and
realize how wonderful the people were or
was it a different way that you arrived?
I'd actually been there a bit before and
because in both EY and Accenture for
whatever reason I was involved in
projects where we were outsourcing work
for other large companies that gave
credibility when I was cold emailing
like random startup founders in London
being like do you want to use my
Filipina team and I'm like I spent 3
years working on big outsourcing deal
with Accenture. So I think it was just
something that I had experience with,
had credibility in. And then why the
Philippines? I think for our work week,
he hired his VA from the Philippines,
Tim Ferrris. And so it was more random,
I think, than strategic.
>> One thing that's really great about the
Philippines is that all of their formal
education and schooling is done in
English. So they speak their native
language at home, but everyone there is
a native English speaker or at least a
very high level English speaker because
that's how their schooling is done. So
it's a great fit for the English
speaking world to work with folks there.
>> Yeah. I also found they're like
extremely I don't know why but very
loyal. If you can provide a like regular
paycheck, a good working environment,
the employee retention is higher than
I've seen in other countries.
>> Yes, I think that's true in a lot of
places that aren't weird, you know,
western, educated, rich, and so on. But
yeah, I love the Philippines. I love
Filipino people. So, it's super cool
>> and still a component of fame if I
remember right too, Tom.
>> Yeah, exactly. We're fully remote and so
obviously some roles don't need to be
done in the west and so we have about 30
people in the Philippines and there was
one person who was involved in that
first outsourcing company that's still
involved in fame today and a lot of the
team have been brought in by that person
and so they're like a connection all the
way through the the last decade of
working in the Philippines. Nice. Well,
kind of jumping into the topic for the
day and just for our listeners, can you
just break down your take on what it
means to have productled growth? Yes.
There's like almost a very holistic way
of looking at business. I'll explain
first and then I'll explain why I think
product growth is so important. If you
think of a business like a system, I
think businesses spend a lot of money on
like outbound sales or advertising. I
feel like that's wasted energy from the
system. like the system is leaking
because often there's no upside for
anyone from interrupting people with
outbound email or spending loads of
money on ads for people that don't care
about it. And so it's just a leakage of
of energy and therefore cash from the
system. And so what we try to do at fame
and what I've tried to do whenever I
build a SAS app is how can I get
advertising in quotes in the process of
a user using my tool. At Fame, we have
built our own podcast hosting tool. And
so the tool simply takes the audio and
then distributes that to Apple and
Spotify, keeps it updated. And so why
that's great for the Fame host, the
tool, and for Fame itself is because
then for every episode, we're able to
produce a web page that sits on our
domain that can get organic traffic.
Today, there's a guy called Rob Walling
who we should definitely try and get on
this show. Two months ago, I had him on
my show. We released the episode a week
ago. today he tweets out a snippet from
that episode but also the link to the
episode that's on our domain and so Rob
Bowling 35,000 followers on Twitter his
audience is probably potential good
customers for fame and so we're getting
exposed just through the use of the tool
the final point there is also that when
people go on podcasts they then also
like to put the link to the episode from
their press page on their site and so
last month we get a backlink to our
domain again it's an episode page of
same host from IBM because one of their
guests went on our client show. So, I've
actually shared like three ways where
just through the use of our tool, we're
able to get brand exposure. And so, what
does that mean? That means we can spend
less money doing outbound sales, less
money running ads to people that don't
care, which enables us to bring our
prices down while still being able to
reinvest to make the service better. And
then it feeds into this holistic loop
which I call the fame playbook. But it's
the same we can just use the same loop
for any SAS company is that we get cheap
clients because our users are bas
essentially doing advertising for us.
And then that enables us to bring price
down to deliver a good service lower
price which makes clients happier which
then increase word of mouth but also
should increase usage of the tool
because they stay for longer which then
gets more clients cheaply because
they're using our tool. Just kind of
thinking through the spectrum of the
process here. Is there some sort of a
threshold or like a volume number or a
metric where that makes more sense but
initially still requires you to rely on
those more traditional sales models or
outbound things or is this something
that the effort goes into it right away?
So it's almost for me like the next time
I build a SAS app one criteria of what I
choose to build is is there some kind of
productled growth in the product and if
I can't do that then I'm less likely to
do it because then I have to adopt this
other ethos of business I don't really
care about and so in my mind that should
be part like obviously if you're
building something you guys know more
about this than me but you want to
prioritize the features and so one input
to that feature per the television
backlog is is this going to help us get
more customers along with like do
customers actually want this how hard it
is to build etc. So I think obviously
when you're small it may not bring any
customers but I still think like it's
part of the product we want it to be
there we want to keep improving and
iterating that over time so we get an
impact from it at the sweetest possible
point.
>> So does that also involve like the
premium model you know again just trying
to get that word of mouth out there to
try to build that customer base so that
you can really leverage it to get these
future sales. Yeah, I do feel like this
approach is better with like maximum
users and so if we're able to give a
premium model then a product like growth
is much more suited to that.
>> Yeah, that makes sense.
>> And so this may be kind of deviating a
little bit from product led growth, but
you're obviously working very hard to
also generate referral based business
and business on referrals as well. Is
that kind of a similar idea where you
get more bang for your buck and don't
spend a lot of time advertising to
people who don't care?
>> Exactly. Right. Let's say we had a five
grand ad budget off or I was going to
hire a new salesperson. It's going to
cost five grand per month. I would
rather keep prices the same whilst
improving the service. Like take that
five grand and invest it in something
that's going to I don't know a promotion
for the team or a new team member that's
going to improve service to then get
that value back through the referrals.
We're basically leaking less financial
energy from the system.
>> Interesting. So what would you say then
just continuing that line of thought
would be pitfalls to this type of an
approach or to those who might try to
you know engineer this like virally?
Yeah, I feel like I've definitely signed
up to tools where like maybe in the sign
up flow it like immediately does
something that is public when obviously
they'll get my permission but it's just
not something that I would want to do.
So the conversion rate on that is going
to be low. When it happens it could have
negative impacts to the user which is
not good to the brand. So the absolute
best example I think is candly because
obviously for anyone to book a meeting
with you, you have to send them
something. And so I wouldn't try and
shoehorn it in, but take every possible
opportunity to get your brand out there
through the usage. One thing that I
think Calendarly do really well is that
they know every time the Calendarly link
is sent, that's like an opportunity for
them to impress. And so the UI and the
design on calendar links I think is the
best out of all the other competitors
and it has been for the last like five
10 years. And so I think that's a place
if you are going to invest in the
product obviously you want to make sure
the product's amazing but it's an
opportunity to impress with every usage.
>> So both for podcast and the calendarly
example these kind of have like this
network effect where there's like
virality is a component inherently in
how that spread. Does does product
growth really only work in that kind of
niche? and we draw tendrils of this
further into other business models that
don't necessarily have that kind of
viral component.
>> One thing we do at Fame, which isn't
part of Fame Host software, it kind of
is, but we don't need Fame Host to do
it. And again, because we're a content
creation agency, in the global show
notes of every episode, we say this was
created with love by fame. And so that's
us being able to get attention through
the content that we're producing for
customers. So that's another
opportunity. So I think any service
business most of them do like create
things that customers use. Again it's a
bit tricky and you probably have to get
permission but that's one like way of
doing this. It is definitely more suited
to the lower cost almost BTOC like SAS
like currently like podcast hosting
software. I used to do like big writeups
of how software companies have grown
like Clickfunnels. I'm sure you guys are
aware of that. that had incredible viral
growth because their free plan. Any web
page you created had the ClickFunnels
bottom in the bottom right and that was
like premium on steroids with that free
offer. What I'd love to do actually is
like study Salesforce like how are
Salesforce possibly getting their brand
exposed. I don't know maybe in marketing
cloud they obviously have like an email
software to send emails to your list
presumably they've like is set by
Salesforce Marketing Cloud at the bottom
of every email. So that's probably an
example. I think it it probably there
probably is ways for most assets, but
it's like that B TOC like tool that it
seems to work the best.
>> We are kind of always prided ourselves
on doing like a very excellent job and
going above and beyond with customer
support, customer service and being
really responsive and kind of being
hightouch and we get referral business
because of that a lot and we have a
reputation in the different communities.
We're because of that and for a services
company that doesn't have a product that
is kind of a little bit of our version
of product l growth where people are
reinforcing that interesting idea.
>> Exactly. We have a fundamental belief of
fame that I think is should be true for
businesses. It seems that you guys are
aligned. Retention is the foundation of
growth. So, let's just try and invest as
much as possible in the customer
experience so that we don't have to work
out how to run a cold outbound process.
Yeah. And I I far prefer that to like
the volume based approach. We've worked
actually as partners with some other
service industries and things like that
who go very deep, but it's all in one
particular vertical. That's where their
expertise lies. That's what they hire
into. That's what it is that they do.
But they also have a product that
they're centering this around. To
Justin's point, it's a little bit
trickier or more challenging you to do
perhaps as a service because until you
have an opportunity to present yourself
in your services and can then direct
potential clients to those recommenders
or or people who have had good service
with us or get it to the web and and be
able to kind of propagate that through
something like a podcast for example, it
becomes kind of challenging in the
industry to do. Yeah. One other idea I
remember coming up with is that if in
the process of using your tool, your
customer or your users create something
that they would be proud of, then
actually we're robbing them of a good
experience by not allowing them to share
that. I remember the tool I studied to
do this was a SAS tool for mind mapping
called MindMeister, I believe. And so
obviously every user creates their mind
maps and then they simply added they
didn't have it before they added one
button that once a map was saved they
had a make public button and then that
would just publish that mind map on
their own domain and then it could be
shared and I think they expand
significant growth after that. So if
your users are creating anything that
they could be proud of that they might
want to share then let's just chuck on
the domain and then allow them to share
it.
>> Gotcha. So you had mentioned earlier too
and I'm sure it's part of some of the
things that you've you've already
mentioned and without necessarily giving
away any secret sauce or things that you
want to keep. Tell me a little bit more
about your fame playbook. You had
mentioned playbook. What does that look
like?
>> The playbook is like a longer dock that
explains like everything. But the point
I think is most relevant here is within
that doc is called the fame flywheel.
And this is popularized by Jim Collins
who wrote goods great probably the best
business book of all time. I think he
has like one chapter he pulled out and
actually created his own book and used
Amazon as a case study called the
firewall effect. And the concept here is
that essentially whenever you're
starting a business you're turning this
wheel and at the start every time you
turn it might take like a year to turn
it cuz it's really hard because you
don't have any previous work. But then
every time you turn it gets a little bit
easier and easier and easier. And so a
good idea for a business is to
understand what what are the steps on
that wheel that you can impact and then
how can you get it to turn faster and
faster. And then ultimately if it's
turning fast enough you can step back
and it will keep going. So this is what
Jeff essentially has done at Amazon. And
so I have tried to create this but for
fame. I'll just quickly talk through the
flywheel if only five steps. So step one
acquire clients cheaply because if we're
acquiring clients expensively then
that's obviously going to push us to
increase prices which is going to
increase the difference between the
amount we charge and the value we
deliver. So I'll talk more about that in
a second. Now the other point about the
flywheel is that in order for a flywheel
to actually work each step has to be
like inevitable based on the next one.
So if we acquire clients cheaply the the
next step we have to do is to hire and
train great values aligned people. And
if we do that well then our service the
fame service is going to improve. That's
the third step. If we improve the
service because we've got clients and
we've acquired them cheaply and we've
acquired and trained great design people
then the next thing that will happen
from an improved service is we have
happy clients. Then if we have happy
clients that means we're going to get
more of four things. So more referrals
as we were just discussing more case
studies which helps with the sales
process and brings down acquisition cost
more word of mouth obviously which will
bring down acquisition cost and more
virality through the methods that we
have discussed today and then obviously
the output of that is acquire cheaply
and then it goes around again and again.
So those are the five steps that if
we're looking to improve the business
that we know that we have to try and
improve one of those five things. So, in
terms of like acquiring clients cheaply
has a subjectivity to it, right? Like I
don't have to share it, but like do you
have a specific number where like this
is a client that was cheap to acquire
versus expensive to acquire or is your
system set up in such a way you don't
talk to clients that are expensive to
acquire?
>> Yeah, good question and very relevant
recently. So, I'm happy to share our top
four acquisition channels which is
roughly 85% of all customers. The first
two is Google, organic and paid. Third
is partnerships and then fourth is my
LinkedIn and podcast. Now, in the
partnerships one, this is very relevant
and topical recently. If we think about
the cost of the partnerships is like the
cost of running the program which is
really just one person like finding
partners and keeping them engaged. So
pretty relatively low. But then
obviously we pay out to partners. We
used to pay 100% of the first month of
revenue and so this would be between two
and $4,000 per customer and we're
shooting for like 2,000 basically but
we're kind of happy or or we really just
testing that to see if that would get us
more referrals and it did. But then what
happened is we had one customer that
came in that maybe wasn't the right
customer to accept only stayed with us
for like three months and we paid the
one month and so really if we ran all
the numbers we probably didn't make any
money on that customer and so that
customer was too expensive to acquire
and so since then we have just reduced
the partnership commission to 50% of the
first month to kind of control that. So
we're probably getting a few less
referrals now but we can be quite
confident that they're going to be cheap
enough. Did you consider paying out the
referral fee over time as opposed to in
one lump sum? And why did you decide
against that? Because it looks like you
did consider it.
>> Yeah, it was more just simplicity, but
you're totally right. Like we actually
used to have 10% per month, but we we're
trying to juice it and make a bit more
center. But yeah, that would like
eradicate the risk of the low lifetime
value. I'll quickly cover how we reduce
cost in the other three growth program.
We call them growth programs. My
LinkedIn and podcast. Obviously the
podcast is cheap to run because we just
run their own in-house and we have uh
the system.
>> You got a couple people there that know
how to do podcasts.
>> Yeah, exactly. We have a couple. And
then my LinkedIn I guess it is cheap for
the business because just I do 100% of
the work. So it could be cheap or
expensive depending on how you look at
it. So like no real significant cost for
either of those. We we pay for the team
to run my show, but that's because we've
honed that down over time. Google
organic, we've already discussed this,
right? Like we got the backlink from IBM
because we have fame hosts. Now that's
strong. like a backlink to the homepage
would be a lot better than backlink to
this like random episode page but we're
trying to like do the structure to still
get the value and so I think we've been
quite good at building SEO which is like
a big part of how we can rank highly and
therefore acquire content cheaply and
then finally Google ads our approach for
Google ads is only I don't know how how
much you guys know about Google ads but
we only bid on like they have intent not
just for a podcast but for a podcast
provider service company agency and we
only use exact have to match. So first
terms like B2B podcast agency or podcast
production company like very focused
only that match. So we're not wasting
money on terms like how do I start a
podcast. So those are the ways that we
focus our energy on acquisition
channels. Got it. So I want to step back
for just a second because you had
mentioned something about a recent
client or a client that you said was not
the right customer to accept and this is
something that Justin and I can attest
to but you know just dealing in the
service industry. One, it's sometimes
challenging to assess whether that
customer is right at the outset. And so
I'm curious how you go about that. And
then two, how do you let them know that
perhaps this is not the best fit for
them organizationally so that you can
amicably kind of part ways?
>> I think on the first question there's
like quantitive and qualitative, right?
There's like during the sales process,
do you get a good feeling? And I a
massive criminal of like getting a bad
feeling, but because I wanted the
revenue or like we didn't have enough
clients, then I would go for it. And so
the only way you learn that is if you
guys are nodding is like through
experience. And so now by like year four
or five I can be like okay we're not
we're not going to have this person. So
we actually did a great analysis a few
months ago of just looking at all of the
term clients from all time and whether
they were on persona. And so on persona
for us now has changed because of that
analysis. We essentially saw that any
company with less than I think 25
employees typically had a lower number
month with us by like 20 to 30%. And so
now we've just changed this criteria in
order to try and accept the companies
that are slightly bigger. And the main
reason for that is because smaller
companies are typically just higher risk
and half of our churn we call
uncontrollable. Eg we don't really have
an impact on it and of company going
bust basically. So we're hoping that's
going to have an impact that change was
made recently. So that's like a
quantitive analysis of historic churn.
But then there is the qualitative like
feeling which I would if anybody's
listening I would like urge people to go
with that more than than ignore it. Uh,
that's a big lesson I've had.
>> I agree that 100%.
>> Final point I didn't answer was how to
let them know. This literally happened
today where there was a customer that
was a nightmare and then we agreed to
finish on this day. We just about
finished. And then today they were like,
"Oh, actually, we've really been
enjoying working with you the past
month. Can we continue work together?"
And actually, it was the head of account
management was like, "I don't think we
should do this." I was like, "I'll leave
it with you. You can decide and you can
do the communication." So, I haven't
actually reviewed what she sent, but I'm
sure it was great. But yeah, I don't
have a good answer to that. Maybe you
guys can share.
>> Yeah, we end up in a little bit of a
sticky situation because a lot of times
we have customers that are dependent
upon us because we know the software or
we have access to things. So we have a
it's very important for us to be proper
stewards of the trust that was put in us
initially even if the relationship isn't
working out and the client's unhappy. So
even if things are really ugly, we have
to cooperate for a period of time
because the customer needs things that
we have and we need to do the right
thing by our customers. But I typically
try to use kind of vague language like
this decision has been made and it's not
working out from our perspective and if
people want really solid feedback as to
why they're an awful client, I usually
have a couple emails or things I can
refer them to. It's like so we don't
typically talk to other human beings
like this and that's why we're not
working with you anymore.
>> What I'll do is I'm just going to get
the actual email that was sent today and
we'll see if it was as good as that.
>> Oh,
real inside baseball now.
>> Yeah. So the the response is basically
like the head of account management
saying to them, I've spoken with the
team and we essentially want to stick
with what we already agreed when we
agreed not to work together a couple of
months back. We're happy to continue
supporting you with the work that we're
currently doing. Sorry if this isn't
what you're hoping to hear, but we hope
it's clear and aligns with what was
previously agreed. I don't think it was
as good as your one, was it?
And we all have different approaches
that we take, too. you know, we've got
an outstanding project manager who knows
the clients better probably than anybody
just by virtue of being project manager.
And so we could always bounce things off
of him of, you know, how do you think
that something like this is going to be
taken and then we could tweak and tune
from there. Justin's always awesome with
just bringing the facts. It's like
here's where we're at and I have a
tendency to be much more touchyfey, but
we all have our approaches and and we've
all seen some success with that. But at
the end of the day, it still comes back
to the assessment of why this was not a
good fit and how do we address that as
an organization and move forward and
either not repeat that or if it does
show back up again, addressing it
better. We don't have that come up a
whole lot though. I'd be curious to know
where it pops up in your business. But
in our business, it's kind of usually
two categories. One of which is that the
customer can't really afford to work
with a team at our scale and quality and
with our business model. And that's not
saying anything bad about them. They
just they need to find a cheaper
solution. And that's okay. It's we're
not inexpensive. and that it is what it
is. Uh the other typical kind of problem
we have with clients is like basic human
decency stuff like people being really
awful to Aaron which makes me angry and
then I get very protective of my team.
And so that's the other reason we've cut
people loose is just like hey life's too
short to work with people who want to
treat other people like this and we just
won't do it. So I guess what are some of
the reasons other than the unsalvageable
clients clients who've turned for fame.
We have this rule on like strikes
because the some cases are like clearly
this person is being rude and so that
would almost be like uh maybe one strike
and then out. But then there are also
clients that maybe had this where
they're not like directly being rude but
they're just almost unpleasant to work
with. So it isn't just like an ethical
thing. I don't think it's actually a
good business decision to try and get
rid of them because for us again like we
talked about retention the same applies
to us for employee retention.
>> Yes. and losing a team member can often
have a bigger impact than losing a
client. And so if the team member is
unhappy, then we'll try to look to
replace them and then bring someone else
who maybe is better suited to the client
before sending the email to essentially
get rid of them. What we have done
recently which you guys might find
interesting is in the sales process as
well as assessing whether we think
they're going to be a good customer is
trying to understand more about the
person we're going to work with if we're
interfacing with that person in the
sales process because then we can try
and match them whether it's
energetically interest-wise tonality
with the right account manager who's
going to work with them and so again
this is a recent change or a recent
initiative but I'm hoping then it almost
feels more seamless for the client and
the account manager when they're working
together which would mean we'd have less
of these people issues. Yeah, you
actually have teetered into something
that I want to explore just a little bit
too. You're talking about growth
strategies and product development, but
you've also gotten into your team
internally in your culture and how that
works. But as an international company,
you know, you have international markets
and there is nuance to that both for
your clients but also for the people who
are going to be interacting with them.
And I'm just kind of curious how you
manage not only internally your team and
and where to position them and how to
position them internationally, but also
how you educate them or what they bring
in terms of dealing with the cultural
differences or the marketing nuances of
where they actually are and who they're
servicing.
>> Yeah. So we made the vision early on
that culturally we thought it would
would be better for like core part of
the team to be in one at least country
because there are obviously cultural
similarities between people within the
same country. So we have I think 30% of
the team in the UK and 40% of the team
in the Philippines and so that's great
for us internally but then with the
majority of our clients being in the US
then the majority of the dynamics
between client and account manager or
client and team member is US to UK and
so this is actually probably a great
opportunity for like training is if we
could have someone internally run it if
we had an American person but I don't
think we do maybe an external person
who's American that understands the
culture could just like come and explain
to us just more about how American
people think. That's actually a really
good idea. I should uh explore this
because it's probably something that we
could improve on if we haven't done it
before. Happy to be guinea pigs for that
if if you need somebody. So, I want to
get a little bit now into kind of
approach. Obviously, a lot of what we're
talking about here is viral for lack of
a better way of putting it, but it's
very network oriented. You know, the
larger your net, the more you're going
to be able to bring back in. We're
spending a lot of time talking about
content and awareness and things like
that. And I'm curious if or how those
tie to business outcomes for the people
that you work with. I know that you have
a diverse set of of businesses that you
work with, particularly in the podcast
space because obviously that's that's
where we come in, but do you become kind
of experts in in their spaces or in
their field so that you can better
engage with them or or how do you
metric, you know, the business outcomes
that you're trying to achieve for your
clients and then tie those solutions? If
we have high employee retention then two
things happen. First is that the service
and podcast knowledge of the team
increases. The second thing happens is
that there's quite a lot of repeat
industries that we get. Most podcasts
sit in a similar space. And so what that
means is that we can often match account
managers with a client that has a
similar topic. For example, like this
show there's like tech but also a bit of
marketing etc. And so we can bring on a
marketing or a tech. So that's the step
one. And obviously what we're really
doing like if we take an episode the
technical expertise is in the episode
the main value we bring is how do we
take the information and format it in a
way that a good podcast episode and so
that actually we don't necessarily need
for that part a lot of the technical
expertise. So that's the first step but
then second step is if we do have the
industry knowledge we can often produce
episodes. So like the foundation is the
podcast knowledge. Second is the
industry specific knowledge. So that's
how we like to produce a good podcast in
terms of how people make money from the
podcast. I learned this when I was doing
content marketing in our decade of
online marketing is that if the long
game and so if in the short term we can
try and gain some kind of benefit from
the content production and then that
enables us to reinvest to get to the
real holy grail which is your ideal
buyers knowing liking and trusting you
before they come to buy. So that's the
holy grail but it takes a long time
especially with podcasting and so then
the question is how on the route to
building the audience that no likes and
trust us can we get some kind of ROI
some kind of business benefit and I
discovered this when I ran the first
podcast for within the decade of
trailing and failing I worked for a B2
SAS company as head of demand generation
we started a podcast and the 11th guest
was the VP of sales ops podcast 11th
guest was the VP of sales also intercom
he came on the show randomly got
chatting with our CEO and then bought
our software for the whole of Intercom
sales team. So that basically at that
point paid for the podcast like nine
times over. So the business now said
they love the podcast, gave us more
money to improve production value,
increase release frequency and that
enabled them to grow the audience which
was the real benefit. And so it's a long
way of saying shortterm how can we get
an ROI from the guests whether that's
them becoming customers them becoming
partners. So that convinces the finance
person or the CEO or even the host who
like wants to know that their work is
having a business impact to keep
investing in the show over 6 months 12
months to build audience.
>> Gotcha. So now looking outward because
you have worked with so many different
businesses and organizations who are
getting into podcast for whatever reason
you know whether that's marketing or
just to enter into the knowledge space
or they're looking to you know gain some
sort of traction or whatever. I suspect
that over the course of these different
businesses and the different podcasts,
you've probably seen successes and
failures of their actual SAS, not so
much the podcast, but of the SAS itself.
So, I'm curious what you see as like the
primary markers of those successes or
failures of the application, less so the
podcast. So I'm not sure if it's going
to answer the question, but I think the
most powerful lesson that I've learned
from like working inside a client's
business essentially tell them with
their podcast was a big company called
High Radius, massive SAS company based
out of India, I think like thousands of
employees. The podcast was with the CEO.
So we'd have quite a lot of meetings
without the CEO and the meetings were
good. All the people were really
intelligent and like once a month we'd
have a meeting with the CEO. And what I
found very impressive and fascinating
was that almost any question that was
put to the CEO, he wouldn't answer, but
he'd give the company value that it
would relate to and push it back to
someone else in their team. And so he
was just like almost he was just like
pushing back and then forcing the team
to decide based on the company's values
that they had like four values. So that
for me was like wow for a company that's
so like thousands of people the CEO at
least really like lives by these values
that was pretty impressive to me and I'm
sure their company is doing very well
financially. So that's one like positive
thing I've seen. It's like basically
living to values at the highest level.
Negative wise it's almost like a
marketing almost like a life ethos like
remember we said that the holy grail is
to build the audience of people that
know like and trust you. So when they
need the service or they need the
software, they come to you. In order to
do that, you have to delay you getting
value. And so some clients are like, we
need to talk about this client case
study we did in this podcast episode
that just talks about our product. But
then like only a very tiny group of
people, the people that are basically
about to buy care about that. And so the
the clients where I've seen it not go so
well is that they haven't understood
that actually we have to gain these
people's trust over time. We have to
entertain them. We have to add value.
And we do that by not talking about
product service, by talking about things
that interest them. So that's one other
thing that I've seen that is probably
correlated with a SAS dying or or
growing.
>> I love hearing you say that. I'm uh
banging that drum all the time with our
podcast and our internal discussions,
which is like, hey, this is not a thinly
veiled advertisement for our services.
This is, you know, real content we want
to put out there. We want to have real
discussions with real people. So love
that.
>> Exactly. Right. And not only longer term
is going to be better for the business,
but it actually like feels good. you
know, you like you created the content
or after someone comes to you on
LinkedIn and say, "I enjoyed the
episode." It's like it's like a good
feeling. It's like a good thing for the
world.
>> Yeah. We feel like we do a number of
things right and in the space that we're
in and we have a lot of experience. I
mean, cumulatively, it's it's, you know,
decades of experience and it just felt
like it's a good time. Let's put some
knowledge out there and and just kind of
get in the space. We had a guest show up
on a recent episode and make a comment
about how we hate JavaScript, which is
not completely inaccurate, but it's also
like I didn't even realize I had put
that out there, but like someone knew of
something about me before
>> that like shows that people are thinking
about you when like you don't even know
who they are. You do obviously when they
became a guest. So that's like we're on
the road to getting people to know like
and trust us.
>> I have one question. We sometimes have
folks show up with an app idea or they
think it'd be cool to do a software and
sometimes they show up with money and
not really much of an idea or certainly
not like a cogent top bottom plan for
how they're going to execute this rough
idea of a business. I imagine you guys
probably also see that a lot where
someone has the idea like it'd be cool
to have a podcast and they come in the
front door and need a lot of guidance on
like what would you talk about and what
would a format be. So do you have in
your playbook like a way to kind of
coach people through that or how does
that process develop with with your team
and someone engages with you? Yes,
throughout the launch process, we have
the what we call the podcast positioning
process, which is actually like a very
high leverage success lever for the rest
of the show. Like if we get the name and
like the brand identity and the ethos of
the show right, then everything else is
easier. And so even if someone has an
idea, we like to filter it through this
methodology because our job is just
going to be so much easier if we get
that right. And then yeah, often I would
say the majority of hosts are open for
coaching or at least they say they are
and they they take the coaching. I don't
know if they they do anything about it,
but we'll see about this Aaron tomorrow.
>> Yeah, present company excluded. But uh
>> so I would say that there's probably two
things people need help with. It's it's
the positioning and we like to do that
for all of them. And then we also offer
coaching and it's also almost always
accepted, but whether it's acted upon is
another question.
>> Well, Tom, it has been an absolute
pleasure and thank you so much for
sharing your time and your talents and
your insights. We have been talking with
Tom Hunt, founder and CEO of Fame. Tom,
where and how can people reach you?
>> Yeah, I saw you mentioned podcast
Confessions of a B2B entrepreneur and
then LinkedIn Tom and also feel free to
just email me to Tom at fame.so if you
have any podcast related questions.
>> Fantastic. And Justin, as always, fun
time my friend. Special thanks as always
to our listeners as well. If you like
what you're hearing, have ideas for the
show, or just want to tell us what's on
your mind, throw a review our way. Hit
subscribe if you are so inclined and we
will see you all next time on SAS that
app.
[Music]