so it's great to have you here um this
this
great man needs no introduction but for
those that don't know him i'm sure that
he's the one that attracted the audience
not me
so um udi whitaker the uh cmo of gong
um would love to give you the floor to
kind of just talk a little bit about
what you're doing and then we can get
into the main event
great to have you absolutely well my
husband appreciates any opportunity i
get to lecture outside of our home
so i'm very happy to be here
that is awesome yeah i've i've been with
gong for
four and a half years now um first
marketer
at the company and uh i i was brought on
very very early by
uh amit the ceo and co-founder uh
he had a team of about a dozen r
d people when when i joined and uh this
is the third company that he and i are
working at
together so that uh that that might give
you some hints on the great alignment
that we have on the
the place of marketing in the company
and uh sort of the resourcing and
priorities that we
we give to it but i'm i'm happy to be
here and uh i guess we'll we'll take it
uh
by the order that chris uh assigns the
questions yeah yeah and you can feel
free to drop
in whatever you want as well so we'll
we'll kind of go on this but
um the main reason that we that prompted
me to reach out one is that you're
awesome
but also that like i think everyone saw
that
there was a b2b software company that
was running a super bowl commercial
yeah so um so i want to dive deeper into
this but just like
talk me through what the thought process
from this i think is going to be super
uh super valuable for people happy happy
to talk about that
so um you know if if you've been
following gong for a while it shouldn't
come as a great surprise that we
we did the super bowl right because uh
one of the
mantras that that i have and uh meet our
ceo has
and i think our entire team lives by is
is trying to be different
and that's how you stand out if you do
what everyone else is doing i mean
if there's a two words that we hate it's
best practices
when someone makes it to that realm of
best practices it's because
everyone is doing it by then and then by
definition it's not a best practice it's
an ordinary press
practice and if you do the ordinary
stuff you're going to get ordinary
results
so i rarely look for best practices
unless like i'm trying to figure out
something that i've never ever done
before so i i want to educate myself and
see what others have been doing to see
what i like what i don't like what might
be a good fit but uh
once you get into the rhythm of things
and you're you're doing a job that
you're qualified for like the last thing
i look for is best practices because
you're just going to get ordinary
results by doing what everyone's already
doing
so i think that led us over the years to
look for
different ways standing out and i'll
i'll just name a few random ways before
we get to the super bowl
uh so it makes more sense uh two and a
half years ago we launched our visual
brand at gong
and we looked at what everyone else was
doing right the best practices you know
what the best practices for a b2b
website are i'll tell you
uh you've got to use all the safe colors
which are what one of my team members
danny calls
a series a blue so look at all the
series a's company they pretty much use
the same blue for the website because it
looks safe and it looks like a best
practice right
so they went with blues okay okay check
we're not gonna use blue
then you look at the the hero part of
the
homepage of every b2b company they have
a big mac screen with a screenshot
you will not understand of their
software right that's what every b2b
company
does so we're not going to do that and
then we kept going and like
okay this looks like they paid some
illustrator on fiverr to quickly make
their logo
and make some icons and then of course
they use lots of stock imagery because
that's what's going to make them look
sophisticated right
uh photos of of uh overly lit rooms with
people in business suits shaking hands
because that's how we all dress for work
right this this is my business suit
so we're not going to do that and we
just kept
building that checklist of what everyone
is doing and just going the exact
opposite direction
so while everyone was showing
screenshots we had a radical idea let's
show
human beings let's actually have human
beings at the top of our website and not
screenshots everyone was trying to be
overly serious
because i feel a lot of companies and
executives
confuse being an authority with being
boring well
they don't have to be synonymous we can
actually be the number one authority in
the world
on data-backed sales but still be quirky
and approachable
and have a bulldog as a mascot so we
auditioned seven dogs for the role of
bruno the dog this is a true story
we auditioned seven dogs for the role of
bruno the dog and bruno the english
bulldog
made it if you go to our website gong.io
you can have a chat with him
um in the chat the bruno bot and he's
all over our
swag and other materials and he's been a
huge huge hit and
completely recognizable with the brand
today and so we
we threw out all the traditional series
a blues and we went for bright pink
and purple and we threw out all the
stock photography there isn't a single
stock photo on the website
like go good luck finding one we
actually
took a dozen actresses and actors from a
wide range of
uh ethnic backgrounds and age groups and
we commissioned a photo shoot and we
chose their wardrobe and we decided well
what shoes would they really be wearing
for work
not the ones in the stock photos and we
bought them shoes
and and clothes and we made them like
look together
good as an ensemble and we really put a
lot of thought into this so we created
this dream
sales team that everyone wants to be a
part of right like go check out the
characters you want to be in the room
where
they're having their tacos right now
that seems like the funnest party in
town
so so that's how we build the brand and
then fast forward i promise i'm getting
to your question chris
fast forward background is awesome i
love it uh i i think it's essential to
understand like
you don't just wake up one morning say
oh maybe we'll try our luck with the
super bowl commercial no
this is four and a half years in the
making of
thinking differently and doing the exact
opposite of what everyone is doing
and so we're looking at okay what are
how do how do we communicate with where
our audience is and for those who don't
know
gong sells to sales leaders and sales
professionals
well they all live on linkedin and it
sounds obvious now but it took us a few
months to figure this out
when i started back in 2016 i was i was
checking out
facebook and youtube and twitter and
it you can see sales leaders in all
these places but turns out that linkedin
is where they really come and they're in
the zone for being
educated and entertained and distracted
and that's where they live they have an
open linkedin tab open all day long
looking for their next job their next
hire their next business partner
so that's where we decided to focus most
of our uh effort
and so we decided to create dedicated
linkedin content we were the first
company in the world
to do a live weekly show on linkedin uh
linkedin came to us
when they had the alpha version of uh
what then became linkedin live
and they said hey gong like you guys
create the most awesome content on
linkedin
we want you to try this new format
because if it fails we know it wasn't
because of your content because that's
really good
it's because of the format so we tested
out their linkedin live format for a few
months and
we always look for these really really
cool uh opportunities
i'll give a couple of final examples
before i get to super bowl um
so back in the last live dream force
here in san francisco that was 2019
um we were thinking okay how do we
hijack some traffic and attention
without paying mark benioff a couple of
million dollars to get a tiny booth and
have a steward behind the booth so i
i never paid a dime to salesforce to
sponsor their show i thought that would
be a waste of money
but what i did do is i uh i came across
an advertising company called rapify
that helped me take 20
rideshare cars from uber and
lyft and wrap them in gong branding
we just launched our new category
revenue intelligence which i'm also
happy to talk about we got the time
and so we wrapped these 20 cars and i
had this
um evil uh evil
leader map where i could see in real
time all the cars around moscone center
and i paid them an extra bonus to swarm
around the moscone center
in the morning hours as they were
dropping off attendees to dreamforce and
in the afternoon hours
as they were picking up attendees to go
to the happy hours and so
we got a ton of awareness at dreamforce
at a at a cost of really pennies uh and
without
like paying a single dollar to
salesforce
and and so that's another yet example of
uh
what we're doing i knew that one i was i
was gonna ask you about it
yeah i saw that um a few months ago the
same company came to me and said you
know we've got this pilot in san jose
a company called uh kiwibot are doing
these food delivery robots and they're
looking for a corporate sponsor to
test it i'm like of course i'm in food
delivery robots of course that's what
i've been looking for
so we did food delivery robots for a
while um and
uh we're still trying to figure out if
we can use them in a more targeted way
imagine that you're trying to sell to a
cmo like me okay
and you know that i order pizza once a
week for my kids what if
the robot delivered the pizza with your
branding on it that would get noticed
right
so so we're spent experimenting with all
these really really cool things that
i'm just leaving the noise and the
clutter behind like i don't want to
fight the bloody oceans
where everyone is trying to get your
attention or in the same way that
everyone's trying to get your attention
i'm trying to do things differently so i
finally get to the super bowl
uh so about three months ago i get an
email from
from a nice uh sales lady at cbs monica
and monica is pitching me super bowl
media
and my first response is like monica
thanks for reaching out you're probably
a couple of years early like i don't
have five and a half million dollars to
pay for a national spot and she responds
within five minutes and she says
uh hey ud you know you could come in at
much much lower than that if you go
regional
um would you like to chat this week i'm
like you know monica you've piqued my
curiosity let's chat
and i jump on a call and i learned that
the super bowl
pricing of the advertising is based on
b2c brands how they are willing to pay
right because if i'm pepsi cola
i want to pay for where there's a lot of
population that can buy pepsi cola
so in densely populated areas you're
going to pay a lot of money
to air your commercial and with the
maximum being the national commercial
which is priced at over
5 million dollars for 30 seconds which
is way more than my budget
but if you're a b2b company like me and
you only have a
short list of specific cities where most
of your customer and prospect
hubs are there's actually an arbitrage
opportunity to pay the b2c pricing but
only for the
few cities that you need so you end up
paying relatively pennies
for getting the exact areas that you
want so i'm like okay monica uh if
60 of my audience is in silicon valley
or the san francisco bay area
and let's add uh new york and seattle
and if i had a little more budget i'd
probably add boston chicago
maybe austin what does that come out to
and turns out that comes out to like
less than
five percent the cost of the national
commercial i'm like okay
this i can actually go defend uh so
that's
just thinking creatively about you don't
have to buy the most expensive media
there i can get to
90 of my audience for five percent of
the price
so that's that's the route that we took
um and then i took my ceo out for drinks
now my ceo
uh i i knew that like me he gets excited
with these things of doing things very
very very differently
so while we were on our second drink i'm
like so amit i had this interesting call
this week with cbs
they're broadcasting the the super bowl
this year
and uh like i was in my second sentence
of saying something like
so i wanted to get you excited about
this opportunity so we can go
twist the arm of our cfo i didn't even
finish the sentence he's like okay i'm
excited what do we do
how much does it cost let's do this um
and the next
the next day he already helped me pitch
this to the cfo and uh
we we dealt with the grumpy face
he asked me what our expectations are so
amit actually toned down
expectations and he said look this is a
long-term brand awareness play but
nobody in our space is doing this
so by definition we stand out by doing
this and we're like
automatically in another league and i
said you know i'm going to be a bit
bolder i'm going to make a bet that
our previous record for
new business opportunities created i
can't share the exact number with you
but the previous record was set
um a few months ago when we announced
our latest
round of finance it was a 200 million
d round and uh that that broke a bunch
of records as you can imagine on inbound
traffic and uh
new ops created and i told tim my cfo i
bet we can beat that
with the super bowl uh plus we're hiring
400 gangsters this year
that traffic probably won't hurt the
career page of the website either
so he's like okay we'll see um so we did
it
um i'll get to the creative in a minute
because i i see some questions here on
that but i'll
maybe jump to the to the results for the
spoiler um
the spoiler is we we did break all the
records by a margin
and the super bowl week became our
biggest week in the history of gong for
new business opportunities
created it was the best week ever so
even the grumpy cfo is fairly
goose bumps man like that or whatever
the happiness equivalent for cfos is
that's a great story um yeah so let's
get
the next thing on the roadmap uh first
like that is awesome
your thought process around it how you
went about it love that targeting the
cities
what was the creative strategy i want to
get deep into this one
yeah so um you know every time we do a
cool commercial
or uh explainer video or uh
last christmas we did a bunch of we did
a series i think five holiday
commercials that were kind of
over the top uh on social media and a
bunch of people asking like who did that
for you i want them to do my commercial
i happily share all my providers i i
think it's stupid to keep them a secret
um
so i'm happy to share all the providers
i work with but
here's what i don't think people get
which is how deeply involved
the client has to be to get outstanding
results
um and it's not just me saying like you
know the branding agency the created
gongs visual brand it's an agency in
israel
they're called atreo uh a t r e o dot co
and they're wonderful but they will they
will be the first to admit that
by working with me and amit closely for
six months we were able to achieve
the results that we achieved together
when they work with other companies
that don't know what they want or aren't
as committed to the process
or aren't willing to take bold risks
like we are
you get a meh result and the same goes
for videos and the same goes for
anything creative that
you're going to create or any type of
content that you're going to create
so so that that's a disclaimer around
sort of how we think about
the creative so here's in a nutshell how
i was thinking about the super bowl
creative um even before we started
thinking about
the the plot or what are we going to do
or who's going to act in it
the first thing i thought about is who's
the audience like who who's this going
out to
and because the super bowl despite
the best targeting that i described to
you of taking
only certain cities that i'm targeting
it's still like
the most terrible targeting of all the
mediums that i've used to date right
because
if i go to linkedin i can target
angelica because she's a vp of sales at
a company of this size in this industry
in this um geography i can't do that
with super bowl like the only targeting
i got is
is geography but i've got everyone from
toddlers
to retirees everyone from
uh the food industry to to
singer-songwriters watching my super
bowl commercial
how do i weed out the sales leaders in
the audience and make sure that they
don't go to the bathroom
during that commercial break because in
the first second of the commercial
they realize that this is for them so
that that was the first thing that kept
me up for a few nights
and when i when i came to our creative
partners we use the
creative studio their name is
picturelab.tv that's picturelab.tv
uh they're bay area based uh creative
studio and they've done a lot of
live action video for us over the last
three years
and i said look we have a targeting
issue here even before we get to the
story like
i need every sales leader
in the audience watching the super bowl
in the first frame of the commercial
to know that this is for them um so let
me
bring that up real quickly to show you
what we did in that first frame to
answer that
in case you haven't watched uh the
commercial yeah let's do a
live preview yep so you know i'm not
going to even play it for now i'm just
going to show you the first frame
but this is the first frame of our super
bowl commercial
now does that make more sense do you
understand what i was going for
i wanted to make sure that every sales
leader in the audience
stopped with their doritos bag and held
on to that bio break for another
30 seconds don't leave the screen now
because this is for you
so that that is the first thing that i
was thinking about how do i draw in all
those
all those sales theaters so nothing is
random there right that there's a reason
we made three versions of that nameplate
and we tested them under the lighting
to see which one would have the most
contrast and and
we had like i i asked them i was on set
for for shooting this
uh we tilted it in a very certain way
that it just
filled the screen enough without being
too in your face um but but got your
attention
so um so that's how we started um so i'm
like okay now here's the challenge
this commercial needs to be an enjoyable
watch for everyone including the
singer-songwriters
caterers and and fitness coaches out
there
it needs to be enjoyable but i want the
sales professionals
to feel like they're in this exclusive
club and have some references in there
that will make even more sense to them
and they will like
have a super enjoyable time watching
this um so you'll see a reference at the
very end to
glenn gary ross about coffee is for
closers
i'll play the commercial in a minute so
you'll hear it so we
we did a take on that um on that
reference that
is still amusing to someone who doesn't
know anything about sales
but those in sales really get it and we
got a ton of comments from people that
got the reference
oh my god like i've been waiting for
this so um
so that was that was the the challenge
there how do we weed out the sales
professionals in the audience and give
them a message
that makes a ton of sense to them and
unlike most of the marketing and content
we create for social channels where i
get a chance
to display content over and over and
over again to the audience where i can
take them on a journey
this was i was thinking about this as a
one-time thing right
i may never get a chance to pitch these
people again sitting in front of the
super bowl
so this has to count so it has to be i
can't assume that they've ever heard the
name gong
unlike most super bowl commercials where
it's like a pepsi or doritos
these are repeating brands that you've
seen a million times before so they
don't need to tell you
who they are what they manufacture where
you can buy their product
like imagine all these things that they
don't have to do that i have to do in my
30 seconds
i'm selling to people who have never
heard of gong before they don't even
know that this is a software product
where do they go to buy it and what is
it used for and who is supposed to use
it and why do they need to care i had to
get all of that in 30 seconds
um so so that's that was the the
creative brief and i i think
i think we figured it out pretty well uh
do we want to watch it
30 seconds let's take a vote from the
audience
i got a couple thumbs up let's do it
let's watch it for those of you this
first super bowl commercial here we go
funny thing happened this year my sales
team went remote leaving everyone
feeling a little little
but my sales team got through it with
gong
thanks the gong i know when a deal's
going south gong even shows us what our
top reps are doing
so now the whole team's doing it that
means more coffee
for more closers
grow your revenue with gong
[Music]
so that was a commercial uh thank you
thank you
um so the idea there we wanted to make
it look
like this was not something generic
because in the background i had a
fallback plan i had uh my team re-edit
three-year-old footage from a two-minute
long
explainer with with the same actor
michael
um into a 30-second commercial the
problem with that is
that it was in a busy office hustling
and busting with people not wearing
masks sitting in meeting rooms together
and i was going like you know this
doesn't feel real
in 2021 it just doesn't feel real like
i i can't i can't air this right now
yeah and so we ended up
flying the actor from new hampshire to
to reshoot this entire commercial
and you see he's the only actor on set
and he starts by saying funny thing
happened this year my team went remote
okay now i'm listening this is real this
is timely this is just like what my team
went through this year so now i'm
listening
and then he took it through the whole
story he showed a couple of screenshots
so that we know this is software
the call to action like we worked for
the last few days of editing just to
steal another half a second
to show the website address at the end
so people know where to go
um so every every split second has to
have a lot of thought in it when you
only have 30 seconds to tell an entire
story like that
the attention to detail is so cool
um and across whatever medium i'm sure
that you agree with this hootie
across whatever medium the creative
really makes a difference
about whether or not you're successful
right like especially on linkedin like
you can target whoever you want but it
depends on what is your objective and
what are you putting in front of those
people and does it actually create an
action
um so i want to talk about that's very
true i i just i'll just have one qualify
though when you said creative um i think
there's two levels to that there's
the actual message and then there's the
packaging and the message
and man matters a lot more than the
packaging
so you could have you know an ugly
website of black text
on white background but if you know what
the message you're trying to deliver is
it'll work
a pretty website will not make up for a
bad story if you don't know who your
audience is what their pain is
if your solution doesn't clearly solve a
problem they have
you can bring the the best designers
from apple they're not going to make it
work
okay so you've got to get the the
message straight first
and then you build a packaging around
that yeah it's a really great point so i
got two places that i want to go and i'm
trying to decide in my head right now
which one i'm going to go to first
talk to me so a lot of people that run
super bowl specifically in b2c or direct
to consumer brands
um think about the after the super bowl
airs how much attention they get
on social after did you experience that
what was it like
sure so um you know when uh my ceo
uh consulted with a couple of board
members before giving me the final
go-ahead
um they both said uh the the two board
members he asked asked
told him well you know we're usually not
fans of b2b companies doing super bowl
because it's usually a huge waste of
money they don't know how to
use it correctly but we we trust you and
udi you always manage to find a creative
solution to go for it
so amit forwards me the email thread
with with
one line he says basically your neck is
on the line good luck
so i'm like okay challenge accepted and
so i set out to build an entire
digital campaign to support this 30
seconds
of very expensive air time so we started
a digital campaign one week before the
game and we
continued it a full week after the game
and it included
everything from employee advocacy so we
had hundreds of gangsters share the
commercial on sunday and monday
getting us hundreds of thousands of
views i
i was one of the first to share it on
sunday and
it it just blew up completely on on
linkedin you know if you've ever
wondered
is sunday a terrible time to share well
it's not if you've got something
exciting to share
uh people couldn't stop commenting go
check out the the
linkedin post i posted on sunday on
super bowl like there were
over a thousand engagements hundreds of
comments hundreds of shares people were
going wild about it
and then we're like okay what else do
people love free swag
so we tied it in with a swag campaign
which we've done a million times and it
works every single time
we printed two special edition gong
super bowl
t-shirts um one of them has bruno the
dog in a
in a football helmet the other just has
the helmet on it and the back says like
closer
and uh we we said let's let's print 200
of these t-shirts
within a few hours of me posting that
commercial on sunday morning saying if
you share this
vince from my team will send you a
special edition super bowl t-shirt
within a few hours the 200 were gone but
they were done in the middle of the day
on sunday
so my team went and quickly ran out and
like ordered 500 more t-shirts on monday
um so we added swag now imagine what
that does right there's a virtuous cycle
there
so if um sherry is watching my super
bowl commercial and she likes it
how can i incentivize her to take her
liking of it to the next steps
so i'm i'm thinking about her journey
well if i don't do anything she might
click like that that's good right
because it tells the linkedin algorithm
that there's something here
likable that they might want to show to
other people but how can i get her to
share this with her network and
i'm guessing on average each of you have
at least 500 people in your network i'd
love to have them in my audience
so what if i give shari an incentive for
sharing my commercial
and make it super simple like hey sherry
if you share this commercial and tag
on we'll contact you for an address and
send you a t-shirt
now you're like well you know for three
seconds a cool gong t-shirt sounds like
a pretty good deal
so hundreds of people share a commercial
now every one of those hundreds of
people have
500 to 5 000 contacts you tell me what
that does to the audience
i'm looking at the number of views on
that just the youtube
installation of that commercial has 200
000 views by now
and that's just on youtube not including
the native linkedin one not including
the one that actually ran on television
and not including
many other placements of that commercial
so you've got to think about
how you build an entire campaign around
this employee advocacy
we contacted our top 10 influencers
i won't mention their name because uh
you've heard some of them and and
some of them uh sort of do this more
organically but we had all the top
influencers in our network share this on
monday morning
giving us boom another huge audience for
this um
and then of course you know social media
we we we
use the commercial for both a paid uh
campaign for the week
and also posted it organically on gong's
page and had hundreds of gongsters
shared on their pages so you know it
blew up but
you've got to plan these things yeah and
so you kind of beat me to the chase on
because i was going to ask about
attribution but clearly that's not an
issue because you had your best
performing ever right like the
correlation is enough but
um especially from that different time
period but i want to talk to you about
attribution it's something that i work
with a lot of companies that get caught
up in it a lot of the things that you're
doing
are going to be difficult to measure
like the um the
food truck thing that drops off your
pizza like how are you going to measure
that unless you know that it's going to
susie and so
um so how do you think about that like
you must have very and i want to get to
ceo cmo
i'm in which it seems like you guys are
great i think people can learn from that
but let's talk about attribution first
sure so here's a really simple approach
to how we treat our attribution
i use the rule of sum of thumb trying to
spend
80 percent of my program's budget on
things that i can clearly
attribute to revenue so percent of my
program budget goes to things i can
attribute to revenue
twenty percent of my stuff i don't wanna
even talk to my cfo
just leave me alone let me do what i do
i'm bringing you enough pipeline with
eighty percent you can
attribute trust me that the other twenty
percent will be used wisely but
i'm not gonna even try and show you how
this is working
and that's where i get to do out of home
and television and robots and
crazy stuff like that that nobody's
asking me to show them that tribution
um so if you do that and you know you
have enough
from your budget going to things that
you can attribute and you show that it's
working and you're hitting your numbers
then you should be able to get that
trust and and rope
to to spend another 20 or so of your
budget start at 10
if you're not there yet okay ask for 10
of your budget um
the official budget line um in the cfo
excel sheet appears as cmo experiments
uh under my internal team's budget it
appears under udi's crazy ideas that
that's what the
the line item says for that budget and i
get i get my budget
um you know obviously it grows over the
years so you start modestly
but you've got to have a budget for
experimenting i'm i'm
thinking about a million different
things how do i do product placement on
netflix now what about regional radio
what there's so many things that we're
not doing that i don't know
if they can help but i'm not going to be
able to attribute them at least
initially
you've got to have some flexibility to
work with a certain percentage of the
budget that you don't
expect to attribute to revenue yeah and
i heard a little nuance there which is
that that 80 percent's got to be getting
to your goals
or that 20 is probably not going to
happen right
so you've got to be able it goes without
saying you know as long as you're
hitting your numbers consistently
you're going to get a lot of trust
credibility and resources
to keep doing what you're doing and
build that next wave and next channel
and
and and stand out but uh make sure that
your focus is
is in the right place of of hitting your
numbers first that that goes without
saying
so it seems like you and a meat are very
aligned so talk to me about
how that works i've seen that go very
well
and very not so well right depending on
the relationship and so what are some
strategies that you have for cmos in
working with a ceo it seemed like you'd
work with them before that sounds like a
really good
good starting point because you are
aligned and have experience doing that
but like
i just work with enough companies to
know that some of the things that you're
doing well i believe they are incredibly
smart and incredibly differentiated and
very effective
a lot of cmos would never have the
opportunity to do stuff like this what
are some recommendations you have for
them
right so i've got an answer i'm not sure
everyone's going to like it though
so here's the thing when you're very
early stage
um in your career like all of us were
you have to choose a good company i mean
you may not even have a lot of choices
right you might have
one job offer and then take it by all
means but as soon as you get some choice
first i would choose company over exact
role and make sure it's a company that
uh has experienced leadership and and
they're on a good trajectory and that
if as the company grows you'll probably
get growth opportunities as well
and you've heard good things about your
future boss from other people who either
work for him now
or her or worked for her in the past
that's how i chose my
my first few jobs and then as you
step into more senior leadership
positions and you actually have more
choices
here's the thing i don't know how to
take
a ceo or for that matter a vp of sales
that don't believe in marketing and turn
them around i don't know how to do that
so i just avoid them i i go to work for
companies where the ceo believes in
marketing it's that simple
um and i i told you you're not gonna not
all of you are gonna like the answer
it's a great answer
because yeah i mean it's a great answer
it's it's painfully true
if your current ceo doesn't believe in
marketing i don't think you're going to
be able to turn her around
i'm i'm sorry just go go work for ceo
who believes in marketing
um but but but more seriously i'll i'll
touch on this in two other angles as
well
one um i've never met a ceo who didn't
believe in sales
but i've met many ceos who said i don't
believe in marketing like the product
sells itself like we build a wonderful
product those are usually like
engineer type ceos that are very product
centric and they think that
their their product is god's gift to
mankind and
all they need to do is open the doors
and everyone will be crashing in like
you know black friday and and grab their
product that that doesn't happen right
that just doesn't happen um so that
that's one problem
the second the thing is i i want us to
point our finger
at ourselves you know the joke about 90
of the lawyers giving a bad reputation
to the rest of them
i think marketers share the same thing
so
there are a lot of mediocre marketers
out there that have never
proven great results that never fully
figured it out
and they've given a bad impression to
their ceos to their vp of sales
and those folks carry that impression to
their next company into their next vp
marketing
and so it's first the onus is on us to
correct that
and to do that we need to be more open
in sharing the thought process behind
what we're doing
you know when i sat with my cfo after he
didn't like a couple of
holiday commercials that we launched on
social media a few months ago
and i explained to him like what i was
trying to do who the audience was
why this part went so crazy why i didn't
even bother explaining the product
because i only used this for retargeting
an audience that i knew
already knew gong he goes you know that
makes a lot more sense now that you
explain this to me
now if you don't take the time to
explain this to your sales leader
to your ceo to your finance leader how
do you expect them to figure this out
so you've got to be open to sharing your
thought process
and also being open to getting feedback
i've
gotten great ideas for things i've
missed or i couldn't
have come up with myself from a bunch of
people at the company
um you know we we named our very
successful
uh annual conference which is now a
quarterly
virtual conference celebrate um the idea
came from one of our sdrs nicolette that
two years later is now part of the
marketing team uh probably no
coincidence but uh
back when she was in sdr she she came up
to the ceo and to me and she
there's an internal story that makes
more sense if you know it but basically
she said what if
what if we called our annual conference
celebrate and the ceo said nicolette
that's an amazing idea
that should be the name of our annual
conference and it still is so
you've got to be open to getting great
ideas from everyone in the organization
and share your thought process be very
open about it share
what you know and what's working share
what you don't know and where you're
challenged
and you will earn more trust that way
love that we're gonna pivot a little bit
so um
i heard early on you'd mention no dream
force and obviously
physical events aren't happening right
now but the the question that i have for
you
is do you see any things that are
happening perhaps there they fit in your
best practice
category that marketers should just
think about cutting out like i'm
a big proponent of like if it's not
working there's no sense in doing it at
all
right like i think a lot of people tend
to check the box are there things that
that you see out there or maybe things
that you've done that are fit into a
best practice you just don't do anymore
yeah i think that's a great point chris
because
marketing teams probably more than any
other team
can always always be busy there's an
infinite amount of activities and
campaigns and programs to run
i've never met a marketing team that
wasn't busy right we have an
infamous infinite number of things that
we couldn't be doing so i think
having discipline around cutting out
things like chris suggested
is just as important as introducing new
things because
your resources are always going to be
limited uh i remember uh meeting with an
executive from google one day and
she was telling me that she outsources
the adwords that she runs for her
product line
to an external agency because she didn't
have enough internal resources at google
to run google adwords for a google
product
so even if you're imagining oh if i only
had more resources like the big
companies no
even at google they outsource running
their own google ads for their own
google products
to an external agency because they don't
have the resources to do that so
if if google can do that you can do that
so you can outsource whatever is not
core to your offering you can cut out
things that are no longer working um
here are a few changes that we made in
the last 12 months so one
we've shifted all of our field events
like most of us
into virtual events and we've landed on
a
an amazing format that i hope stays
forever and i believe
will stay forever if not as a standalone
virtual event than as a hybrid event i
think just like every meeting
for the rest of time is going to be a
zoo meeting because you're not going to
ever be able to get all the people you
need in the room
like never ever again it's always going
to be a zoom meeting i think events are
always going to be a virtual event
with some form of hybrid even when we
can get into a room or a auditorium
together
they're going to be another thousand
people that couldn't make it couldn't
fly out they're in a different country
different time zone
they're going to tune in virtually just
like schools are running now right the
open schools
are doing hybrid well that's how events
are going to run forever if you're not
already
educating yourself on how to make that
work you're about six or nine months
late
so this is how events are always going
to run don't sit back waiting for
field events to come back the way they
used to i don't think they will i could
be wrong
i don't think they will um another thing
that we did is
um everything that was not digital in my
program's budget so
out of home advertising cars uh robots
all of that stuff
i took all that budget and and put it
into digital this past year because
a couple of things happen one um nobody
at least here on the west coast is in
office these days
um not only are we not in the office
area where i could carefully choose
placement of out of home
advertising for say employer branding
we've done billboards in the last three
years many times
to celebrate our outstanding gangsters
and
um showcase them in billboards
within a miles ranges from the office
which was strategically placed
because i wanted to make sure that every
candidate walking into an interview in
the office saw one of our billboards
and that stuck in their mind and every
single candidate that came in mentioned
seeing one of our billboards
and how that gets them excited because
we're uh we're celebrating our employees
on
billboards that's kind of a big thing
that again i haven't seen other
companies do
um so i stopped doing that and then um a
couple of weeks ago we had our
uh global kickoff and we had to figure
out how are we going to recognize our
outstanding gangsters this year
without doing physical billboards
because not only are we not in the
office but
60 of our team members have left town
and we're now spread across 20 states
in the us so i'm like okay this has to
be digital this has to be virtual
but people still love the feel of a
billboard right you feel big and
important and
like you love seeing your face up there
in lights so i'm like
i i literally had this thought in the
shower one morning i said okay what if
we created this 3d world where
um we placed our outstanding gangsters
in times square
and in piccadilly circus in the uk and
in
in osaka and other cities and i came to
a couple of my team members i'm like
okay team ready for another crazy idea
we have a month to build this thing
and then they they build it and uh they
came up with this thing which we shared
um with our outstanding gangsters a
couple of uh weeks ago
so if we go to say times square
so we actually built this virtual 3d
world i hope this is showing up well
over zoom yeah it looks great
and we actually put hannah and sunny
and laura in our outstanding going
straight you can you can walk and zoom
in and pan
and build this whole thing and we we
build this across
uh four different cities right so if you
want to go to
the uk here's piccadilly circus for you
i missed that place and we've we've got
liam and we've got the recruiting team
set up here and we did that
where else here in las vegas another
spot that we're not going to get to
visit very soon but look
isn't this beautiful where we're
featuring our team on on billboards
and you can imagine that they're sharing
this with their families they're excited
they love the experience like
they've never seen anything like this at
any other company so
just you know this costs like pennies
i've got an internal
web uh programmer uh who reports to an
ops person and a copywriter who managed
the project with the graphic designer
and it's like boom
just you build it
right on i got a final question and then
what we love to do is if we can do like
five ten minutes of q a we can maybe
there's a couple questions brewing but
one more question for you
um you strike me as a as a what of a
brand guy like the executions that you
do
the the company that's been built right
now like it's
a lot of the executions are on brand how
do you feel about performance marketing
direct response drive a lot of leads
so i'm glad you brought that up chris
because
obviously the the sexy stuff the the
super bowl the virtual billboards
uh the the hacking traffic at uh
salesforce
is is a lot of brand awareness and
creative stuff but
our first priority in most hours of the
week
most dollars of the budget and most head
count on the team
are heads down doing good old-fashioned
not not old-fashioned but good new
fashion demand generation or revenue
marketing
uh we're hitting our numbers we're
creating thousands of qualified
opportunities
and we use a lot of the same tools that
i think most of you are using
um i i don't mind sharing because i
don't think there's any secrets you can
steal from us i i hope
everyone starts doing better marketing
but the three top channels for us
are our organic linkedin page is a huge
huge source
of inbound traffic which we later
convert to demo and pricing requests
our second source is our email list so
we have hundreds of thousands of fans
that love getting our emails
like i've got incoming emails saying how
can i get more emails from gong
that's what people are writing literally
like so you know your content is good
when when they do that
um and the third is our virtual events
so if i
if i had to cut out everything else if i
had to go back to being a one person
team which
i've been five times because i've been
the first marketer at five companies
the first three things i would do is
manage our linkedin page our email
subscription list and when i could
our virtual events those three things
account for the majority of what's
working for us right now
i see some of you taking notes please
don't don't go tell your boss udi said
that these are the three things we need
to focus on
because they are right for me i don't
know if they're right for you right now
i don't know where your audience lives
if you're selling to to millennial
youtubers
they're probably not on linkedin go find
them on tick tock or clubhouse or
wherever they are so you've got to test
these things for yourself and figure it
out
but definitely the focus is on
repeatable
revenue marketing machine that brings in
the leads
eventually on auto mode and and like we
have you know we
obsess about measuring the response time
um someone wrote on sunday this last
sunday
someone wrote on linkedin um i reached
out to three customer success leaders at
gong asking them about an open role
all three responded within like two
hours that's pretty amazing
on a sunday um and and that's customer
success people but if you
if you put in your demo request on our
website either using the bruno bot
or in a form you should get the first
answers within like minutes
and we obsess about these slas every
tuesday morning we have a revenue
leadership meeting
we look at every segment like oh why are
they below 90
meeting their sla which is within two
hours get back to every inbound lead
that's the stuff that that really moves
the needle once you you master that
stuff
that really moves the needle yeah let's
talk through it because honestly i think
a lot of companies deal with follow-up
for a lot of different reasons
geoterritories
account segmentation like jimmy over
here needs to do the enterprise and
susie's doing the smb and jimmy can only
handle
boston so we need to figure out the
territory is there something
that you do in order to facilitate that
like sub five minute response time on
pricing and demo request because
honestly i don't see a lot of companies
getting there
um yes well first there is a
there's a technological barrier that you
need to solve so you need
good people who know the systems and the
tools at hand to figure it out like
we had a breakthrough when we lowered
the time that it takes the lead to get
from our website to an sdr
alert from like 23 minutes to seven
minutes
there was a lot i can't even explain
what kyle on my team did there but
he did some magic and sorcery that cut
through a lot of
systems that were holding back the
response time so we could cut cut down
that uh
that valuable time but the second thing
is really having the entire
company obsessing over what we call
create raving fans
right we have eight operating principles
they're all on our website
the first one is create raving fans and
that means that everything we do is
designed
to create a raving fan experience how do
we create a raving fan experience for a
prospect
asking for pricing no matter where they
are in the world
uh try us like go at 4am or when you're
traveling somewhere go to our website
and ask for a demo tell me what you
think of the experience
you can have a friendly chat with a
robot dog any time of the
of the day or night and if you if we can
pre-qualify you
because we used a lot of real-time
enrichment and fancy products to do that
if we can pre-qualify you you can
schedule your own demo
at any time or of day or night uh
directly with an ae
and if if we can't pre-qualify you then
we'll let you schedule
a short discovery call with an inbound
sdr we've got all these different tiers
of figuring out um how much resources we
want to spend on talking to you basing
based on your qualification and and tie
that
in with the raving fan experience so
like we count the clicks that it takes
you to schedule a call
i want to eliminate any unnecessary
clicks to do that
uh don't assume that just because
someone wants to talk to you you can
drag them through a 20 click experience
that that's horrible
like who wants that i love i love the
calendar booking i imagine that the
conversion rate from that to sql sql was
significantly better than
through a demo form and then waiting
three hours to get an email back from an
sdr
for for sure for sure we want to make
sure that the people
i mean here's the thing right because
when you look at the
the world out there they're the ones
that you want to sell to they're the
ones that are now interested in you
if you can draw that venn diagram and
find the overlap of the ones that you
want to sell to and are
currently at the very moment interested
in talking to you those are your hottest
leads right you really want to talk to
them now
so design your website experience to
capture those people
with as close to zero friction as you
can
and and go through the process yourself
have your partner
go through the process have your mother
go through the process of asking for a
demo
if she gets stuck many of her prospects
are getting stuck like
design it that that really any any
imbecile could go through the process
and and
don't make it difficult to get hold of
you don't make it difficult so many
companies
they ask me like 25 things on the form i
want to talk to you but not that badly
love that love that cool um angelica you
got a couple
couple questions we can go with udi on
yeah we got a couple
um let's see so question for udi
what were or would you be now
or would be now your priorities as the
first marketer at a company specifically
if you have a limited budget
so the the the first thing here's here's
what i do when i come into a company i
i start thinking about outbound and
inbound now
inbound is going to take a lot of time
but that's the holy grail right um
currently at gong forty percent of our
pipeline comes in inbound
forty percent when i joined the company
four and a half years ago that was zero
because nobody ever heard of us nobody
was on my website nobody was converting
nobody cared
um but i started building an inbound
engine early
so that four years later i have 40
percent of a very big pipeline
coming in inbound so you want to start
that early but set expectations
to yourself and everyone around you that
the fruits of that
effort are going to come in much much
later but you have to start it early
or you're going to delay the the fruits
the second thing is
go very aggressive on outbound on day
one that is the only way you're going to
keep your job
and the company is going to stay alive
until their next round of funding
by going aggressive on outbound i mean
usually the following so if you're in
b2b
uh usually content marketing is going to
work it's worked for most b2b companies
that i've worked for
so we came up with a unique strategy of
what can we
educate our buyers on that nobody else
is doing in the way that
we're thinking about doing so that we're
top of mind for them when they're
finally ready to buy something
um in our case the the short version of
it was
they're a million books on sales but
they're all based on someone's
individual experience and opinion
there's nothing out there based on data
and every other profession i know like
marketing and finance
they're already working on metrics and
dashboards and a b testing and analytics
but sales is still living in the
in the dark ages or so they were four
and a half years ago
so we're going to be the number one
authority on data backed sales we're
going to show people
demonstrate what actually works and
doesn't work based on our own analysis
and we we we were fortunate that that
that was a very good bet until this day
that's what we're known for and that's
what people consume
every day on our linkedin page and our
emails and our events etc
and then to go with that we hired an sdr
like almost on day one to start making
calls very bad cold calls which we
tweaked
very very quickly using our own tool
gong to quickly see what's working and
not working
so you've got to go very aggressive on
on outbound to get in front of as many
people as you can
our ceo personally sold the first
probably
50 companies himself because he said how
can i hire vp sales and expect them to
figure it out if i don't know how to
sell my own product
so he hired me a full year before he
hired a vp sales
to start building demand gen to start
building a brand so that when our vp
sales came in he already had a platform
to work on
he had leads coming in he had meetings
set and he could focus on actually
closing those leads that is so smart
that is awesome uh love that maybe one
more question so i
just to clarify people i love the idea
of getting
cmo vp of marketing and first building
the engine and then having sales come
most series seed series a companies do
the opposite and you have an expensive
vp of sales with no leads that has to
build it from the ground up with no
brand it's a tough place to be for that
vp of sales
the one warning that i would attach to
that recommendation though is
um and i've written and talked about
this extensively the the one biggest
thing that i don't think
marketing can fix is product market fit
so if the company has not achieved
product market fit yet
you're probably wasting a lot of money
if you're asking marketing to just
design a message i mean how can i design
a message for a product that doesn't
work or nobody wants
i can't i can't do that and and that's
why the marketing
gets fired and and you want to come oh
they'll bring
great messaging and they'll build demand
i can't build a mansion if you don't
have a product that people want to use
so um i i try and become a better judge
of
product market fit before i join a
company and and you should probably do
that
um i've worked for companies where there
was not great product market fit
i don't know how to fix that um maybe
some of you do
but if you don't um that should be a big
warning sign for you if you don't see
product market fit and there's ways for
for checking it go read their g2 reviews
ask to talk to three customers
um if nobody is excited and loving the
product you might want to look for
somewhere else where
there's that initial product market fit
that will allow you to succeed as a
marketer
cool i think we got time for one more
let's do it
awesome okay so daniel asked what are
your thoughts on the cookie list future
and what's the responsibility of brands
there
good good point so uh first i will say i
am not the world's
best expert on the alternatives that are
emerging i know that there
are to uh to the cookie-less future
um i think it will limit our ability to
personalize our our marketing
and uh we're gonna have ways we're gonna
have to find ways sometimes that are
less scalable
to do that right so retargeting is gonna
become more difficult uh
providing a personal experience on our
website it's going to become more
difficult
but if you have a team of rockstar sdrs
that know how to personalize their
message
and you're finding other ways of
communicating with with customers i mean
on social media
i don't do almost any personalization it
works really really well
um in many of the sort of marketo emails
i'm not doing any personalization and it
works really really well
because we write them in a very human
compelling way in virtual events we
don't do any personalization but they
work really really well so
i think that's one area of marketing on
your website where where the cookieless
future is definitely going to have an
impact
but uh i i don't see this as you know
collapsing the whole house of cards of
marketing programs that we built
it's just one medium we're going to
adapt to it and i'm sure they're going
to be
interesting solutions and hacks to get
around some of the challenges that that
brings on and i think it gives it gives
marketers that are really strong an
advantage
against those that needs tools like that
in order to perform well
it's the way that i feel could be
interesting i think if you took away
if you took away the tools and the
different things like that then the
really great marketers shine
that is true you know one way uh i like
talking about these tools is that don't
get a tool that will allow you to
run a bad campaign to more people but
that's what a lot of marketers do
right think about it not even a market
to give give like an outreach or a sales
loft to a bad sdr like oh my god the
amount of courage that they can
do is incredible we had one rep come in
i won't mention his name because i love
the guy
and he's one of our top reps today but
when he came in he was so
uh zealous about getting out there he
basically like downloaded our entire crm
luckily he only had like 5 000 contacts
in it put it in his outreach cadence and
blasted the
out of everything and we were like
oh my god what is this guy doing
and a lot of marketers do that they're
like oh if i just have the right tools
i'll get drift and i'll get marquette
those are great tools
they're not going to solve your
marketing problems they're not going to
solve
what you communicate with customers how
often you do it
in what tone of voice you do it what are
you telling them what's the follow-up
you've got to still figure all that out
the tools are going to help you automate
something and hopefully you've got
something good
that you want to scale but don't say
something bad and hope that the
tool will help you scale it and that
will bring you a good result it'll just
be doing more of a bad thing so
watch out for that as well love that
point
cool uh ooty any final words this has
been amazing i'm sure that people have
loved it i
really love diving deep into that with
you but would love if you have anything
to close out
no um the best way to to follow me and
and reach out is on linkedin so there's
only one udi letter
on linkedin so it should be pretty easy
to find um
please uh follow me and i apologize in
advance if i can't get back to everyone
and every request
i get more of them than i i should uh
and i wish i could answer more of them
so uh best of luck to everyone i will
try and do my help to
to answer anything that i do get on
linkedin
awesome thank you everyone for joining
hope you enjoyed it and
we'll see you back for another episode
soon thank you udi
thank you soon bye